[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
DAVID MALAN: All right, this is CS50.
大卫·马兰：好的，这里是 CS50。
And this is week 3.
这是第三周。
And as promised, we thought we'd take a bit of a break on new syntax this week
正如承诺的那样，我们想在这周稍微休息一下新的语法
and focus a lot more on algorithms and implementation
更多地关注算法和实现
thereof because over the past few weeks, besides Scratch, we've now had C.
因为在过去的几周里，除了 Scratch，我们现在还有 C。
And you have a lot of vocabulary now.
现在你们有了很多词汇。
Even if it might not seem yet that you fully
即使现在你们可能还没有完全
grasp all of the functionality of this particular language, with practice,
掌握这种特定语言的所有功能，但随着练习，
it'll get easier and easier.
会越来越容易。
But today, we'd focus instead on ideas and ultimately on this,
但今天，我们将重点关注想法，最终关注的是，
how to think algorithmically, and so to take problems in the real world
如何进行算法思考，以及如何将现实世界中的问题
and try to quantize them in a way that you can map those puzzle
进行量化，以便你们能将那些难题
pieces from week 0 or all of this new syntax from weeks 1 and 2
从第 0 周开始的拼图，或者从第 1 周和第 2 周开始的所有新的语法
on to actually writing code to solve those problems.
映射到实际编写代码来解决这些问题。
To contextualize this, though, we thought
为了说明这一点，我们想
we'd remind you of this here chart from week zero.
提醒你们第零周的这张图表。
And recall that in week zero, we painted this picture where
还记得我们在第零周画了这张图，图中
on the x-axis on the horizontal was the size of the problem.
横坐标表示问题的规模。
And the number of phone book pages increased
电话簿的页数随着
as you went from left to right.
从左到右而增加。
And then on the vertical axis or y-axis, we had time to solve.
然后在纵坐标上，我们有解决问题所需的时间。
So this was like how many seconds, how many page turns,
所以这就像多少秒，多少页翻页，
how many units of measure-- whatever you're using.
多少单位，无论你们使用什么。
We might actually describe the solution there too.
我们实际上也可以在那里描述解决方案。
And the first algorithm we had in week 0 for the phone book
在第 0 周，我们针对电话簿的第一个算法是
was, like, one page at a time.
一次翻一页。
So we plotted it with this 1 to 1 slope.
所以我们用 1:1 的斜率绘制了它。
The second algorithm, we started doing two pages
第二个算法，我们开始一次翻两页
at a time, which did risk a bug.
但这确实存在出现错误的风险。
I might have to double back one page.
我可能需要回退一页。
But it was still going for the most part twice as fast.
但它仍然大部分时间快了两倍。
So it was still a slow but sort of a 2 to 1 slope instead of 1 to 1.
所以它仍然很慢，但斜率是 2:1 而不是 1:1。
But the third and final algorithm, recall,
但第三个也是最后一个算法，还记得
was sort of fundamentally different.
它在本质上是不同的。
And it was this logarithmic curve, so to speak,
它是一个对数曲线，可以这么说，
whereby it kept increasing, increasing, increasing but very, very slowly.
它不断增长，增长，增长，但非常非常慢。
So even if you, like, doubled the size of the phone book,
所以即使你们将电话簿的大小翻倍，
as by having Cambridge and Allston here in Massachusetts merge, no big deal.
就像让马萨诸塞州的剑桥和奥尔斯顿合并一样，没什么大不了的。
It was just one more page turn, not another 500 or another 1,000.
只需要多翻一页，而不是多翻 500 页或 1000 页。
So think back today on that particular idea of how we began to divide
所以今天回忆一下我们如何开始划分这个问题的具体想法
and conquer the problem.
并征服这个问题。
And that sort of gave us a fundamentally better advantage.
这种方法给我们带来了一个本质上更好的优势。
So we thought we'd see if we can apply this lesson learned as follows.
所以我们想看看是否可以将这条经验教训应用到以下情况。
If I were to take, like, attendance today sort of here on stage,
如果今天我要在这舞台上点名，
I could do it old school, like, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, and so
我可以像老式那样做，像 1、2、3、4、5、6、7、8，然后继续下去，一次一步。
forth, so one step at a time.
一次一步。
I could also double the speed--
我也可以将速度提高一倍
2, 4, 6, 8, 10, 12, 14, 16, and so forth.
2, 4, 6, 8, 10, 12, 14, 16, 等等。
But I dare say we can learn a bit from week zero.
但我想我们可以在第零周学到一些东西。
And if you'll indulge me right in place, could everyone
如果你愿意的话，请大家
stand up and think of the number one.
站起来，想想数字 1。
So right where you are, just stand up if you could.
就在你所在的位置，只要你能站起来就好。
Stand up.
站起来
And think of the number one.
想想数字 1。
So at this point, hopefully, everyone's literally thinking of the number one.
所以，现在，希望大家都在认真地想着数字 1。
And the second step of this algorithm, which I claim ultimately theoretically
而这个算法的第二步，我认为最终从理论上来说
should be much faster than either my one person at a time
应该比我的一个人一次的方法快得多
or two people at a time, step two is this.
或者两个人一次的方法，第二步就是这样。
Pair off with someone standing.
与一个站着的人配对。
And add their number to yours.
把他们的数字加到你的数字上。
And remember the sum.
记住总和。
Person can be in front of, behind, left, or right of you.
这个人可以站在你前面、后面、左边或右边。
All right most likely most everyone in the room assuming you
好的，假设你在房间里，大多数人可能
found someone is thinking of the number two
找到了一个正在想着数字 2 的人
now unless you're sort of an odd person out in the row.
现在，除非你是队伍里比较特别的人。
And that's fine.
这没关系。
If you're still one, that's fine.
如果你还是 1，那也没关系。
But most of you are probably two.
但你们大多数人可能是 2。
Next step is that one of you in those pairs should sit down.
下一步是，你们中的一个人应该坐下。
OK, so many of you tried to sit down as quickly as possible we noticed.
好的，我们注意到，你们很多人试图尽快坐下。
But so next step now, at this point, rather, most of you
但现在，更确切地说，大多数人
are thinking of the number two.
正在想着数字 2。
A few of you are thinking of the number one.
你们中有些人正在想着数字 1。
And that's OK.
这没关系。
The next step, and notice we're about to induce a loop, so the rest of this
下一步，注意我们即将进入循环，所以剩下的步骤
is on you, if still standing, go back to step two.
就靠你了，如果还站着，回到第二步。
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
[声音交叠]
DAVID MALAN: If still standing, notice that this is a loop.
DAVID MALAN：如果还站着，注意这是一个循环。
So keep going.
所以继续。
Keep going if still standing.
如果还站着，继续。
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
[声音交叠]
DAVID MALAN: There?
DAVID MALAN：那里？
How about there?
那里呢？
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
[声音交叠]
DAVID MALAN: That's OK.
DAVID MALAN：没关系。
But now keep going.
但现在继续。
Keep going.
继续。
Keep pairing off, so maybe you two.
继续配对，也许你们两个。
All right, a few more seconds.
好的，再过几秒钟。
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
[声音交叠]
DAVID MALAN: So step two, still.
DAVID MALAN：所以，第二步，继续。
All right, keep pairing if you're standing.
好的，如果你站着，继续配对。
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
[声音交叠]
DAVID MALAN: All right.
DAVID MALAN：好的。
All right, so theoretically, there's only one person standing left.
好的，所以从理论上来说，应该只剩下一个人站着。
But clearly, that's not the case.
但很明显，情况并非如此。
That's fine.
没问题。
I will help with the pairing because some of you are far away.
我会帮助你们配对，因为你们中有些人离得很远。
So let's see.
让我们看看。
What's your number here?
你在这里的号码是多少？
Sorry?
什么？
What's your number?
你的号码是多少？
Eight.
八。
OK, go ahead and sit down.
好的，请坐。
How about in back?
后面怎么样？
What's your number?
你的号码是多少？
46.
Nice.
不错。
OK, go ahead and sit down.
好的，请坐。
Who else is standing?
还有谁站着？
Over here, what's your number?
这边，你的号码是多少？
You're 16?
你是16号？
OK, so go ahead and sit down.
好的，请坐。
And behind you?
你身后呢？
48.
OK, go ahead and sit down.
好的，请坐。
Is anyone still standing?
还有人站着吗？
Yeah?
是吧？
32.
Nice.
不错。
Still standing over here.
这边还有人站着。
43.
OK, nice.
好的，不错。
Sit down.
坐下。
And anyone else still standing here?
还有其他人站在这里吗？
22.
Go ahead and sit down.
请坐。
Is anyone still standing and participating?
还有人站着并参与吗？
Yeah, where-- oh, yeah.
是的，在哪里，哦，是的。
16.
OK, go ahead and sit down.
好的，请坐。
Anyone else still standing?
还有人站着吗？
OK, so theoretically, everyone's paired off.
好的，理论上，每个人都配对好了。
You were the last person standing.
你是最后一个人站着。
So when I hit Enter here, having just greased the wheels
所以当我在这里按下回车键，刚刚才润滑了一下齿轮
to do all of the remaining additions myself,
准备自己完成所有剩余的加法，
we should have the total count of people in the room.
我们应该就能得到房间里的人数的总计。
And recognize that unlike my algorithm, which
并且要注意，与我的算法不同，我的算法
would have required pointing at each and every person
需要指着每一个人的
or my second algorithm, which would mean pointing at every two people
或者我的第二个算法，意味着要指着每两个人
twice as fast, theoretically, the algorithm you all just executed,
快两倍，理论上，你们刚刚执行的算法，
I daresay, should've been fundamentally faster.
我敢说，应该更快。
Why?
为什么？
Because no matter how many people in the room-- maybe, like,
因为不管房间里有多少人，可能，比如，
if there were 1,000 people in the room, there
如果房间里有1000人，那就
would then have been 500, just as there would be 500 pages in week zero.
那么，人数就会变成 500，就像第零周有 500 页一样。
Then from 500, there'd be 250--
然后从 500 人开始，就会有 250 个人——
125.
125 个人。
Why?
为什么？
Because on each step of the algorithm, half of you
因为在算法的每一步中，你们中有一半的人
theoretically were sitting down, sitting down, sitting down, dividing
理论上来说，是坐下来，坐下来，坐下来，并解决问题。
and conquering that problem.
并且战胜了那个问题。
So the total number of people in the room as of now according to your count
所以根据你的计算，目前房间里的人数总共
is 231.
是 231 人。
As a backup, though, Carter kindly did it the old-fashioned way,
作为备份，Carter 友善地用老式方法做了这件事，
one person at a time.
一次一个人。
And Carter, the actual number of people in the room is?
Carter，房间里实际的人数是多少？
[LAUGHS]
[笑声]
OK, so our first real world bug to be fair.
好的，公平地说，这是我们遇到的第一个现实世界的错误。
So theoretically, that should have worked.
所以理论上，应该可以实现。
But clearly, we lost some numbers along the way, so a bug
但很明显，我们在过程中遗失了一些数字，所以这是一个错误
that we can fix today.
我们可以今天解决的。
But remember that really, this is just similar in spirit
但请记住，实际上，这只是在精神上类似于
to that algorithm we indeed did in week zero.
我们在第零周做的那个算法。
It's the same as the phone book example.
这与电话簿的例子一样。
It went off the rails in this case.
在这种情况下，它偏离了轨道。
But it's the same idea, ultimately dividing and conquering.
但本质上，它是一样的，最终都是分而治之。
And any time you have this halving, halving, halving,
只要你遇到这种，二分，二分，二分，
there's going to be a logarithm involved there,
就会有对数参与其中，
even if you're a little rusty on your math.
即使你对数学有点生疏。
And that's fundamentally faster than just doing something n times
而且这从根本上来说比直接做某事 n 次
or even n divided by 2 times where n is the number of people in the room
甚至做 n 除以 2 次（n 是房间里的人数）
or in week zero, the number of pages in the phone book.
或者在第零周，电话簿中页面的数量。
So even when you're using your iPhone or Android device later today, like,
所以，即使你今天晚些时候使用你的 iPhone 或 Android 设备，例如，
if you search for a contact using autocomplete,
如果你使用自动完成功能搜索联系人，
it is that so-called divide and conquer algorithm that's
就是那个所谓的“分而治之”算法，
finding people in your address book.
在你的地址簿中找到联系人。
It's not starting top to bottom or bottom up.
它不是从上到下或从下到上开始。
It's probably going roughly to the middle
它可能大致会去到中间
and then doing the top half or the bottom half, repeating again and again.
然后处理上半部分或下半部分，一次又一次地重复。
So these ideas are everywhere.
所以这些想法无处不在。
And hopefully, you end up finding just the one
希望你能最终找到你唯一想要的那个
person you're looking for or in your case,
人，或者在你这种情况中，
the one person last standing who should have theoretically
最后一个站立的人，理论上应该是
had the count of everyone because if each of you started by representing 1,
拥有所有人的计数，因为如果你们每个人一开始代表 1，
effectively handed off your number, handed off your number,
有效地传递了你的数字，传递了你的数字，
handed off your number, it theoretically should have coalesced
传递了你的数字，理论上它应该会汇聚
in that final person standing.
在最后一个站立的人身上。
So let's consider the connection now between this idea
所以现在让我们考虑这个想法
and what we introduced last week, which was this idea of very simple data
与我们上周介绍的内容之间的联系，也就是非常简单的数据的概念
structures in your computer's memory-- like, actually using this memory as
结构存在于你的计算机内存中——就像真正地将内存用作
though it's kind of a grid of bytes.
字节网格。
Each one of these squares, recall, represents 1 byte or 8 bits.
请记住，每个方块代表 1 个字节或 8 个比特。
And we can get rid of the hardware and sort
我们可以摆脱硬件，并排序
of abstract it away as just this grid of memory or this canvas.
将其抽象为这个内存网格或画布。
And then we introduced arrays last week.
然后我们上周引入了数组。
And what was the key definition of an array?
数组的关键定义是什么？
How would you describe an array?
你如何描述数组？
What is it, anyone?
是什么，有人知道吗？
What's an array?
什么是数组？
Yeah, in the middle.
是的，中间那个人。
A collection.
一个集合。
And I don't love data types only because in C, it tends to be the same type.
我不喜欢数据类型，只是因为在 C 语言中，它往往是相同的类型。
So a collection of data.
所以，数据的集合。
I do like that.
我喜欢这样。
But there's one other key characteristic.
但还有另一个关键特征。
Do you want to be more precise?
你想更精确一点吗？
It's not just a collection--
它不仅仅是一个集合——
something about where it is.
关于它在哪里。
Potentially strings.
可能是字符串。
But strings are just an example of putting char, char, char, char.
但字符串只是一个例子，就是将 char、char、char、char 放在一起。
It could certainly be integers or floating point values.
它当然可以是整数或浮点数。
Another characteristic?
还有其他特征吗？
Sorry?
你说什么？
It's not necessarily ordered.
它不一定是有序的。
Actually, we'll come back to that today.
实际上，我们今天会回到这个问题。
It could be in any order.
它可以是任何顺序。
And certainly a string isn't necessarily in sorted order.
当然，字符串也不一定是有序的。
It's in whatever the word is.
它就是那个词的顺序。
It's a list in concept.
从概念上来说，它是一个列表。
But there was something key about where we put things in memory.
但是，在我们把东西放在内存中的位置，有一个关键点。
Yeah?
是吧？
Consecutive-- the memory is consecutive, a.k.a., contiguous.
连续的——内存是连续的，也就是相邻的。
An array is important in C because, yes, it's a list of values.
数组在 C 语言中很重要，因为它确实是一个值的列表。
Yes, it's a collection of values.
是的，它是一个值的集合。
But the real key distinction in an array in C is that it's contiguous.
但在 C 语言中，数组的真正关键区别在于它是连续的。
The bytes are back to back to back somewhere in the computer's memory,
字节在计算机内存中的某个地方，挨在一起。
at least for any given data type, be it an int, a float, a bigger string.
至少对于任何给定的数据类型，无论是 int、float 还是更大的字符串。
All of the characters are back to back to back in the computer's memory,
所有字符都紧挨着，在计算机的内存中。
not spread all out, even if you have space elsewhere.
即使你其他地方有空间，它们也不分散。
So with that said, we can actually start to solve problems with that mindset.
所以，我们可以开始用这种思维方式解决问题。
And for instance, if I kind of pare this down to just an abstract array of size
例如，如果我把这缩减成一个抽象的数组，大小
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, for instance, suppose
是 1、2、3、4、5、6、7，例如，假设
that there are these numbers inside of this array of memory.
在这个内存数组中，有这些数字。
So here are seven integers or ints in C. I have in this case
所以这里有七个整数，或 C 语言中的 int，在本例中，
sorted them just to make the numbers pop out as obviously smallest to largest.
我排序了它们，只是为了让数字看起来明显地从小到大排列。
But the catch with C is that if I were to ask you
但 C 语言中的问题是，如果我问你
or if you were to ask the computer through code to find you the number 50,
或者你想要通过代码让计算机找到数字 50，
well, obviously, every human in this room
那么，很明显，房间里的每个人
just found it obviously right there because we kind of have this bird's eye
立即找到了它，因为它就在那里，因为我们有一个鸟瞰的
view of the whole memory at once.
视角，可以一次性看到整个内存。
But the computer ironically does not have
但具有讽刺意味的是，计算机没有
that bird's eye view of its own memory.
它就像一只鸟，只能鸟瞰自己的记忆。
It can only look at each location one at a time.
它一次只能查看一个位置。
So if you really were to do this like a computer, you would kind of have to,
所以如果你真的想像电脑一样做这件事，你必须得...
like, shield your eye and only look at one number at a time from left
就像遮住你的眼睛，一次只看一个数字，从左
to right, from right to left, or in any order
到右，从右到左，或者按任何顺序
in order to find is the 50 actually there.
来找到50是否真的在那里。
You can't just take a step back.
你不能后退一步。
And boom, it pops out at you.
然后，它就会跳出来。
So this is kind of analogous, this array,
所以这有点类似，这个数组，
to being like a set of gym lockers or school
就像是一排健身房的储物柜，或者学校
lockers like this where the doors are actually closed by default.
的储物柜，默认情况下，门都是关着的。
The numbers are in there.
数字都在里面。
But the doors are closed, which is to say the computer
但门是关着的，也就是说，电脑
and we can't actually look.
我们实际上不能看。
So we couldn't find yellow lockers.
所以我们找不到黄色的储物柜。
But we did find red lockers here.
但我们在这里找到了红色的储物柜。
And so I propose that you think of these lockers on the stage
因此，我建议你把舞台上的这些储物柜
here of which there are seven as well as representing an array.
想象成一个数组，它们总共有七个。
And just so we have some terminology, notice that I've labeled these bracket
为了方便理解，请注意我已经给这些括号标了号
0, bracket 1, bracket 2, 3, 4, 5 and 6.
0、括号 1、括号 2、3、4、5 和 6。
And the bracket notation recalls the new syntax
这种括号符号提醒我们上周学到的新语法
from last week that lets you index into--
它允许你在数组中进行索引，也就是...
go to a specific spot inside of an array.
访问数组中的特定位置。
And notice that even though there are seven lockers,
注意，尽管有七个储物柜，
I only counted as high as six.
但我只数到六。
But again, that's just a side effect of our generally counting from 0.
但再次强调，这仅仅是因为我们通常从 0 开始计数。
So 0 through 6 or 0 through n minus 1 because if there are n equal 7 lockers,
所以从 0 到 6，或者从 0 到 n 减 1，因为如果总共有 n 个储物柜，也就是 7 个，
n minus 1 is 6.
n 减 1 就是 6。
So that's the left bound and the right bound respectively.
所以这就是左右边界。
So suppose that we were to use these lockers as representing a problem,
假设我们将这些储物柜看成一个问题，
like we want to find an actual number behind these doors.
比如，我们想找到这些门后面真正的数字。
So this is actually a very common problem in the real world.
这实际上是现实世界中非常常见的问题。
And you and I take for granted every day that big companies like Google
你我每天都理所当然地认为，像谷歌这样的大公司
and Microsoft and others, like, do this for us
以及微软等其他公司，都在为我们做这件事
constantly, not to mention AI doing something similar nowadays,
而且他们一直在做，更不用说现在的 AI 也在做类似的事情，
searching for information.
搜索信息。
And we'll focus on some basics first that
我们首先要关注一些基础知识，这些知识
will lead us to more sophisticated algorithms ultimately.
最终将引导我们了解更复杂的算法。
But all we're going to talk about fundamentally
但从根本上来说，我们讨论的都是
is this same picture from week zero and from week one and from week two
从第一周到第二周，我们一直看到的这个画面
where here is a problem to be solved.
这里有一个需要解决的问题。
So if for instance, the input to this problem is an array of numbers--
例如，这个问题的输入是一个数字数组，
an array of seven numbers--
一个包含七个数字的数组，
I can't see them all at once-- but I'm looking for something like the number
我无法同时看到所有数字，但我正在寻找类似数字
50--
50 的东西，
ultimately, I want to get back out.
最终，我想要得到一个结果。
I claim true or false.
我要得到真或假的结果。
Like, the number 50 is there.
也就是说，数字 50 是否存在。
Or it is not.
或者它不是。
That's one way of thinking about the search problem.
这是一种思考搜索问题的方法。
Find me some piece of data if it's there.
如果数据存在，请找到它。
Otherwise, tell me that it's not-- true or false, respectively.
否则，告诉我它不存在 - 分别为真或假。
So the algorithm inside of this black box,
所以这个黑盒内部的算法，
though, is where we're going to actually have to do some thinking
然而，是我们真正需要思考的地方。
and actually figure out how best to find the number or the data we care about.
并真正弄清楚如何最好地找到我们关心的数字或数据。
And even though we'll use numbers to keep things simple today,
即使我们今天使用数字来简化事物，
you could certainly generalize this to web pages or contacts
你当然可以将其推广到网页或联系人
or any other type of information that are in some computer or database more
或任何其他类型的存储在计算机或数据库中的信息。
generally.
一般来说。
So maybe to keep things interesting, could we
为了保持趣味性，我们可以
get-- how about two volunteers?
找两位志愿者怎么样？
Wow, that was fast.
哇，太快了。
OK, come on down.
好的，请过来。
And how about one other volunteer?
再找一位志愿者怎么样？
I'll go over here.
我到这边去。
OK, how about you?
好的，你呢？
Come on down.
请过来。
Sure, round of applause for our volunteers.
当然，为我们的志愿者鼓掌。
[APPLAUSE]
[鼓掌]
OK, welcome.
好的，欢迎。
Come on over.
请过来。
Do you want to introduce yourself to the group?
你想向大家介绍一下自己吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
观众：[听不清]
DAVID MALAN: Like a few seconds is fine.
大卫·马兰：几秒钟就好了。
AUDIENCE: Hi, I'm Sam.
观众：你好，我是萨姆。
I am not a CS concentration.
我不是计算机科学专业的。
DAVID MALAN: [LAUGHS] So what are you?
大卫·马兰：[笑]那你是什么专业呢？
Do you know yet?
你知道了吗？
AUDIENCE: Applied math.
观众：应用数学。
DAVID MALAN: OK.
大卫·马兰：好的。
Nice.
不错。
Nice to meet you.
很高兴认识你。
Welcome.
欢迎。
And?
还有呢？
AUDIENCE: Hi, I'm Louis.
观众：你好，我是路易斯。
I'm from first year, Matthews.
我是一年级生，住在马修斯宿舍。
And I'm going to do Econ with Stats.
我准备学习经济学和统计学。
DAVID MALAN: Oh, you're in Matthews too?
大卫·马兰：哦，你也是住在马修斯宿舍吗？
OK.
好的。
[CHUCKLES] I was in Matthews too, so Matthews South?
[轻笑] 我也住在马修斯宿舍，住在南区吗？
Oh, wow.
哦，哇。
Oh, my god.
我的天啊。
I was room 201.
我住在201号房间。
AUDIENCE: 103.
观众：103号。
DAVID MALAN: Fifth floor--
大卫·马兰：五楼 -
all right, so anyhow.
好吧，总之。
And so we have Louis and your name?
所以我们有路易斯，你的名字呢？
AUDIENCE: Sam.
观众：萨姆。
DAVID MALAN: Sam.
大卫·马兰：萨姆。
Louis and Sam.
路易斯和萨姆。
So Louis and I are going to step off to the side for just a moment because Sam,
所以路易斯和我将退到一旁一会儿，因为萨姆，
we have a problem for you to solve.
我们有一个问题需要你解决。
This feels a little bit like Price Is Right.
这有点像“价格对了”。
But behind you are these seven lockers.
但你身后有这七个储物柜。
And we'd like you to just find us the number 50.
我们希望你找到50号。
That's all the information you get.
这就是你得到的所有信息。
But we'd like you to then explain how you go about finding it.
但我们希望你解释一下你是如何找到它的。
AUDIENCE: Wait, are they in order or anything?
观众：等等，它们是有顺序的吗？
Or [INAUDIBLE] it just kind of [INAUDIBLE]??
还是[听不清]它只是[听不清]？
DAVID MALAN: Find us the number 50.
大卫·马兰：找到50号。
And then tell us how you found it.
然后告诉我们你是怎么找到的。
OK, what was in there, just so the audience knows.
好吧，里面是什么，让观众知道一下。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID MALAN: Yes.
大卫·马兰：是的。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
AUDIENCE: It was $10, a very, very big $10 bill.
观众：是10美元，一张非常非常大的10美元钞票。
DAVID MALAN: OK.
大卫·马兰：好的。
AUDIENCE: Fake money.
观众：假钱。
DAVID MALAN: OK.
大卫·马兰：好的。
AUDIENCE: That was $100.
观众：那是100美元。
$1.
1美元。
$5.
5美元。
OK, I'm not lucky.
好的，我不走运。
Oh, I found it.
哦，我找到了。
DAVID MALAN: Nice.
大卫·马兰：不错。
Take it out and so people can believe.
拿出来，让大家相信。
All right, wonderful.
好的，太棒了。
So you found the 50.
所以你找到了50号。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
And now if you could explain.
现在如果你能解释一下。
I'll take that.
我接受。
If you could explain, what was your algorithm?
如果你能解释一下，你的算法是什么？
What was the step-by-step approach you took?
你采取的逐步方法是什么？
AUDIENCE: I didn't really have one.
观众：我并没有什么特别的算法。
I just started on one end.
我只是从一端开始。
And I went down because it wasn't in order or anything.
然后我往下走，因为它们没有顺序。
So I just kept going until I found it.
所以我一直往下走，直到找到它。
DAVID MALAN: OK, so that's actually pretty fair.
大卫·马兰：好吧，这其实很公平。
And in fact, let's step forward here.
事实上，让我们继续。
Carter's going to very secretly kind of shuffle the numbers
卡特将非常秘密地以一种特殊的新排列方式打乱这些数字
in a particular new arrangement here.
这里。
And so you really went from right to left.
所以你实际上是从右到左。
And I dare say maybe going from left to right might be equivalent.
我敢说也许从左到右可能是等效的。
But could she have done better?
但她能做得更好吗？
Could she have done better, because that took 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 steps?
她能做得更好吗，因为这花了1、2、3、4、5步？
Could Sam have done better?
萨姆能做得更好吗？
Sure.
当然。
How?
怎么做？
OK, so you got lucky.
好吧，你运气不错。
You could have found the number in one step.
你本可以一步就找到这个数字。
Although, luck isn't really an algorithm.
不过，运气本身并不是一种算法。
It really isn't a step-by-step approach.
它真的不是一个循序渐进的过程。
So another thought?
还有其他想法吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] dollar bills--
观众：[听不清] 美元钞票 -
sort them in order?
按顺序排列它们？
DAVID MALAN: Oh, interesting.
大卫·马兰：哦，很有趣。
So you could have taken out all of the dollar bills, sorted them,
所以你可以把所有的美元钞票拿出来，把它们排序，
put them back in, and then you probably could have done something
放回去，然后你可能就能做一些
like the divide and conquer approach.
类似于分而治之的方法。
AUDIENCE: I didn't know I was allowed to do that.
观众：我不知道我可以这样做。
DAVID MALAN: No, you weren't allowed to.
大卫·马兰：不，你不能。
So that's fine.
所以没关系。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID MALAN: But that would be a valid algorithm.
大卫·马兰：但这将是一个有效的算法。
Although, it sounds very inefficient to do all this work just
不过，仅仅为了找到数字 50 就做所有这些工作听起来非常低效，因为在做这些工作的时候，
to find the number 50 because in doing that work,
她已经找到过 50 一次了。
she would've found the 50 once.
但这可能是一个合理的解决方案
But that might actually be a reasonable solution
如果她打算反复搜索，不仅仅搜索 7 个数字
if she plans to search again and again and again, not just for seven numbers
而是可能很多数字。
but maybe a lot of numbers.
也许你确实想在前期投入一些成本，以及所有数据
Maybe you do want to incur some cost up front and all the data
以便更快地找到它。
so as to find it faster.
但让我们更系统地来做这件事。
But let's do this a little more methodically.
我们再稍微偏离一下。
We'll step off to the side once more.
按照惯例，如果你想继续 - 我们需要这个吗？
And just by convention, if you want to go ahead and-- do we need this?
好的。
OK.
观众：明白了。
AUDIENCE: Got it.
好的，我们从左到右。
DAVID MALAN: OK, let's go from left to right.
是的。
Yep.
请继续展示给大家看这些数字，
And go ahead and show everyone the numbers just
以证明这里没有作假。
to prove that there's no funny business here.
观众：20。
AUDIENCE: 20.
大卫·马兰：[笑]
DAVID MALAN: [LAUGHS]
观众：哦，好吧。
AUDIENCE: Oh, OK.
500。
500.
大卫·马兰：不错。
DAVID MALAN: Nice.
观众：10。
AUDIENCE: 10.
大卫·马兰：嗯哼。
DAVID MALAN: Mm-hm.
所以看起来这次也没有排序。
So it doesn't sound like it's sorted, either, this time.
观众：5。
AUDIENCE: Five.
大卫·马兰：不错。
DAVID MALAN: Nice.
还有？
And?
观众：100。
AUDIENCE: 100.
大卫·马兰：哦，太接近了。
DAVID MALAN: Oh, so close.
观众：[听不清]
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
我知道。
DAVID MALAN: I know.
我们只是在逗你玩。
Now we're just messing with you.
观众：1。
AUDIENCE: 1.
DAVID MALAN: OK, and lastly?
大卫·马兰：好的，最后一个？
AUDIENCE: [GASPS] 50.
观众：[倒吸一口气] 50。
DAVID MALAN: Very well done.
大卫·马兰：做得很好。
OK, so nicely done.
好的，做得很好。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
And so thank you.
所以谢谢你。
So this is a say whether she goes from left to right or right to left,
所以这是一个说她从左到右还是从右到左，
like, the performance of that algorithm just going linearly
就像，那个算法的性能只是线性地
from side to side really depends on where the number ends up being.
从一侧到另一侧真的取决于数字最终的位置。
And it kind of does boil down to luck.
这确实归结为运气。
And so that was kind of the best you could do because I dare say,
所以那是你能做的最好的，因为我敢说，
had you gone linearly from right to left-- and go ahead to reset--
如果你从右到左线性地走——继续重置——
had you gone from right to left, that time you would have gotten lucky.
如果你从右到左走，那一次你就走运了。
So on average, it might just kind of work out.
所以平均来说，它可能只是奏效。
And so half the time, it takes you maybe half as many steps--
所以有一半的时间，它可能只花费你一半的步骤——
half the number of lockers to find it on average
平均来说，只需要一半的储物柜就能找到它
because sometimes it's in the one end.
因为有时它在一边。
Sometimes it's on the other end.
有时它在另一边。
Sometimes it's smack dab in the middle.
有时它正好在中间。
But we're going to give you the option now,
但现在我们要给你一个选择，
Louis, of knowing that it's sorted.
路易斯，知道它已经排序了。
So we're going to take away the microphone from you.
所以我们要拿走你的麦克风。
But stay on up here with us.
但留在这里和我们在一起。
And you are now given the assumption that the numbers
现在，你被告知这些数字
are this time sorted from smallest to largest, left to right.
这一次是从最小到最大，从左到右排序。
And might you want to take more of a divide and conquer approach here?
你是否想在这里采取更多的分治方法？
Wait a minute.
等一下。
AUDIENCE: [LAUGHS]
观众：[笑]
DAVID MALAN: What might you do as your algorithm, Louis?
大卫·马兰：路易斯，你的算法可能会怎么做？
AUDIENCE: Well, I think I know all the numbers, right?
观众：嗯，我想我知道所有数字，对吧？
It's 1, 5--
它是 1，5——
DAVID MALAN: Oh, damn it.
大卫·马兰：哦，该死。
AUDIENCE: 10, 20, 50.
观众：10，20，50。
DAVID MALAN: OK, so Louis has some memory, as we'll say.
大卫·马兰：好的，我们可以说路易斯有一些记忆。
OK.
好的。
AUDIENCE: But assuming if I didn't have memory.
观众：但假设如果我没有记忆。
DAVID MALAN: OK, assuming if you didn't have
大卫·马兰：好的，假设你没有
memory, where would you start first?
记忆，你会先从哪里开始？
AUDIENCE: I would probably start in the middle.
观众：我可能会从中间开始。
DAVID MALAN: OK, go ahead.
大卫·马兰：好的，继续。
Go in the middle.
去中间。
And what do you see?
你看到了什么？
AUDIENCE: 20.
观众：20。
DAVID MALAN: 20.
大卫·马兰：20。
OK, what does that mean now for you?
好的，现在对你来说意味着什么？
AUDIENCE: So now that means that since4 I know there's some numbers bigger,
观众：所以现在这意味着，既然我知道有一些数字更大，
I'll go to the right.
我会去右边。
DAVID MALAN: Good.
大卫·马兰：很好。
So you can tear the problem in half, so to speak.
所以你可以将问题一分为二，这么说吧。
As per week zero, skip all of the lockers on the left.
就像第零周一样，跳过左边所有的储物柜。
And now go where relative to these three?
现在相对于这三个，你要去哪里？
AUDIENCE: Relative to the middle.
观众：相对于中间。
DAVID MALAN: OK.
大卫·马兰：好的。
AUDIENCE: So maybe [? you ?] don't know what's on the right-hand side.
观众：所以也许你不知道右边是什么。
And so now it's 100.
所以现在是 100。
DAVID MALAN: OK, nice.
大卫·马兰：好的，不错。
AUDIENCE: So the 50 must be between 20 and 100.
观众：所以 50 必须在 20 和 100 之间。
So it must be this one.
所以一定是这个。
DAVID MALAN: Indeed.
大卫·马兰：确实。
So a round of applause for Louis for getting this right this time.
所以让我们为路易斯这次答对了而鼓掌。
[APPLAUSE]
[鼓掌]
We have some lovely parting gifts, since we're using monopoly money.
我们有一些可爱的临别礼物，因为我们使用的是大富翁的钱。
So it's not actual money.
所以这不是真钱。
But this is the Cambridge edition Harvard Square and all for both of you.
但这是剑桥版哈佛广场，给你们两个。
So welcome.
欢迎。
Thank you so much.
非常感谢。
[APPLAUSE]
[鼓掌]
So Louis was actually getting particularly clever there
所以路易斯实际上在那里变得特别聪明
when his first instinct was to just remember
当他第一反应只是记住
what were all the numbers and then sort of deduce
所有的数字，然后推断出来
where the 50 must obviously be.
50 显然必须在哪里。
So that's on us.
所以这算我们。
Like, ideally, we would have completely changed the dollar amount so
理想情况下，我们应该完全改变美元金额，这样
that he couldn't use that information.
他就无法使用这些信息。
But it turns out Louie's instinct there to figure out where the number should
但事实证明，路易斯在那里的直觉，弄清楚数字应该在哪里
be and jump right there--
并直接跳到那里——
index into that exact location-- is actually a technique.
索引到那个确切的位置——实际上是一种技巧。
And it's a technique we'll talk about in future classes
这是一种技巧，我们将在未来的课程中讨论
where you actually do take into account the information
在那里你实际上考虑了信息
and go right where you want.
并直接去你想去的地方。
It's an example of what we'll eventually call hashing, so to speak,
这可以算作我们最终将要称为散列的一个例子，
in a concept called hash tables.
在一个叫做散列表的概念中。
But for now, let's try to formalize the algorithms
但现在，让我们尝试将这两个志愿者的算法形式化
that both of these volunteers kind of intuitively
这两个志愿者直觉地想出来的，第一个和第二个。
came up with, first and second.
第一个和第二个。
And we'll slap some names on them.
我们给他们取一些名字。
So the first, and I've hinted at this, is what we would call linear search.
所以第一个，我暗示过，是我们所说的线性搜索。
Anytime you search from left to right or from right to left,
无论何时你从左到右或从右到左搜索，
it's generally called linear search.
它通常被称为线性搜索。
Why?
为什么？
Because you're kind of walking in a line, no matter which direction
因为你在一条线上行走，无论你朝哪个方向
you're going.
行走。
But now for today's purposes, let's see if we can't truly
但现在为了今天，让我们看看我们是否可以真正地
formalize what our volunteers' algorithms were by translating them,
将我们志愿者的算法形式化，通过翻译它们，
not necessarily to code yet, but pseudocode.
不一定用代码，而是伪代码。
See if we can't map it to English-like syntax that gets the ideas across.
看看我们是否可以将其映射到类似英语的语法，以便表达这些想法。
So I dare say, the first algorithm, even though she went from right to left,
所以我想说，第一个算法，尽管她从右到左，
then from left to right, might look like this.
然后从左到右，可能看起来像这样。
For each door from left to right, she checked if 50 is behind the door
对于从左到右的每一扇门，她检查了 50 是否在门后
as by looking at it.
通过查看它。
If it was behind the door, then she returned true.
如果数字在门后面，她就会返回真值。
Like, yes, this is the 50.
就像，是的，这是数字50。
That didn't happen on the first iteration, though.
不过，这在第一次迭代时没有发生。
So she moved on again and again.
所以她一次又一次地继续寻找。
And now notice the indentation here is just
现在请注意，这里的缩进只是
as important as it was in week zero.
和第零周一样重要。
Notice that only at the very bottom of this algorithm
请注意，只有在这个算法的最底部
do I propose returning false.
我才建议返回假值。
But it's not indented inside of this pseudocode.
但是它并没有在这个伪代码中缩进。
Why?
为什么？
Well, because if I had changed it to be this,
因为如果我把它改成这样，
what would be the logical bug in this version of that algorithm?
在这个版本的算法中，逻辑错误是什么？
Yeah?
是吗？
Exactly.
没错。
If she had opened the first door, found it to be the wrong number if it says
如果她打开了第一扇门，发现它不是正确的数字，如果上面写着
else-- if it's not behind the door, then return false--
否则，如果数字不在门后，就返回假值——
that would erroneously conclude the 50's not there,
这将错误地得出结论，数字50不在那里，
even though it could certainly be among those other doors.
尽管它肯定可能在其他门中。
So this first version of the code where the return false is
所以这段代码的第一个版本，其中返回假值是
sort of left indented, so to speak, and the very last thing
可以说，被留下了缩进，并且是最后一件事情
you do if you don't previously return true, that just
如果你之前没有返回真值，你需要做的事情，就是
makes sure that we're handling all possible cases.
确保我们处理了所有可能的情况。
But let's make this maybe a little more technical.
但是让我们把它变得更加技术化一些。
This is how a computer scientist or a programmer
这就是计算机科学家或程序员
would likely express this instead.
可能会这样表达。
Instead of just drawing it in broad strokes,
而不是仅仅用概括性的笔触来绘制它，
it's actually fine to kind of steal some of the syntax from languages like C
实际上可以从像C这样的语言中借用一些语法
and actually use some of the indices or indexes like 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6,
并实际使用一些索引，比如0、1、2、3、4、5、6，
to represent the pieces of data we care about.
来表示我们关心的数据片段。
So this is a little more precise.
所以这更精确一些。
For i-- like a variable i-- from the value 0 to n minus 1,
对于i——就像一个变量i——从值0到n减1，
so in the case of seven doors, this is like saying, for i starting at 0,
所以对于七扇门的情况，这就像是在说，对于从0开始的i，
going up to 6, do the following.
一直到6，执行以下操作。
If the number 50 is behind the doors array--
如果数字50在门的数组后面——
so I'm using array syntax, even though this is technically still pseudocode--
所以我在使用数组语法，即使这在技术上仍然是伪代码——
if the ith location of my doors array has the number 50, return true.
如果我的门数组的第i个位置包含数字50，就返回真值。
Otherwise, if you do that again and again and again--
否则，如果你一遍又一遍地做——
n total times-- and you still don't find it, you want to return false.
总共n次——你仍然没有找到它，你就需要返回假值。
So we introduced this.
所以我们引入了这个。
This is just an example of how you can start to borrow ideas from actual code
这只是一个例子，说明了如何开始从实际代码中借用想法
to paint the picture even more precisely of what
来更精确地描绘你想要你的同事做什么，什么
it is you want a colleague to do, what it
是你想让你的同事做，你的代码
is you want your code to do, ultimately, by sort
最终想让它做，通过某种方式
of borrowing these ideas from code and incorporating it into our pseudocode.
从代码中借用这些想法，并将它们融入我们的伪代码中。
But what about the second algorithm here,
但是这里第二个算法呢，
the second algorithm, whereby he took a divide and conquer approach,
第二个算法，他采用了分而治之的方法，
starting in the middle and then going right and then going left.
从中间开始，然后向右，然后向左。
Well, it turns out this is generally called binary search.
事实证明，这通常被称为二分搜索。
Bi implying two, because you're either going
“二”表示两个，因为你要么
with the left half or the right half again and again.
选择左半部分，要么选择右半部分，一次又一次。
This is literally what we've been talking about since week zero
这正是我们从第一周就开始讨论的
when I searched the phone book.
当我搜索电话簿时。
That too was binary search, dividing and dividing and dividing in half and half.
那也是二分搜索，不断地将范围一分为二。
So if we were to draw some pseudocode for this,
所以，如果我们要为此写一些伪代码，
I would propose that we could do something like this.
我建议我们可以这样做。
If 50 is behind the middle door, then we got lucky.
如果50在中间门后面，那我们很幸运。
Just return true.
直接返回true。
Else if the 50 is less than the value at the middle door--
否则，如果50小于中间门的数值
so if it's smaller than the middle door--
如果它小于中间门
I want to search to the left.
我想搜索左侧。
So I can say search left half.
所以我可以说搜索左半部分。
Else if 50 is greater than the middle door, I want to search to the right.
否则，如果50大于中间门，我想搜索右侧。
And I think that's almost everything, right?
我想这几乎囊括了所有情况，对吧？
Is there a fourth possible case?
还有第四种情况吗？
What else could happen?
还有什么可能发生？
Good.
好。
So taking into account that if there are no doors left or no doors
所以，考虑到如果门已经搜索完，或者一开始就没有门
to begin with, we better handle that case
我们最好处理这种情况
so that we don't induce one of those spinning beach balls,
这样就不会出现电脑卡死的状况，
so that the computer doesn't freeze or crash.
也不会导致电脑崩溃。
There's really four possible scenarios in searching for information.
在搜索信息时，实际上只有四种可能的情况。
It's either in the middle or to the left or to the right.
它要么在中间，要么在左侧，要么在右侧。
Or it's just not there at all.
或者它根本不存在。
And so I sort of slip that in at the end because technically, that's a question
所以，我在最后加入了这个，因为从技术角度来说，这是一个问题
you should ask first because if there's no doors, there's no work to be done.
你应该首先询问，因为如果没有门，就没有工作要做。
But logically, this is the juicy part-- the other three questions
但从逻辑上讲，这是核心部分——另外三个问题
that you might ask yourself.
你可能会问自己。
So this then might be the pseudocode for binary search.
所以，这可能是二分搜索的伪代码。
And we could make it more technical.
我们可以把它做得更专业一些。
And this is where it kind of escalates quickly syntactically.
而这里，它在语法上迅速升级。
But I'm just using the same kind of syntax.
但我只是使用同样的语法。
If doors in my pseudocode represents an array of doors,
如果伪代码中的“门”代表一个门数组，
well, then doors bracket middle is just a pseudocode-like way
那么，括号内的“门”中间，就是一个类似伪代码的方式
of saying go to the middle door in that array.
来说明在那个数组中，指向中间门。
And then notice, else if 50 is less than-- that middle value--
然后请注意，否则，如果50小于中间值
then search doors bracket 0, so the leftmost one--
那么搜索“门”括号0，也就是最左边的那个
through doors middle minus 1.
一直到“门”中间减1。
So you don't need to waste time researching the middle door.
所以，你不需要浪费时间搜索中间门。
So I say middle minus 1 so that I scooch over slightly to the left, so to speak.
所以我说是中间减1，这样说，我稍微向左移动了一点。
Else if 50 is greater than the value at the middle door,
否则，如果50大于中间门的数值，
then you want to search 1 over to the right,
那么你想要搜索右侧的1，
so middle plus 1 among those doors, through the last door, which is not n,
因此，在这些门中，从中间加1开始，一直到最后一个门，这不是n，
because we start counting at 0, but n minus 1.
因为我们从0开始计数，而是n减1。
And the rest of the algorithm is the same.
其余的算法相同。
This is just a little more precise.
这仅仅是更精确了一些。
And I dare say, when writing a program in C or any language,
我敢说，在用 C 语言或任何语言编写程序时，
like, honestly, starting in pseudocode like this will generally make it
说实话，像这样用伪代码开始通常会让它
much easier to write the actual code.
更容易编写实际代码。
So in fact, in this and future problem sets, do get into the habit,
所以实际上，在这个和未来的问题集中，要养成习惯，
especially if you're struggling getting started-- just
特别是如果你在开始时遇到了困难——就
write things out in English and maybe high level
用英文写下来，也许用更高级别的
English a little more like this.
英语，更像这样。
Then as a version two, go in with your keyboard or paper, pencil.
然后作为第二版，使用你的键盘或纸笔。
And make it a little more precise using some code-like syntax.
并使用一些类似代码的语法使其更精确一些。
And then I dare say in version 3, you can now
然后我敢说在第三版中，你现在可以
translate this pretty much verbatim to C code.
几乎逐字逐句地将其翻译成 C 代码。
The only headache is going to be rounding issues
唯一的麻烦是舍入问题
with integers because if you divide an integer and you a fraction,
对于整数，因为如果你除以一个整数，而你又得到一个小数，
it's going to truncate, so all that kind of headache.
它将被截断，所以所有这些都会让人头疼。
But you can work through that by just thinking
但是你可以通过思考来解决这个问题
through what's going to get truncated when
在舍入时，哪些部分会被截断
you round down or up as a solution.
你向上或向下舍入作为解决方案。
Any questions, though, on this pseudocode
关于这个伪代码，有什么问题吗？
for either linear or binary search as we've defined them--
无论是我们定义的线性搜索还是二分搜索——
linear or binary search--
线性搜索或二分搜索——
no?
没有？
All right, well, let's consider then a bit more
好吧，那么让我们再考虑一下
formally a question that we'll come back to in the future in future classes
更正式地讲，这个问题我们将在未来的课程中再回来讨论
as well.
也一样。
What is the running time of these algorithms?
这些算法的运行时间是多少？
What is, that is to say, the efficiency of these algorithms?
也就是说，这些算法的效率如何？
And how do we actually measure the efficiency of an algorithm?
我们如何实际衡量算法的效率？
Is it with a stopwatch or with some other mechanism?
是用秒表还是其他机制？
Well, I propose that we think back to this picture
好吧，我建议我们回过头来看看这幅图
here, whereby this, again, was representative of both the phone book
在这里，这，再次，代表了电话簿
example from week zero and theoretically, bug aside,
第零周的例子，从理论上来说，除了错误之外，
the attendance counting algorithm from earlier today, whereby
今天早些时候的出勤计数算法，其中
this same green line theoretically represents how much time it should have
同一条绿线理论上代表了我们作为团队应该花费多少时间
taken us as a group to count ourselves.
来数我们自己。
Why?
为什么？
Because if maybe another class comes in and doubles
因为如果另一个班级进来，人数翻倍
the size of the number of humans in this room, no big deal.
这个房间里的人数，没什么大不了的。
That's just one more step or one more iteration of the loop
那只是一步或循环的一次迭代
because half of the people would anyway sit down.
因为一半的人都会坐下。
So this green algorithm still represents the faster theoretical algorithm today.
所以这个绿色算法仍然代表了今天理论上更快的算法。
And so recall that we described these things more mathematically as n.
所以，回想一下，我们用数学方法将这些东西描述为 n。
So this was one page at a time or one person at a time.
所以，这是每次一页或每次一个人。
This was two people or two pages at a time.
这是每次两个人或两页。
So it's twice as fast, so if n is the number of people or pages
所以速度快一倍，所以如果 n 是人数或页数
and divided by 2 is the total number of steps.
而除以 2 就是总步数。
And then this one got a little mathy, but log base 2 of n.
然后这个就有点数学了，但它是以 2 为底的对数 n。
And log base 2 of n just means what is the value when you take n and divide it
2 的对数底为n，意思是在你取n并将其除以2 时，得到的值是多少
in two by 2 again and again and again and again
再除以2，再除以2，一直重复下去
until you're left with just one page or one person standing.
直到只剩下一个页面或一个人站着。
But in the world of running times, it turns out that being this precise
但在运行时间的世界里，事实证明，做到如此精确
is not that intellectually interesting.
在智力上并不那么有趣。
And it sort of devolves into lower level math.
它有点退化成了低级别的数学。
It's just not necessary when having discussions
在讨论时，这并不必要
about the efficiency of an algorithm or even code that you've written.
关于算法的效率，甚至是你写的代码的效率。
So generally, a computer scientist, when asked
因此，一般来说，当被问及
what's the running time of your algorithm
你的算法的运行时间
or what's the efficiency of your algorithm or more
或你的算法的效率，或者更多地
generally how good or bad is your algorithm,
一般来说，你的算法有多好或多坏，
they'll talk about it being on the order of some number of steps.
他们会谈论它是某种数量级的步骤。
This is a phrase you'll hear increasingly in computer science
你会越来越多地听到这个词语在计算机科学中
where you can kind of wave your hand at it.
在那里你可以对此挥手。
Like, oh, the lower level details don't matter that much.
就像，哦，低级别的细节并没有那么重要。
All you care about in broad strokes are certain numbers
你关心的只是某些数字的大致范围
that will add up the most.
这些数字加起来最多。
And in fact, when computer scientists talk
事实上，当计算机科学家谈论
about the efficiency of algorithms, they tend
算法的效率时，他们倾向于
to throw away constant factors, so literally, numbers like 2
丢弃常数因子，也就是像2这样的数字
that might be dividing here or a base here.
可能在这里除，或在这里作底数。
So for instance, these two algorithms to a computer scientist
例如，这两个算法对计算机科学家来说
would sort be the same.
应该是一样的。
Like, yeah, it's technically twice as fast.
就像，是的，它技术上快两倍。
But look at the lines.
但看看这些线。
I mean, they're practically the same and this one here too, log base 2-- sure.
我的意思是，它们实际上是一样的，这个也是，2 为底的对数——当然。
But if you remember from math class, you can change the base of any logarithm
但是如果你记得数学课上的内容，你可以很容易地改变任何对数的底
from one number to another pretty easily.
从一个数字到另一个数字。
So ah, let's just generalize it as log of n.
所以，让我们将其概括为 log n。
It doesn't really matter fundamentally what the numbers actually are.
从根本上来说，这些数字的实际值并不重要。
And honestly, if we zoom out slightly so that the y-axis and the x-axis
而且，老实说，如果我们稍微缩小一点，使得 y 轴和 x 轴
get even bigger, honestly, these first two algorithms
变得更大，老实说，这两个算法
really do start to resemble each other closer and closer.
确实开始越来越像彼此了。
And I daresay in your mind's eye, imagine zooming further and further
我敢说，在你的脑海中，想象一下不断地放大
and further out.
和放大。
Like, that red and yellow line are pretty much-- once n is large enough--
就像，那条红线和黄线，一旦 n 足够大，它们基本上
going to be functionally the same.
在功能上将是相同的。
Like, they're practically the same algorithm.
就像，它们实际上是同一个算法。
But this one is still doing amazingly because it's
但这个仍然做得惊人，因为它
a fundamentally different shape.
是一个完全不同的形状。
So this is to say when a computer scientist talks about, thinks
所以，当计算机科学家谈论、思考
about the efficiency of algorithms, we just throw away the constant terms
算法的效率时，我们只是丢弃常数项
that when n gets really large just don't seem to matter as much.
当 n 变得非常大时，这些常数项似乎并不那么重要。
They don't add up as much or fundamentally
它们加起来并不多，也不从根本上
change the picture in a case like this.
改变这种情况下的局面。
So what I'm describing here with this capital letter O has a technical term.
所以，这里我用大写字母 O 描述的东西有一个专业术语。
This is called big O notation.
它被称为大 O 符号。
And this is omnipresent in computer science
这在计算机科学中无处不在
and often rears its head even in programming,
而且它经常出现在编程中，
specifically when talking about the design of some algorithm.
特别是在谈论某些算法的设计时。
And this is a little cheat sheet here on the screen now.
现在屏幕上有个小小的速查表。
Very often, algorithms that you write or you
很多时候，你编写的或使用的算法
use will be describable as being on the order of one of these running times.
可以描述为这些运行时间中的某一种。
So n is just representative of the number of things-- number of people,
所以 n 代表事物数量——人数，
number of pages--
页数——
whatever it is you're actually doing in code.
无论你在代码中实际做什么。
So the mathematical formulas inside of the parentheses
所以括号内的数学公式
describe as a function of the size of that input
描述的是作为输入大小函数的
how fast or slow the algorithm's going to be.
算法运行速度的快慢。
So this algorithm in the middle here, big O of n, so to speak,
所以这里中间这个算法，可以说是大 O 的 n，
means that it takes linear time, in other words.
也就是说，它需要线性时间。
So my first algorithm--
所以我的第一个算法——
1, 2, 3, 4--
1、2、3、4——
or my first algorithm in week zero--
或者我第一周的算法——
1, 2, 3, 4.
1、2、3、4。
That was a linear search.
那是一个线性搜索。
The number of steps it takes is on the order of n because if there's n pages,
它所需要的步骤数量是 n 阶的，因为如果有 n 页，
in the worst case, like, John Harvard's all the way at the end of the phone
在最坏情况下，比如，约翰·哈佛在电话簿的最后面，
book, so it takes me n steps.
所以需要 n 步。
In this case, it's always going to take me n steps to count you all
在这种情况下，总是要花 n 步才能数完你们所有人
because if I want to point at each and every one of you,
因为如果我想指着你们每个人，
that is always going to take me n steps.
这总是需要我 n 步。
So big O represents an upper bound on the number of steps
所以大 O 代表着你可能需要计算的步骤数量的上限
that you might be counting.
你可能会计算的步骤数量。
And so we often use it to consider the worst case and the worst
所以我们经常用它来考虑最坏情况，最坏
case, John Harvard, or whoever might be all the way at the end of the phone
情况，约翰·哈佛，或者任何可能在电话簿最后面的人。
book.
簿。
So that linear search is on the order of n.
所以那个线性搜索是 n 阶的。
But what about n squared?
但是 n 平方呢？
This means n people doing n things.
这意味着 n 个人做 n 件事情。
So for instance, and we won't do this today,
举个例子，我们今天不做这个，
but if we were to ask you again to stand up and shake
但是如果我们再让你们站起来，互相握手，
everyone's hand in the room--
房间里每个人的手——
not good for health nowadays-- but shake everyone's hand in the room,
现在对健康不好——但是要和房间里的每个人握手，
how many handshakes would there be?
会有多少次握手？
Well, if there's n of you and you've got to shake everyone else's hand,
好吧，如果有 n 个人，而且你必须和其他人握手，
that's technically n times n minus 1.
理论上就是 n 乘以 n 减 1。
Let's throw away the minus 1.
我们把减 1 扔掉。
That's n times n or n squared handshakes.
那就是 n 乘以 n 或者 n 平方次握手。
That's a lot of handshakes.
那可真是很多次握手。
And so the running time of shaking everyone's hand
所以，和房间里每个人握手
in the room to introduce yourself would be on the order of n squared.
自我介绍的运行时间将会是 n 平方阶的。
At the other end of the spectrum, the faster end, big O of 1
在光谱的另一端，也就是更快的一端，大 O 的 1
doesn't mean that the algorithm takes literally one step.
并不意味着算法只执行一步。
It could take two steps or three or even 1,000 steps.
它可能需要两步、三步，甚至 1000 步。
But what it means is it's a constant number of steps.
但重要的是，它始终是固定数量的步骤。
So it doesn't matter how many people are in the room,
所以房间里有多少人并不重要，
this describes something taking just one step total
这描述的是一个总共只进行一步的操作
or a constant number of steps total.
或者总共固定数量的步骤。
So for instance, earlier when everyone stood up at the same time,
例如，之前大家同时站起来时，
that was constant time because if we had twice as many people
那就是常数时间，因为如果我们的人数翻倍
come into the room, it's not going to take us twice as long to stand up
进入房间，我们站起来的时间并不会翻倍
if everyone stands up at the same time.
如果大家同时站起来。
That would be a constant time algorithm.
那将是一个常数时间算法。
So this is linear.
所以这是线性的。
This is constant.
这是常数。
If you want to get fancy, this is quadratic.
如果你想变得更复杂，这是二次的。
This is logarithmic.
这是对数的。
And this is n log n.
这是 n log n。
Or there's other fancier terms we can give it as well, but for now,
或者我们也可以用其他更专业的术语来描述它，但现在，
just a common list of running times that we might apply to certain algorithms.
只列出一些我们可能用于特定算法的常见运行时间。
So linear search, I claim, is in big O of n
所以，我认为线性搜索在 O(n) 范围内
because it's going to take in the worst case n steps.
因为它在最坏情况下会进行 n 步。
What about binary search?
那么二分搜索呢？
How many steps does binary search take on the order of
根据图表，二分搜索大约需要多少步
according to this chart?
？
Yeah?
是吗？
AUDIENCE: Log n.
观众：log n。
DAVID MALAN: Log n.
大卫·马兰：log n。
Yeah, because no matter what with binary search, you're dividing in half,
是的，因为无论二分搜索如何，你都在进行二分，
half, half.
二分，二分。
But in the worst case, it might be in the last door you check.
但在最坏情况下，它可能在最后一个检查的门里。
But you only took log n steps to get there.
但你只用了 log n 步才到达那里。
But it still might be the last one you check.
但它仍然可能是你检查的最后一个。
So binary search indeed would be on the order of log n.
因此，二分搜索的确是 log n 级的。
But sometimes, you do get lucky.
但有时，你确实会走运。
And we saw with our volunteers that sometimes you can get lucky
我们从志愿者身上看到，有时你确实会走运
and just find things quicker.
并且能更快地找到东西。
So we don't always want to talk about things in terms of an upper bound,
因此，我们并不总是想用上限来谈论事情，
like how many steps in the worst case might this algorithm take.
比如，在最坏情况下，该算法可能需要多少步。
Sometimes it's useful to know in the best case
有时，了解在最佳情况下
how few steps might an algorithm take.
一个算法可能需要多少步是很有用的。
So for that, we have this capital Greek omega, which
为此，我们有这个大写的希腊字母 Ω，它
is another symbol in computer science.
是计算机科学中的另一个符号。
And whereas big O represents upper bound, omega represents lower bound.
而大 O 代表上限，Ω 代表下限。
And it's the exact same idea.
它指的是完全相同的概念。
It's just a different symbol to represent
只是用不同的符号来表示
a different idea, the opposite, in this case.
不同的概念，在本例中是相反的。
So here's a similar cheat sheet here.
所以这里也有一个类似的速查表。
But when you use the omega symbol, that just
但当你使用 Ω 符号时，它只是
means that this algorithm might take as few as this many steps,
表示该算法可能只需要这些步骤，
for instance, in the very best case.
例如，在最佳情况下。
So by that logic, if I ask about linear search,
所以，根据这个逻辑，如果我询问线性搜索，
our first demonstration with the lockers, let's consider the best case.
我们对储物柜的第一个演示，让我们考虑最佳情况。
How many steps might it take to search n lockers
搜索n个储物柜需要多少步骤
using linear search in the best case?
在最佳情况下，使用线性搜索？
You get lucky.
你很幸运。
So I heard it.
所以我听到了。
Yeah, just one step.
是的，只有一步。
So we could say that linear search is an omega of 1, so to speak.
所以可以说，线性搜索是1的欧米伽，可以这么说。
What about binary search?
二分查找呢？
If you've got n lockers, in the best case, though,
如果你有n个储物柜，在最好的情况下，
how few steps might it take us?
我们需要多少步骤？
Again, one, because we might just get lucky.
同样，一个，因为我们可能只是运气好。
And boom, it happens to be right there in the middle.
然后，它正好在中间。
So you could say that both linear search and binary search are an omega of 1.
所以可以说，线性搜索和二分查找都是1的欧米伽。
Now, by contrast, my attendance algorithm, the first one I proposed--
相比之下，我的考勤算法，我提出的第一个算法——
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, I claimed a moment ago that that's in big O of n
1，2，3，4，5，6，7，我之前说过，它属于大O(n)
because if there's n people in the room, I've got to point at everyone.
因为如果房间里有n个人，我必须指点每个人。
But equivalently, if there's n people in the room
但同样，如果房间里有n个人
and I have to point at everyone, what's the fewest number of steps
我必须指点每个人，最少需要多少步骤
it could take me to take attendance using this linear approach?
我才能用这种线性方法点名？
So still n, right, unless I guess, which is not an algorithm.
所以仍然是n，对吧，除非我猜，但这不算是算法。
Like, unless I guess, I'm not going to get the right answer,
比如，除非我猜，我不会得到正确答案，
so I kind of have to point at everyone.
所以我必须指点每个人。
So in both the best case and the worst case,
所以在最好的情况下和最坏的情况下，
some algorithms still take n steps.
一些算法仍然需要n步。
And for this, we have what we'll call theta notation, whereby
为此，我们有我们称之为θ记法的概念，即
if big O and omega happen to be the same, which is not always the case
如果大O和小ω恰好相同，虽然并非总是如此
but can be, then you can say that algorithm is in theta of such and such.
但可能相同，那么你可以说这个算法属于θ(某个东西)。
So my attendance-taking algorithm, the very first, 1, 2, 3, 4,
所以我的考勤算法，第一个，1，2，3，4，
all the way on up to n would be in theta of n
一直到n，将属于θ(n)
because in both the best case and the worst case,
因为在最好的情况下和最坏的情况下，
it takes the same number of steps as per my big O and omega analysis.
它需要与我的大O和小ω分析相同的步数。
Now, there is a more formal mathematical definition for both of these.
现在，这两个都有更正式的数学定义。
And if you take higher level computer science,
如果你学习更高阶的计算机科学，
you'll go more into the weeds of these ideas.
你会更深入地研究这些概念。
But for now, big O, upper bound.
但目前，大O，上限。
Omega, lower bound.
欧米伽，下限。
Questions on this symbology?
关于这种符号，有什么问题吗？
It'll be a tool in our tool kit.
它将成为我们工具箱中的工具。
No?
没有？
OK, so with that said, let's see how we might translate this to actual code
好的，既然这样，让我们看看如何将它翻译成实际代码
in something that makes sense now using C and not so much
使用C语言，现在用一些有意义的东西，而不仅仅是
new syntax but applications of similar ideas from last time.
新语法，而是上一次类似概念的应用。
So for instance, let me actually go over to search dot C. And in search dot C,
例如，让我实际转到search.c。在search.c中，
I'm going to go ahead and implement the idea of linear search,
我将继续实现线性搜索的理念，
very simply, using integers initially.
非常简单，最初使用整数。
So to do this, let me go ahead and give myself the familiar CS50 dot h
所以要做到这一点，让我继续给自己熟悉的CS50.h
so that I can ask the human what number to search for.
这样我就可以问人类要搜索哪个数字。
Then let me go ahead and include standard io.h
然后让我继续包含stdio.h
so that I can use printf and the like.
这样我就可以使用 printf 等等。
Then I'm going to go ahead and do int main void without any command line
然后，我将继续执行 int main void，不带任何命令行
arguments because I'm not going to need any for this particular demonstration.
参数，因为在这个特定的演示中我不会用到任何参数。
And someone asked about this a while back.
有人之前问过这个问题。
If I want to declare an array of values but I
如果我想声明一个值的数组，但是我
know in advance what the values are, there is a special syntax I can use,
事先知道这些值是什么，我可以使用一种特殊的语法，
which is this.
就是这个。
If I want a whole bunch of numbers but I want those numbers to be stored
如果我想得到一大堆数字，但是我想把这些数字存储
in an array, I can store them in--
在一个数组中，我可以将它们存储在——
using these curly braces.
使用这些花括号。
And I'm going to use the same numbers as the monopoly denominations
我将使用与我们一直在玩的大富翁面额相同的数字
that we've been playing with.
我们一直在玩。
And I'm just going to put them in sort of random order.
我只是要随机地把它们放进去。
But I'm going to deliberately put the 50 all the way at the end
但我故意把 50 放到最后
just so that I know that it's going to try all possible steps, so big O of n,
这样我就知道它会尝试所有可能的步骤，所以是 n 的大 O，
ultimately.
最终。
Now let's go ahead and ask the user for a value n.
现在让我们继续让用户输入一个值 n。
And we'll use get int.
我们将使用 get int。
And just ask the user for a number to search for, be it 50 or something else.
然后，就让用户输入一个要查找的数字，可以是 50 或者其他数字。
And then here's how I might implement in code now linear search,
然后，这就是我现在在代码中实现线性搜索的方法，
translating effectively the pseudocode from last time.
有效地将上一次的伪代码翻译过来。
For int i equals 0.
对于 int i 等于 0。
i is less than 7. i plus plus.
i 小于 7。i 加加。
And then inside of this loop, I can ask a question.
然后在这个循环里面，我可以问一个问题。
If the ith number in the numbers array--
如果 numbers 数组中的第 i 个数字——
so numbers bracket i-- equals, equals the number n
也就是 numbers 中的第 i 个数字—— 等于，等于数字 n
that I care about, well, this is where I could just declare return true
我关心的那个数字，那么，我可以在这个地方直接声明 return true
or return false.
或者 return false。
Here, I'm going to go ahead and just use a printf statement.
这里，我将继续使用一个 printf 语句。
And I'm going to say found, backslash n, just to know visually
我将说 found，反斜杠 n，只是为了视觉上
that I found the number.
知道我找到了这个数字。
And else I might do something like this.
否则我可能会做这样的事。
Else if that's not the case, I'll go ahead
否则，如果情况不是这样，我会继续
and print out not found backslash n.
并打印出 not found 反斜杠 n。
All right, so let me zoom out for just a moment.
好吧，让我稍微放大一点。
Here's all of my code.
这是我所有的代码。
Any concerns with this implementation of what I claim is now linear search?
对这个我声称是线性搜索的实现有任何疑问吗？
Any concerns with what I claim is linear search?
Yeah?
有吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
DAVID MALAN: Exactly.
大卫·马兰：没错。
If I search the first number and it's not found, it's going to say not found.
如果我搜索第一个数字，并且没有找到，它会说没找到。
But it's going to keep saying not found, not found, not found,
但它会一直说没找到，没找到，没找到，
which might be fine.
这可能是可以的。
But it's a little stupid.
但有点傻。
I probably want to know if it's found or not.
我可能想知道它是否找到了。
So I've made that same mistake that I called out earlier.
所以我犯了之前提到的同样的错误。
Like, the else is not the alternative to not finding
比如，else 不是在第一个位置没有找到数字的替代方案。
the number in that first location.
它不是在第一个位置没有找到数字的替代方案。
It's the final decision to make when I haven't actually found the value.
这是在我没有真正找到值的时候要做的最终决定。
So I think what I want to do is get rid of this else clause.
所以我想做的是去掉这个else子句。
And then at the outside of this loop, I think
然后在这个循环的外面，我认为
I want to conclude printf not found.
我想总结一下，printf 没有找到。
But here too there's a new bug that's arisen.
但在这里也出现了一个新的错误。
There's a new bug, even though I fixed the logical error you just described.
虽然我已经修复了您刚才描述的逻辑错误，但仍然存在一个新的错误。
What symptom are we still going to see?
我们还会看到什么症状？
Yeah, now it's going to always print not found,
是的，现在它总是会打印找不到，
even when I have found it because even once I've found it
即使我找到了它，因为即使我找到了它
and I finished going through the array, it's still going
并且我完成了遍历数组，它仍然在
to assume that I got to the bottom.
假设我到达了底部。
And therefore, it's not found.
因此，它没有找到。
So I need to somehow exit out of main prematurely, if you will.
因此，如果可以的话，我需要以某种方式提前退出 main 函数。
And recall that last week, we also introduced the idea
还记得上周我们也介绍了这个概念
that main all this time does actually return a value, an integer.
就是 main 函数实际上一直都在返回一个值，一个整数。
By default, it's secretly been zero.
默认情况下，它一直是秘密的零。
Anytime a program exits, it just returns zero, an exit status of zero.
只要程序退出，它就会返回零，退出状态为零。
But we do now have control over that.
但我们现在可以控制它。
And so a convention in C would be that when
因此，在 C 语言中，约定是，当
you want your main function to end prematurely if so,
您希望您的 main 函数提前结束，如果这样的话，
you can literally just return a value.
您可以直接返回一个值。
And even though this feels a little backwards, this is just the way it is.
虽然这感觉有点倒退，但这就是事实。
You return zero to indicate success.
您返回零表示成功。
And you return any other integer to indicate failure.
您返回任何其他整数表示失败。
So by convention, people go to 1 and then 2 and then 3.
因此，按照惯例，人们会使用 1，然后是 2，然后是 3。
They don't think too hard about what numbers to use.
他们不会过多地考虑使用哪些数字。
But in this case, I'm going to go ahead and return 1
但在这种情况下，我将继续返回 1
if I do get to the bottom of this file.
如果我确实到达了这个文件的底部。
So now if I open back up my terminal window, I run make search.
所以现在，如果我重新打开我的终端窗口，运行 make search。
No syntax errors-- dot slash search.
没有语法错误-- 点斜杠 search。
I'm going to be prompted for a number.
我将被提示输入一个数字。
Let's go ahead and search for the number 50.
让我们继续搜索数字 50。
And I should see found.
我应该看到找到了。
Meanwhile, if I run it again-- dot slash search--
同时，如果我再次运行它-- 点斜杠 search--
I search for the number 13, that should be not found.
我搜索数字 13，它应该找不到。
So I claim that this is now a correct implementation of linear search
所以，我认为这现在是线性搜索的正确实现
that's gone from left to right, looking for a number that may or may not
它从左到右进行，寻找一个可能存在也可能不存在的数字
be there.
在那里。
Any questions on this version of the code here?
关于这段代码有什么问题吗？
Yeah?
对？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众： [听不见]
DAVID MALAN: Return zero indicates success
大卫·马兰：返回零表示成功
when doing it from main in particular.
特别是从 main 函数执行时。
And that's backwards only in the sense that generally 0 is false.
这只是因为一般情况下 0 代表假。
And 1 is true.
而 1 代表真。
But the logic here is that if the program works correctly, that's zero.
但这里的逻辑是，如果程序正常工作，那就是零。
But there's an infinite number of things that can go wrong.
但可能出现无限多种错误。
And that's why we need 1 and 2 and 3 and 4 and all the way up.
这就是为什么我们需要 1、2、3、4 以及一直到最大值。
Other questions?
还有其他问题吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众： [听不见]
DAVID MALAN: Yes.
大卫·马兰：是的。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID MALAN: Correct.
大卫·马兰：正确。
When you return zero or return any value from main wherever it is in your code,
当你从 main 函数中返回 0 或任何值，无论它在代码中的位置，
the program will effectively terminate right then and there.
程序将立即终止。
No additional code will get executed at the bottom of the function.
函数底部将不会执行任何额外的代码。
You'll effectively exit out.
你将有效地退出。
Just like in a normal function that isn't main, when you return a value,
就像在不是 main 函数的普通函数中一样，当你返回一个值时，
it immediately exits that function and hands back the value.
它会立即退出该函数并返回该值。
Yeah?
是的？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID MALAN: So return 1 is just me being
大卫·马兰：所以返回 1 只是我
pedantic at this point because I'm frankly not going to really care what
在这个时候过于严格，因为坦白地说，我并不关心
the exit status is of this program.
这个程序的退出状态是什么。
But once I've introduced the idea of manually returning 0 on this line 14
但是，一旦我在第 14 行手动返回 0 的概念，
to indicate success, it stands to reason that I should also
来指示成功，那么有道理的是，我也应该
return a different value when I want to indicate failure.
在我想指示失败时返回一个不同的值。
And so even though this does not functionally
即使这在功能上
change the program-- it will still work-- it will still
不会改变程序——它仍然会工作——它仍然会
print the same things correctly-- it's a lower level detail
正确地打印相同的东西——这是一个更底层的细节
that programmers, teaching assistants, testing software,
程序员、助教、测试软件，
might appreciate, knowing what actually happened
可能会觉得有用，因为他们知道程序底层实际发生了什么
in the program underneath the hood.
。
All right, so what about strings?
好的，那么字符串呢？
So it turns out with strings, we're going
事实证明，对于字符串，我们将
to have to think a little harder about how best to do this.
不得不更认真地考虑如何才能做到这一点。
So let me actually go ahead and do this.
所以，让我实际操作一下。
Let me go ahead and get rid of much of this code but transition
让我把大部分代码去掉，但要转到
to a different type of array, this time an array of strings.
一种不同的数组类型，这次是字符串数组。
And I'm going to call the array strings itself plural, just to make clear
我将把这个数组称为字符串本身的复数，只是为了清楚地表明
what's in it instead of numbers.
它里面是什么，而不是数字。
I'm going to use the square bracket notation, which
我将使用方括号表示法，它
just means I don't know at the moment how many elements it's going to have.
只是意味着我现在不知道它将有多少个元素。
But the compiler can figure it out for me.
但是编译器可以帮我弄明白。
And in the spirit of Monopoly, let's go ahead in our curly braces,
秉承大富翁的精神，让我们在花括号中，
do something like this.
做一些这样的事情。
Battleship is going to be one of the strings.
战舰将是其中一个字符串。
Boot is going to be another.
靴子将是另一个。
Cannon is going to be a third.
大炮将是第三个。
Iron is going to be the fourth.
铁将是第四个。
Thimble-- and if you've ever played Monopoly,
顶针——如果你玩过大富翁，
you know where these are coming from-- and top hat, for instance.
你就知道这些东西是从哪里来的——例如，还有帽子。
So this gives me 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
所以，这给了我 1、2、3、4、5、6。
I could write the number 6 here.
我可以在这里写数字 6。
And the compiler would appreciate it.
编译器会感激的。
But it doesn't matter.
但这并不重要。
The compiler can figure it out on its own just based on the number of commas.
编译器可以根据逗号的数量自行判断。
And this also ensures that I don't write one number to the left
这也确保我不会在左边写一个数字，
and then miscount on the right.
然后在右边算错。
So omitting it is probably in everyone's benefit.
所以省略它可能对每个人都有利。
Now let's do this.
现在让我们这样做。
Let's ask the user for a string using get string instead of get int
让我们使用 get string 而不是 get int 来询问用户一个字符串。
for some string to search for.
用于搜索某些字符串。
Then let's go ahead and do the exact same thing.
然后让我们继续做完全相同的事情。
For i int i equals 0.
对于 i int i 等于 0。
i is less than 6, which is technically a magic number.
i 小于 6，在技术上是一个神奇数字。
But let's focus on the searching algorithm for now.
但让我们暂时关注搜索算法。
i plus plus.
i 加加。
And then inside of this loop, let's do this.
然后在这个循环内，让我们这样做。
If strings bracket i equals equals, s, then let's go ahead
如果字符串中括号内的 i 等于 s，那么让我们继续
and print out just as before, quote, unquote, found-- backslash n--
并像以前一样打印出来，引号，引号，已找到——反斜杠 n——
and proactively return zero this time.
并主动返回零。
And if we don't find it anywhere in the loop,
如果我们在循环中任何地方都没有找到它，
let's go ahead and return 1 at the very bottom,
让我们继续并在最底部返回 1，
before which we will print not found backslash n.
在此之前，我们将打印未找到反斜杠 n。
So it's the exact same logic at the moment,
所以现在逻辑完全相同，
even though I've changed my ints to strings.
即使我已经将我的整数更改为字符串。
Let me go ahead and open up my terminal window now.
现在让我打开我的终端窗口。
Do make search again and see, OK, so far, so good.
再次进行搜索并查看，好的，到目前为止，一切顺利。
Let me now go ahead and do dot slash search.
现在让我继续执行点斜杠搜索。
And let's go ahead and search for-- how about top hat.
让我们继续搜索——怎么样，顶帽子。
So we should see found.
所以我们应该看到已找到。
Huh.
嗯。
All right, not found.
好的，未找到。
All right, well, let's do dot slash search again.
好的，好吧，让我们再次执行点斜杠搜索。
How about thimble?
怎么样，顶针？
Maybe it's because it's just two words.
也许是因为它只是两个词。
No, thimble's not found, either.
不，顶针也没有找到。
Dot slash search-- let's search for the first one, battleship.
点斜杠搜索——让我们搜索第一个，战舰。
Enter-- still not found.
回车——仍然没有找到。
Let's search for something else like cat.
让我们搜索其他东西，比如猫。
Not found.
未找到。
What is going on because I'm pretty sure the logic is exactly the same?
到底发生了什么，因为我确信逻辑完全相同？
Well, it turns out in C, this line here, currently line 11,
好吧，事实证明在 C 中，这里这行，当前第 11 行，
is not how you compare strings.
这不是你比较字符串的方式。
If you want to compare strings in C, you don't do it like you did integers.
如果你想在 C 中比较字符串，你不能像比较整数那样做。
You actually need another technique altogether.
你实际上需要另一种完全不同的技术。
And for that, we're going to need to revisit one of our friends, which
为此，我们需要重新审视我们的一个朋友，即
is string.h, which is one of the header files for the string library
string.h，它是字符串库的头文件之一
that we introduced last week that has in addition to functions
我们在上周介绍过，它除了函数外
like strlen, which gives you the length of a string, it also gives us,
比如 strlen，它可以给出字符串的长度，它还给我们，
as per the documentation here, another function that we'll
根据这里的文档，另一个我们将
start to find useful here, succinctly named strcmp, for string compare.
在这里开始发现有用的，简洁地命名为 strcmp，用于字符串比较。
And string compare will actually tell us if two strings are the same or not.
字符串比较实际上会告诉我们两个字符串是否相同。
It will indeed compare them.
它确实会比较它们。
And if I use this now, let me go back to my code
如果我现在使用它，让我回到我的代码
here and see what I might do differently if I go back into my code here
这里看看如果我回到我的代码这里，我可能会做些什么不同的事情。
and change this value.
并且更改此值。
Instead of using strings bracket i equals, equals s, let's do str compare.
与其使用字符串方括号 i 等于，等于 s，不如使用 str compare。
And I read the documentation earlier.
我之前已经阅读过文档了。
So I know that it takes two arguments, the first and the second string
所以我知道它需要两个参数，第一个和第二个字符串
that you want to compare, so strings bracket i and then s,
你想要比较的，所以是字符串方括号 i 然后是 s，
which is the string that the human typed in.
也就是人类输入的字符串。
But somewhat weirdly, what I want to check for
但有点奇怪的是，我想检查的是
is that str compare returns zero.
str compare 返回 0。
So if str compare when given two strings is input, strings bracket i and s,
所以如果 str compare 在给出两个字符串时，输入的是字符串方括号 i 和 s，
returns an integer 0, that actually means the strings are the same.
返回一个整数 0，实际上意味着字符串是相同的。
So let's try this.
所以让我们试试这个。
Let me do make search again.
让我再次执行 make search。
Huh.
嗯。
What did I do wrong here?
我这里做错了什么？
A whole bunch of errors popped out.
一堆错误弹出来了。
What did I do wrong?
我做错了什么？
Yeah?
是吗？
Yeah, so I didn't include the very header file we're talking about.
是的，所以我没有包含我们正在讨论的头文件。
So again, it doesn't necessarily mean a logical error.
所以再次强调，这并不一定意味着逻辑错误。
It just means a stupid error on my part.
这只意味着我犯了一个愚蠢的错误。
I didn't actually include the header file.
我实际上并没有包含头文件。
So let me go back and actually do that.
所以让我回去做一下。
Up at the top in addition to cs50.h and standard io,
在顶部，除了 cs50.h 和标准输入之外，
let's also include string.h.
我们也包含 string.h。
Let me clear my terminal and do make search again.
让我清空终端并再次执行 make search。
Crossing my fingers.
祈祷吧。
That time it worked.
这次它成功了。
And now if I do dot slash search and search for top hat like before,
现在如果我执行 ./search 然后像之前一样搜索 top hat，
now, thankfully, it is, in fact, found.
现在，感谢上帝，它确实被找到了。
If I do it once more and search for battleship, now it's, in fact, found.
如果我再次执行并搜索 battleship，现在它确实被找到了。
If I do it once more and search for cat, which should not be in there,
如果我再次执行并搜索 cat，它不应该出现在那里，
that is not, in fact, found.
它确实没有被找到。
So now just intuitively, even if you've never done this before,
所以现在直观地，即使你以前从未做过这个，
why might it be valuable for this function called strcmp
为什么这个叫做 strcmp 的函数
to return zero if the strings are equal as opposed
如果字符串相等就返回 0，而不是
to a simple Boolean like true or false, which might have been your intuition?
一个简单的布尔值，比如真或假，这可能就是你的直觉？
When you compare two strings, what are the possible takeaways
当你比较两个字符串时，你可能会从比较两个字符串中得到哪些可能的结论？
you might have from comparing two strings?
你可能从比较两个字符串中得到哪些可能的结论？
It's not just that they're equal or not.
不仅仅是它们是否相等。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众： [听不清]
DAVID MALAN: OK, so maybe if the ASCII values are the same, that
大卫·马兰：好的，所以也许如果 ASCII 值相同，
might imply, indeed, literal equality.
可能会暗示，实际上，是字面上的相等。
But something else.
但还有其他东西。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] about how similar these things are [INAUDIBLE]..
观众： [听不清] 关于这些东西有多相似 [听不清]..
DAVID MALAN: Ah, nice.
大卫·马兰：啊，不错。
Like, you and I in English, certainly, are very much
就像你我一样，在英语中，当然，我们非常
in the habit of sorting information, whether it's
习惯于对信息进行排序，无论是
in a dictionary, in our contacts, in a phone book, in any such technology.
在字典里，在我们的联系人中，在电话簿里，在任何此类技术中。
And so it's often useful to be able to know, does this string equal another?
所以，通常能够知道这个字符串是否等于另一个字符串是很有用的。
Sure.
好的。
But does this string come before another alphabetically or maybe
但是这个字符串在字母顺序上是在另一个之前还是之后呢？
after another alphabetically?
或者在另一个之后呢？
So sometimes, you want functions to give you back three answers.
所以有时，你希望函数能够返回三个答案。
But equals, equals alone can only give you true or false, yes or no.
但是等于，仅仅等于只能给你真或假，是或否。
And that might not be useful enough when you're
这可能在你试图解决一些与字符串相关的难题时不够用。
trying to solve some problem involving strings.
当你试图解决一些与字符串相关的难题时。
So it turns out str compare actually compares the two strings for equality
事实证明，str compare 实际上比较了两个字符串的相等性
but also for what's called, playfully, ASCII-betical order.
但也比较了所谓的，开玩笑地说，ASCII-betical 顺序。
So not alphabetical order, per se, but ASCII-betical order
所以不是严格意义上的字母顺序，而是 ASCII-betical 顺序。
where it actually compares the integer values of the letters.
它实际上比较了字母的整数值。
So if you're comparing the letter A, It's
所以如果你要比较字母 A，它
going to compare 65 against some other letter's integer value-- hence
将比较 65 与其他字母的整数值，因此
ASCII-betical value.
ASCII-betical 值。
So we're not doing any form of sorting here.
所以我们这里没有进行任何形式的排序。
So it's sort of immaterial.
所以它有点无关紧要。
But as per the documentation, I do know that str compare
但是根据文档，我确实知道 str compare
returns zero if two strings are equal.
如果两个字符串相等，则返回零。
And a little teaser for next week, it turns out when I was only using equals,
下周的小剧透，事实证明，当我只使用等于时，
equals to compare strings bracket i and s,
等于来比较字符串括号 i 和 s，
I was not comparing the strings in the way that you might have thought.
我没有按照你可能认为的方式比较字符串。
And if you have programmed in Java or Python before, equals, equals
如果你以前用 Java 或 Python 编程过，等于，等于
is actually doing something different in those languages
实际上在这些语言中做着不同的事情
than it is actually doing in C. But more on that next week.
而不是它在 C 中实际做的事情。但更多内容下周再说。
For now, just take on faith that str compare is indeed
现在，就相信 str compare 确实是
how you compare two strings.
比较两个字符串的方式。
So let's actually put this into play with some actual additional code.
所以让我们实际用一些实际的额外代码来演示一下。
Let me propose that we implement a very simplistic phone book, for instance.
例如，我建议我们实现一个非常简单的电话簿。
Let me go ahead and implement here--
让我在这里实现一下
how about in a new file.
在一个新文件中。
Instead of search dot C, let's actually do phone book dot c.
而不是 search dot C，让我们实际做 phone book dot c。
And in this phone book, I'm going to go ahead and include the same header file,
在这个电话簿中，我将继续包含相同的头文件，
so cs50.h, so I can get input--
所以是 cs50.h，这样我就可以获得输入
standard io.h, so I can use printf--
standard io.h，这样我就可以使用 printf
string.h so that I can use str compare.
string.h，这样我就可以使用 str compare。
Let me give myself a main function again without command line arguments for now.
让我再次给自己一个 main 函数，现在还没有命令行参数。
And let me go ahead now and store a proper phone book, which
让我现在继续存储一个完整的电话簿，它
has some names and some actual numbers.
有一些名字和一些实际的号码。
So let's store the names first.
所以让我们先存储姓名。
So string-- names is going to be the name of my array.
所以字符串，names 将是我的数组的名称。
And let's go ahead and store Carter's name,
让我们继续存储 Carter 的姓名，
how about my name, and maybe John Harvard for phone book throwback.
我的名字怎么样，还有也许是 John Harvard，作为电话簿的怀旧之情。
Then let's go ahead and give me another array called numbers wherein I'll put
然后让我们继续给我另一个叫做 numbers 的数组，我将在其中放入
our phone number, so 617-495-1000 for Carter--
我们的电话号码，所以 Carter 是 617-495-1000
617-495-1000 for me-- technically, directory assistance here.
我的是 617-495-1000，技术上来说，这里是电话信息台。
And then for John, we'll give him an actual one.
然后对于 John，我们会给他一个真实的号码。
So it's actually going to be 949-468-2750.
所以实际上应该是 949-468-2750。
You're welcome to text or call John when you want.
欢迎你在需要的时候给 John 发短信或打电话。
Whoops.
哎呀。
And just for good measure, let's go ahead and put our country codes
为了保险起见，让我们加上国家代码
in here plus 1, even though at the end of the day, these are strings.
在里面加上 1，即使最终这些都是字符串。
So indeed notice I'm not using an integer for these values.
所以确实注意我并没有用整数来表示这些值。
I kind of sort of should.
我应该这样做。
But here's where data types in C and programming more
但这就是 C 语言和编程中数据类型可能会误导你的地方。
generally might sometimes mislead you.
一般情况下可能会让你误解。
Even though we call it, obviously, a phone number.
即使我们很明显地称之为电话号码。
It's probably best to represent it generally as strings, in fact,
事实上，最好用字符串来表示它，
so that you can have the pluses-- you can have the dashes so that it doesn't
这样你就可以有加号，也可以有减号，这样它就不会
get too big and overflow an integer.
变得太大而溢出整数。
Maybe it's an international number for which there's even more digits.
也许它是一个国际号码，有更多位数。
You don't want to risk overflowing a value.
你不想冒险让值溢出。
And in general, the rule of thumb in programming
一般来说，编程中的经验法则是
is even if in English we call something a number,
即使我们在英语中称某事物为数字，
if you wouldn't do math on it ever, you should probably be storing it
如果你永远不会对它进行数学运算，你应该把它存储为
as a string, not as an integer.
字符串而不是整数。
And it makes no logical sense to do math on phone numbers, per se.
严格来说，对电话号码进行数学运算没有任何逻辑意义。
So those are best instinctively left as strings.
所以最好直觉地将它们保留为字符串。
And in this case, even more simply, this ensures
在这种情况下，更简单地说，这确保了
that we have pluses and dashes stored inside of the string.
我们有加号和减号存储在字符串中。
All right, so now that I have these two arrays in parallel, if you will.
好的，所以现在我有这两个并行的数组，如果你愿意的话。
Like, I'm assuming that Carter's name is first.
比如，我假设 Carter 的名字排在第一位。
So his number is first.
所以他的号码排在第一位。
David's name is second.
David 的名字排在第二位。
So his number is second.
所以他的号码排在第二位。
John's is third and thus third.
John 的排在第三位，所以他的号码也排在第三位。
So let's actually search this.
所以让我们实际搜索一下。
Let's ask the user for--
让我们询问用户
how about a name using get string.
使用 get string 输入一个名字。
And this will be a name to search for in the phone book
这将是一个要在电话簿中搜索的名字
just like we did in week zero.
就像我们在第 0 周做的那样。
Let's do for int i equals 0, i less than 3.
让我们执行 for int i 等于 0，i 小于 3。
Again, the 3 is bad practice.
再说一次，3 是一个不好的做法。
I should probably store that in a constant.
我应该把它存储在一个常量中。
But let's keep the focus for today on the algorithm alone--
但是让我们今天的重点放在算法本身
i plus, plus.
i 加加。
Then in here, let's do if--
然后在这里，让我们做 if
how about names bracket i equals, equals name typed in.
名字中括号 i 等于，等于用户输入的名字。
But wait a minute.
等等。
I'm screwing this up again.
我又搞砸了。
What should I be using here?
我应该在这里使用什么？
str compare again-- so let's do str compare, names bracket i comma,
再次使用 str compare，所以让我们执行 str compare，名字中括号 i 逗号
name, which came from the user.
名字，来自用户。
And if that return value is zero, then let's go ahead
如果返回值为零，那么让我们继续
and print out, just like before, found backslash n.
打印出来，就像之前一样，找到反斜杠 n。
But you know what?
但是你知道吗？
We can do something more interesting.
我们可以做一些更有趣的事情。
Let's actually print out the number.
让我们实际打印出这个号码。
So I didn't just find something.
所以我不仅找到了东西。
I found the name.
我找到了姓名。
So let's actually plug in that person's corresponding number.
所以让我们实际将该人的相应号码填入。
So now it's a more useful phonebook or contacts app
所以现在它是一个更有用的电话簿或通讯录应用程序
where I'm going to show the human not just found
在那里我将向人们展示的不只是找到
but found this specific number.
而是找到了这个特定的号码。
Then I'm going to go ahead as before and return 0 to indicate success.
然后我会像以前一样继续前进，返回 0 来表示成功。
And if we get all the way down here, I'm going to go ahead and say not found
如果我们一直走到这里，我会继续说没找到
and not print out any number because I obviously haven't found one,
并且不打印任何号码，因为我显然没有找到，
and return one by convention to indicate failure.
并且按照惯例返回 1 来表示失败。
So let me open my terminal window.
所以让我打开我的终端窗口。
Let me do make phone book-- enter.
让我做 make phone book-- 然后输入。
So far, so good-- dot slash phone book.
到目前为止，一切顺利-- dot slash phone book。
Let's search for Carter--
让我们搜索 Carter--
enter-- found his number.
输入-- 找到了他的号码。
Let's do it again.
让我们再做一次。
Dot slash phone book--
David-- found it.
David-- 找到了。
Let's do it one more time for John--
让我们再为 John 做一次--
found it.
找到了。
And just for good measure, let's do one other here like Eli--
为了保险起见，让我们再做另一个，比如 Eli--
enter-- not found in this case.
输入-- 在这种情况下没有找到。
All right, so it seems to be working based on this example here.
好吧，从这里这个例子来看，似乎工作正常。
But now we've actually implemented the idea of, like, a proper phone book.
但是现在我们实际上已经实现了，比如，一个真正的电话簿的概念。
But does any aspect of the design of this code,
但是，这段代码的任何设计方面，
even if you've never programmed before CS50,
即使你之前从未在 CS50 中进行过编程，
does anything rub you wrong about how we're storing our data--
我们的数据存储方式是否让你觉得有什么不对劲--
the phone book itself-- these names and numbers?
电话簿本身-- 这些姓名和号码？
Does anything rub you the wrong way?
有什么让你觉得不对劲吗？
Yeah, in back.
是的，在后面。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, really good observation.
大卫·马兰：是的，非常好的观察。
I'm separating the names and the numbers,
我将姓名和号码分开，
which indeed, it looks a little bit weird.
的确，这看起来有点奇怪。
And there's actually this technical term in the world of programming,
在编程世界里，实际上有一个技术术语，
which is code smell, where, like--
那就是代码味道，就像--
[SNIFFING]---- something smells a little off about this code in the sense that,
[闻闻]---- 这段代码有点奇怪，从某种意义上来说，
like, this probably doesn't end well, right?
比如，这可能不会以好的方式结束，对吧？
If I add a fourth name, a fourth number, a fifth name, a fiftieth name
如果我添加第四个姓名，第四个号码，第五个姓名，第五十个姓名
and number, like, at some point, they're probably
和号码，比如，在某个时刻，它们可能
going to get out of sync, right?
会不同步，对吧？
So, like, there's something awry about this design
所以，就像，这个设计有点问题
that I shouldn't decouple the names from the numbers.
我不应该将姓名和号码分开。
So something kind of smells about this code, so to speak.
所以，可以说，这段代码有点味道。
And any time you perceive that in your code,
而且无论何时你感觉到你的代码中出现这种情况，
it's probably an opportunity to go about improving it somehow.
这可能是一个改进代码的机会。
But to do that, we actually need another tool in the toolkit.
但要做到这一点，我们实际上需要工具箱中的另一个工具。
And that is, again, this term that I've used a couple of times--
而且，这又是我多次使用过的术语--
再说一次，就是我之前提过几次的这个词——
data structures.
数据结构。
Like, arrays have been the first of our data structures.
比如，数组是我们数据结构中的第一个。
And they're so simplistic.
它们非常简单。
It just means storing things back to back to back contiguously in memory.
它只是意味着在内存中连续地将事物存储在一起。
But it turns out C--
但事实证明 C——
and a little bit of new syntax-- but it's not a lot of new syntax today--
以及一些新的语法，虽然今天我们不会学太多新的语法——
a little bit of new syntax today will allow
今天学习一些新的语法将允许我们
us to create our own data structures, our own types of variables,
创建我们自己的数据结构，我们自己的变量类型，
largely using syntax we've seen thus far.
主要使用我们迄今为止所见过的语法。
So to do this, let me propose that in order
因此，为了做到这一点，我建议为了
to represent a person in a phone book-- well, let's
在电话簿中表示一个人，我们不妨
not just implement them as a list of names and a list of numbers.
不要仅仅将它们实现为一个姓名列表和一个号码列表。
Wouldn't it be nice if C had a data type actually called person?
如果 C 语言实际上有一个叫做“person”的数据类型，那岂不是很棒？
Because if it did, then I could go about creating an array called--
因为如果存在，那么我就可以创建一个名为——
using the pluralized form-- people--
使用复数形式——people——
containing my people in my phone book.
包含我电话簿里的每个人。
And maybe a person has both a name and a number.
也许一个人同时拥有姓名和号码。
And therefore, we can kind of keep everything together.
因此，我们能够将所有信息整合在一起。
So how can I do this?
那么，我该怎么做呢？
Well, what is a person?
好吧，什么是人呢？
Well, a person, really, in this story is a person has a name.
嗯，在故事中，一个人的确是拥有名字的。
And a person has a number.
而且一个拥有电话号码。
So can we create a new data type that maybe has both of these together?
所以，我们可以创建一个新的数据类型，它可以将这两者结合在一起吗？
Well, we actually can by using one piece of new syntax
事实上，我们可以通过使用一个新的语法来做到这一点
today, which is just this here.
就是这里。
Using what's called a struct, we can create our own data structure
使用名为“struct”的结构体，我们可以创建我们自己的数据结构
that actually has some structure in it.
它实际上具有某种结构。
It's not just one thing like a string or an int.
它不仅仅像字符串或整数那样只是一个东西。
Maybe it's two strings.
也许是两个字符串。
Maybe it's two ints.
也许是两个整数。
Maybe it's one of each.
也许是一个字符串和一个整数。
So a structure can be a variable that contains any number of other variables,
因此，结构体可以是一个包含任意数量其他变量的变量，
so to speak.
这么说吧。
And typedef is a cryptic keyword that just
而 typedef 是一个神秘的关键字，它只是
means define the following type-- invent the following data type for me.
意味着定义以下类型——为我创建以下数据类型。
And the syntax is a little weird.
语法有点奇怪。
But you say typedef struct curly brace.
但你应该说 typedef struct 大括号。
Inside of the curly braces, you put all of the types
在大括号内，你放置所有你想与这个新的数据类型关联的变量类型。
of variables you want to associate with this new data type.
在大括号之后，你创建你想赋予它的名称。
And then after the curly brace, you invent the name
这将创建一个名为“person”的新数据类型，
that you want to give it.
即使几十年
And this will create a new data type in C called person,
之前在 C 语言被创建出来的时候，
even though no one thought of this decades
人们都没有想过要创建像“person”这样的数据类型，
ago when C was created alongside of the ints and the floats and so forth.
当时 C 语言只是创建了整数和浮点数等等。
So how can I actually use this?
那么，我该如何使用它呢？
Well, it turns out that once you have this building
结果证明，一旦你有了这个创建你自己的数据结构的
block of creating your very own data structures, I can go back into my code
模块，我就可以回到我的代码中。
and improve it as follows in direct response to your concern
并根据您的关注进行改进，如下所示
about it seeming not ideal that we're decoupling the names and the numbers.
关于我们分离姓名和号码似乎并不理想。
Now, it's going to look a little more complicated at first.
现在，它看起来会更复杂一些。
But it will scale better over time.
但随着时间的推移，它将变得更易于扩展。
So within my code here, I'm going to go ahead
因此，在我这里代码中，我将继续
and essentially type out exactly that same data type.
并基本上完全写出相同的数据类型。
So define a structure that has inside of it a string called name and a string
因此，定义一个结构，其中包含一个名为“name”的字符串和一个名为“number”的字符串
called number.
叫做数字。
And let's call this thing a person.
我们称之为一个人。
So these new lines copied and pasted from the slide a moment ago just
所以，片刻前从幻灯片中复制和粘贴的这些新行，
invent the data type called person.
发明了名为“person”的数据类型。
So the only thing we need today is the syntax via which
因此，我们今天唯一需要的是语法，通过它
we can set a person's name and number-- like, how can we access those values.
我们可以设置一个人的姓名和号码--比如，我们如何访问这些值。
So to do this, I'm going to go ahead and erase the hard-coded arrays
所以，为了做到这一点，我将继续删除之前硬编码的数组
that I had before.
之前我有的。
And I'm going to give myself one array of type person called people
我将给自己一个名为“people”的“person”类型数组
with room for three people.
有三个人的空间。
So this seems like a bit of a mouthful.
所以，这听起来有点拗口。
But the new data type is called person.
但新的数据类型被称为“person”。
The array name is called people, which in English is weird.
数组名称叫“people”，这在英语中很奇怪。
I mean, it could call it persons to make it a little more parallel.
我的意思是，它可以称之为“persons”，使其更加平行。
But we call them people, generally.
但我们通常称他们为“people”。
And I want three such people in my phone book.
我想要在我的电话簿中拥有三个这样的人。
Now, how do I actually initialize those people?
现在，我该如何实际初始化这些人呢？
Well, previously, I did something like this-- names, bracket, 0.
好吧，之前，我做了一些类似于这样的事情--“names”，方括号，“0”。
And then I did numbers, bracket, 0.
然后，我做了“numbers”，方括号，“0”。
Well, it's a similar idea.
好吧，这是一个类似的想法。
I do people, bracket, 0.
我做“people”，方括号，“0”。
But if I want to set this person's name, the one new piece of syntax today
但如果我想设置这个人的名字，今天新的一段语法
is a period, a literal dot operator, that says go inside of this person
是一个句点，一个字面上的点运算符，它表示进入这个人内部
and access their name field or their name attribute.
并访问他们的姓名字段或姓名属性。
And set it equal to, quote, unquote, "Carter."
并将其设置为，引号，“Carter”。
Then go into that same person.
然后进入同一个人。
But go into their number field.
但进入他们的号码字段。
And set that equal to plus 1, 617-495-1000.
并将其设置为加1，617-495-1000。
Then-- and I'll just separate it with white space
然后--我将用空格将其分隔开
for readability-- go into people bracket 1.
为了易读性--进入“people”方括号“1”。
Set their name into mine, David.
将他们的名字设置为我的名字，“David”。
Let's go into people bracket 1 number.
让我们进入“people”方括号“1”的“number”。
Set that equal to the same, since we're both available through the directory,
将其设置为相同，因为我们俩都可以通过目录访问，
so 617-495-1000.
所以是617-495-1000。
And then lastly, let's go ahead and do people bracket 2 dot name equals,
最后，让我们继续执行“people”方括号“2”点“name”等于
quote, unquote, "John," and then people bracket 2 dot number equals, quote,
引号，“John”，然后“people”方括号“2”点“number”等于，引号
unquote, "plus 1, 949-468-2750--
引号，“加1，949-468-2750--
let me fix my dash--
让我修正我的连字符--
semicolon.
分号。
And now I think I can mostly keep the rest of the code the same
现在我认为我可以将大部分代码保持原样
because if I'm searching for this person's name,
因为如果我要搜索这个人的名字，
I think the only thing I want to change is this because I don't have a names
我认为唯一要更改的是这部分，因为我不再有names
array anymore.
数组了。
So what should I change this highlighted phrase to in order
所以，为了搜索第i个人的姓名，我应该将这个高亮显示的短语更改为
to search the ith person's name?
什么？
What should this be?
这应该是什么？
Yeah?
对吗？
People bracket i dash name because the whole point of this loop
people[i].name，因为这个循环的全部目的是
is to iterate over each of these people one at a time.
一次迭代一个地遍历这些人。
So people bracket i gives me the ith person-- first [INAUDIBLE] people 0,
所以，people[i]给了我第i个人——第一个（无法识别）people 0，
people 1, people 2.
people 1，people 2。
But if on each iteration, I want to check that person's name
但是，如果在每次迭代中，我想检查该人的姓名
and compare it against whatever the human typed in,
并将其与用户输入的内容进行比较，
now I can do exactly that.
我现在就可以做到。
But I have to change the output to be people bracket i dot number,
但我必须将输出更改为people[i].number，
in this case.
在这种情况下。
So I've added a little bit of complexity.
所以，我增加了一些复杂性。
And granted, this is not going to be the way long term you create a phone book.
当然，从长远来看，这并不是创建电话簿的方式。
Odds are, we're going to get the phone book with a loop of some sort.
很有可能，我们会使用某种循环来获取电话簿。
We're going to use a constant, so I know how many people I have room for.
我们将使用一个常量，这样我就知道可以容纳多少人。
For demonstration sake, I'm just typing everything out manually.
为了演示，我正在手动输入所有内容。
But I think logically now, we've achieved the same thing.
但我认为现在逻辑上我们已经实现了相同的功能。
So let me do make phone book for this new version--
所以，让我为这个新版本创建phone book——
no syntax errors-- dot slash phone book.
没有语法错误——./phone book。
Let's search for Carter-- enter.
我们搜索Carter——回车。
And there indeed is his number.
他的号码确实在那里。
Let's go ahead and search for David.
让我们继续搜索David。
There's my number.
我的号码在那里。
And lastly, let's search for John--
最后，我们搜索John——
his number.
他的号码。
And again, we'll search for someone we know is not there--
再一次，我们搜索一个我们知道不存在的人——
Eli.
Eli。
And Eli is not found.
Eli没有找到。
So what we've done is try to solve this problem of introducing a brand new data
所以，我们所做的是尝试解决引入一个全新的数据的问题
type that allows us to represent this custom data that you and I just
类型，这种类型允许我们表示您和我在
created.
创建的自定义数据。
And that is by using the struct keyword to cluster these things together
而实现方法是使用struct关键字将这些东西聚合在一起
and the typedef keyword to give it a brand new name that we might like.
并使用typedef关键字为它赋予一个新的我们喜欢的名字。
Now, as an aside, when it comes to styling your code,
另外，在代码风格方面，
you'll actually see that style50 and similar tools will actually
您实际上会发现，style50和类似的工具实际上会
put the name of the data type on the same line as the closing curly brace,
将数据类型的名称放在与闭合大括号相同的行上，
just sort of a curiosity.
只是好奇心而已。
That's fine.
这没问题。
Even though I wrote it the first way for consistency
即使我为了与Scratch和我们之前的示例保持一致而以第一种方式编写，
with Scratch and our prior examples, this is the right way in styling it.
但这是正确的方式。
Any questions now on this data type?
现在对这个数据类型有任何问题吗？
Yeah?
有吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[无法识别]
DAVID MALAN: The question is, do you have
DAVID MALAN：问题是，您是否
to assign both the name and the number when creating a person?
在创建一个人时，必须同时分配姓名和号码吗？
Or can you only get away with assigning one of them?
或者您只能分配其中一个？
You can.
你可以。
But that's going to be one of those so-called garbage values, typically.
但这通常将成为所谓的垃圾值之一。
And so there's just going to be some bogus data there.
因此，那里将有一些虚假的数据。
And unless you are so careful as to never touch that field thereafter,
除非你非常小心，以后再也不碰那个字段，
you probably run the risk of some kind of bug, even a crash in your code,
你很可能会遇到某种错误，甚至代码崩溃，
if you try to access that value later, even though you've never
如果你稍后尝试访问该值，即使你从未
initialized it.
初始化过它。
So yes, it's possible.
所以，是的，这是可能的。
But no, do not do that.
但是，不，不要这样做。
Other questions?
还有其他问题吗？
No?
没有？
All right, well, now that we have the ability
好吧，现在我们有了能力
to sort of represent more interesting structures, up until now,
来表示更有趣的结构，到目前为止，
we've sort of assumed that in order to get to binary search,
我们一直假设，为了进行二分查找，
we have a phone book that someone already sorted for us.
我们有一本电话簿，有人已经为我们排序了。
For our second demonstration with our volunteers,
对于我们与志愿者的第二次演示，
we assumed that someone, Carter in that case,
我们假设有人，在这种情况下是 Carter，
had already sorted the information for us.
已经为我们排序了信息。
It was proposed by the audience that, well,
观众提出了，嗯，
what if we sort the information first and then go find the number 50?
如果我们先对信息进行排序，然后再去查找数字 50 会怎样？
That invited the question even early on-- well, how expensive is it to sort?
这在早期就引发了一个问题——嗯，排序的成本有多高？
How much time and money and inefficiency do Google and Microsoft and others
谷歌、微软和其他公司花了多少时间、金钱和效率
spend to keep their data and our data sorted?
来保持他们的数据和我们的数据排序？
Well, let's consider what the problem really is.
好吧，让我们考虑一下这个问题的本质。
If this is how we represent any problem, the unsorted data
如果这就是我们表示任何问题的方式，未排序的数据
that we might consume by typing things in randomly to a search engine
我们可能通过在搜索引擎中随机输入内容来消费这些数据
or crawling the internet or just adding context in any old order to our phone
或抓取互联网，或只是以任何顺序将上下文添加到我们的电话中
is arguably unsorted.
可以说是未排序的。
It's certainly not alphabetically sorted by default.
它肯定不是默认按字母顺序排序的。
But we want to get it sorted.
但我们想要对它进行排序。
And so somewhere in here in this black box, we need a set of algorithms
因此，在这个黑盒子里面的某个地方，我们需要一组算法
for actually sorting information as well.
来对信息进行排序。
For instance, if we have these integers here unsorted--
例如，如果我们有这些未排序的整数——
72541603-- effectively random, the problem of sorting, of course,
72541603——实际上是随机的，当然，排序问题
is to turn it into 01234567 instead.
就是要把它变成 01234567。
And there's a bunch of different ways to do this.
有很多不同的方法可以做到这一点。
But before we do that, I think it's probably time for some brownies.
但在我们进行之前，我认为可能是吃布朗尼的时候了。
So let's go ahead and take a 10-minute break.
所以让我们休息 10 分钟。
And we'll see you in 10.
10 分钟后见。
All right, we are back.
好的，我们回来了。
And where we left off was this cliffhanger.
我们上次结束的地方是这个悬念。
We've got some unsorted numbers.
我们有一些未排序的数字。
We want to make them sorted.
我们想要对它们进行排序。
How do we do this?
我们该如何做到呢？
And at the risk of one too many volunteers,
冒着志愿者太多的风险，
could we get eight more volunteers?
我们可以再找八个志愿者吗？
Wow, OK, overwhelming.
哇，好的，太多了。
OK, how about 1, 2, 3, 4.
好的，1、2、3、4 怎么样？
How about all three of you?
你们三位怎么样？
OK, 5, 6, 7--
好的，5、6、7——
OK, 8.
好的，8。
Come on.
来吧。
All right, one from each section--
好的，每个部分选一个人——
all right, come on down.
好的，请下来。
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
[声音交叠]
DAVID MALAN: All right, come on down.
大卫·马兰：好的，请下来。
Thank you.
谢谢。
And if you all could grab a number here.
请你们每个人从这里拿一个数字。
So you'll be 7.
所以你就是7号。
Stand on the left there if you could.
如果你能的话，请站在左边。
All right, you'll be number 2.
好的，你就是2号。
Stand to his left.
站在他的左边。
OK, keep coming.
好的，继续来。
OK, yeah.
好的，没错。
OK, here we go.
好的，开始吧。
There you go.
好了。
OK, [INAUDIBLE] 0 and 3.
好的，[听不清] 0和3。
OK, so let's just make sure they match what we've got there.
好的，让我们确保这些数字与我们之前得到的一致。
Good so far.
目前为止都很好。
OK, so we have eight volunteers here, an array of volunteers, if you would.
好的，我们这里有8名志愿者，一排志愿者，如果你愿意这么说的话。
This time, we've used eight rather than seven.
这次，我们用了8个人而不是7个人。
We deliberately had seven lockers just so that the divide by 2 math
我们故意设置了7个储物柜，这样除以2的计算
worked out.
就能算出来。
That was very deliberate that there was always a [INAUDIBLE] a middle,
这是刻意安排的，因为始终有一个[听不清] 中间，
a middle, a middle.
中间，中间。
In this case, it doesn't matter because we're going to focus on sorting.
在这种情况下，这并不重要，因为我们要专注于排序。
But first, how about some introductions from each group?
但首先，每个小组都介绍一下自己吧？
AUDIENCE: I'm Rebecca.
观众：我是丽贝卡。
I'm a first year in Pennypacker.
我是一年级学生，在佩妮帕克学院。
And I'm thinking about studying environmental science
我正在考虑学习环境科学
and public policy.
和公共政策。
[CHEERING]
[欢呼]
DAVID MALAN: Nice.
大卫·马兰：不错。
[APPLAUSE]
[鼓掌]
AUDIENCE: I'm [? Mariella. ?] I'm also in Pennypacker.
观众：我是[？马里埃拉？]，我也在佩妮帕克学院。
I'm a first year.
我是一年级学生。
And I'm thinking of studying bioengineering.
我正在考虑学习生物工程。
DAVID MALAN: Wonderful.
大卫·马兰：太棒了。
AUDIENCE: My name's [? Haron ?] [? Li. ?] I'm a freshman in Matthews.
观众：我叫[？哈伦？] [？李？]，我是马修学院的大一新生。
I'm planning on studying applied mathematics.
我打算学习应用数学。
DAVID MALAN: Nice-- Matthews.
大卫·马兰：不错——马修学院。
AUDIENCE: My name is Emily.
观众：我叫艾米丽。
I'm a first year in Canada.
我是一年级学生，在加拿大学院。
And I'm still deciding what to study.
我还在决定学什么。
DAVID MALAN: Fair.
大卫·马兰：说得有道理。
AUDIENCE: My name's [? Tanai. ?] I'm a first year from Toronto.
观众：我叫[？塔奈？]，我是多伦多来的大一新生。
And I'm planning on studying ECON and CS.
我打算学习经济学和计算机科学。
DAVID MALAN: Nice.
大卫·马兰：不错。
AUDIENCE: My name is Teddy.
观众：我叫泰迪。
I'm a first year in Hurlbut.
我是一年级学生，在赫尔伯特学院。
And I'm planning on concentrating in computer science with linguistics.
我打算主修计算机科学和语言学。
DAVID MALAN: Nice.
大卫·马兰：不错。
AUDIENCE: Yeah!
观众：是的！
DAVID MALAN: Nice.
大卫·马兰：不错。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
AUDIENCE: My name's [? Lenny. ?] I'm a first year in Matthews.
观众：我叫[？莱尼？]，我是一年级学生，在马修斯学院。
And I'm planning on concentrating in gov and CS.
我打算主修政府和计算机科学。
DAVID MALAN: Ah, nice.
大卫·马兰：啊，不错。
[CHEERING]
[欢呼]
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
And?
还有呢？
AUDIENCE: My name is Eli.
观众：我叫伊莱。
I'm a first year in Hollis.
我是一年级学生，在霍利斯学院。
And I plan on concentrating in CS.
我打算主修计算机科学。
DAVID MALAN: Eli, we keep looking for you today.
大卫·马兰：伊莱，我们今天一直在找你。
OK, so if you guys could scooch a little bit this way just
好的，如果你们能稍微往这边挪动一下，
to be a little more centered.
这样更居中一些。
Notice that this array of volunteers is entirely unsorted.
注意，这组志愿者完全没有排序。
So we thought we'd do three passes at this.
所以我们想对此进行三次操作。
Could you all sort yourselves from smallest to largest?
你们能从最小到最大给自己排序吗？
Go.
开始。
All right, that was very good.
好的，这做得很好。
So yes, so, sure.
所以，是的，当然。
OK.
好的。
[CHEERING]
[欢呼]
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
And let's see.
我们来看看。
What was your algorithm?
你的算法是什么？
AUDIENCE: I just kind of found the person that
观众：我只是找到了那个
was, like, one lower or one higher.
比我低一个或高一个的人。
So I looked at him.
所以我看着他。
He had 2.
他拿的是2。
So I knew I had to be on his left.
所以我明白我得站在他的左边。
And then she had 3.
然后她拿的是3。
So I told her to come to my right.
所以我叫她到我右边。
And then I knew he had 5.
然后我知道他拿的是5。
DAVID MALAN: OK, nice-- pretty clever.
大卫·马兰：好的，不错，很聪明。
And how about your algorithm?
你的算法呢？
AUDIENCE: Same thing-- looked for the number that was lower and higher
观众：一样，我找到了比我低和高的数字
and found the middle.
然后找到了中间的那个。
DAVID MALAN: OK, interesting, because I think from the outside view,
大卫·马兰：好的，很有趣，因为我认为从外部视角来看，
it all seemed very organic.
这一切看起来都很自然。
And things just kind of worked themselves out, which is fine.
事情就这么自然而然地解决了，这很好。
But I dare say what you guys did was probably a little hard for me
但我敢说，你们做的事情可能对我来说有点难
to translate into code.
翻译成代码。
So let me propose that we take two passes at this.
所以，我建议我们对此进行两次操作。
If you could reset yourselves to be in that order from left
如果你能回到原来的顺序，从左
to right, which is just the exact same sequence, just so that we're
到右，也就是完全相同的顺序，这样我们就能
starting from the same point each time.
每次都从同一个点开始。
[INAUDIBLE]
[听不清]
Very good.
非常好。
All right, so let me propose this.
好的，我来提议一下。
We can approach sorting in a couple of different ways.
我们可以用几种不同的方法来进行排序。
But it needs to be methodical.
但需要有条理。
Like, it needs to translate ideally to pseudocode and eventually code.
例如，它需要理想地转换为伪代码，最终转换为代码。
So as much as we can quantize things to be step by step,
因此，我们尽可能地将事情量化成一步一步的步骤，
I think the better this will scale overall,
我认为这样做能使整体规模更大，
especially when there's not eight people but maybe there's 80 people or 800.
尤其是在不是八个人，而是八个人或八百人的情况下。
Because I dare say that if we had everyone in the room sort themselves--
因为我敢说，如果我们让房间里的每个人自己排序，
if they were all handling a number--
如果他们都处理一个数字，
like, that probably wouldn't have worked out very well.
这样可能不会很有效。
It probably would have taken forever because there's just so much more data.
这可能要花费很长时间，因为数据量要多得多。
So let's be a little more methodical.
所以让我们更有条理一些。
So for instance, I don't have a bird's eye view of the numbers
例如，我没有一个鸟瞰的视角去看这些数字，
just as before because even though we don't
就像之前一样，尽管我们没有
have doors in front of our volunteers, they're effectively lockers too.
在志愿者前面设置了门，但他们实际上也是储物柜。
And the computer or the human in my case can only look at one door at a time.
而电脑或像我一样的人一次只能看一个门。
So if I want to find the smallest number and put it
所以，如果我想找到最小的数字并把它
where it should go on the left, I can't just
放到它应该在左边的地方，我不能仅仅
take a step back and be like, OK, obviously, there's the one.
后退一步说，好吧，显然，这里有一个。
I have to do it more methodically.
我必须更有条理地做这件事。
So I'm going to check here--
所以我要检查一下这里 -
7.
7。
At the moment, this is actually the smallest number I've seen.
目前，这是我见过的最小的数字。
So I'm going to make mental note of it.
所以我要把它记在心里。
OK, 2 I see now.
好的，我现在看到的是 2。
I can forget about the 7 because 2 is clearly smaller.
我可以忘记 7，因为 2 显然更小。
5-- I don't need to remember it.
5 - 我不需要记住它。
4-- I don't need to remember it.
4 - 我不需要记住它。
1-- OK, that's clearly smaller.
1 - 好的，这显然更小。
Have I found my smallest number?
我已经找到最小的数字了吗？
Not even because there actually is a 0.
还没有，因为实际上有一个 0。
So I should go through the whole list.
所以我要遍历整个列表。
But I will remember that my smallest element is now 1.
但我会记住，我现在的最小元素是 1。
6 is not smaller-- oh, 0 is smaller, so I'll remember this.
6 不比它小 - 哦，0 比它小，所以我会记住它。
3 is not smaller.
3 不比它小。
And so now, our volunteer for 0-- what was your name?
现在，0 的志愿者 - 你叫什么名字？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
观众：[听不清]
DAVID MALAN: Mariana, and where should we put you clearly?
DAVID MALAN：玛丽安娜，我们应该把你放到哪里？
So there.
放在那里。
But what's your name again?
但你叫什么名字？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID MALAN: Eli's in the way.
DAVID MALAN：伊莱挡路了。
So we could have Mary Ellen?
所以我们可以让玛丽·艾伦来？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID MALAN: [? Mariella ?] just go to the right of Eli.
DAVID MALAN：[玛丽埃拉？] 就在伊莱的右边。
But that's kind of cheating, right?
但这样有点作弊，对吧？
Because if this is an array, recall that they are contiguous.
因为如果这是一个数组，请记住它们是连续的。
But there could be other stuff in memory to the left and to the right.
但内存中可能有其他东西在左边和右边。
So that's not quite fair.
所以这不太公平。
We can't just have the luxury of putting things wherever we want.
我们不能仅仅享受把东西放在任何我们想要的地方的奢侈。
But Eli, you're not even in the right order, anyway.
但埃利，无论如何你甚至没有排在正确的位置。
So why don't we just swap you two.
所以我们为什么不交换你们两个呢？
So [? Mariella ?] and Eli swap.
所以 [？玛丽埃拉？] 和埃利交换。
But now I've taken one bite out of this problem.
但现在我已经从这个问题中啃下一口了。
I've coincidentally made it a little better
我无意中让它变得好了一点
by moving Eli closer to where he is.
通过将埃利移近他的位置。
But you know what?
但你知道吗？
He was in a random location, anyway.
无论如何，他在一个随机的位置。
So I don't think I made the problem any worse, fundamentally.
所以我不认为我从根本上使问题变得更糟。
Now I can do this again.
现在我可以再做一次。
And I can shave a little bit of time off of it
我也可以节省一点时间
because I don't need to revisit [? Mariella ?] because if she
因为我不需要再去看 [？玛丽埃拉？] 因为如果她
was the smaller and I've already selected her from the array,
是最小的，我已经从数组中选中了她，
I can just move on and take one fewer bites this time around.
我可以直接继续，这次少啃一口。
So 2 is the smallest number, not 5, not 4.
所以 2 是最小的数字，不是 5，也不是 4。
OK, 1 is the smallest number.
好的，1 是最小的数字。
So I'm going to remember that as with a mental variable- 6, 7, 3.
所以我将用一个心理变量来记住它 - 6, 7, 3。
OK, 1 is the smallest.
好的，1 是最小的。
So let me select number 1.
所以让我选择数字 1。
And we're going to have to evict you, which
我们必须把你赶出去，这
is making the problem slightly worse.
使问题稍微变得更糟。
But I think it'll average out.
但我认为这会平均出来。
And now 0 and 1 are in the right place.
现在 0 和 1 在正确的位置了。
So now let me do this again but faster.
所以现在让我再做一次，但要快一点。
So 5-- OK, 4--
所以 5 - 好的，4 -
2 is the smallest--
2 是最小的 -
6, 7, 3.
6, 7, 3。
OK, 2, let's put you where you belong, evicting 5.
好的，2，让我们把你放在你该在的地方，赶走 5。
Now I can skip all three of these volunteers.
现在我可以跳过这三个志愿者。
OK, 4, is the smallest.
好的，4 是最小的。
Nope.
不是。
3, you're the smallest.
3，你是最小的。
Let me evict 4.
让我赶走 4。
All right, and now let me move in front of these volunteers.
好的，现在让我走到这些志愿者前面。
5, 6, 7, 4, come on back.
5，6，7，4，回来。
All right, and now let's select 6, 7, 5.
好的，现在让我们选择 6，7，5。
OK, come on back.
好的，回来。
Oh, no, no cheating, Eli.
哦，不，不作弊，埃利。
OK, and then let's see.
好的，然后让我们看看。
5, 7, 6-- OK, 6, come on back.
5，7，6 - 好的，6，回来。
OK, now you have to move.
好的，现在你必须移动。
OK, and now we've selected in turn all of the numbers from left to right.
好的，现在我们已经依次从左到右选择了所有数字。
And even though that did feel slower--
尽管这感觉有点慢 -
I was doing it a little more verbally as I stepped through it--
我在一步一步地做的时候，用更多的话语来表达它 -
but I dare say we could translate that probably more to code.
但我敢说我们可能可以将它更多地翻译成代码。
Why?
为什么？
Because there's a lot of, like, looping through it
因为有很多像循环遍历之类的
and probably a lot of conditionals just asking the question,
而且可能有很多条件语句只是在问这个问题
is this number smaller than this one or conversely greater than this other one.
这个数字是否小于这个数字，或者反过来是否大于另一个数字。
All right, let's do this one more time.
好了，我们再做一次。
If you guys could reset yourselves to this ordering.
如果你们能将自己重置为这个顺序。
All right, so we again have 72541603.
好了，我们再次得到72541603。
Good.
好的。
So how about this?
那么这个怎么样？
I liked the intuition that they originally
我喜欢他们最初的直觉
had, funny enough, whereby they just kind of organically
有，很有趣，他们只是自然而然地
looked to the person to the left and to the right
看了一下左边和右边的人
and kind of fixed the problem.
并试图解决问题。
So if they were out of order, they just kind of swapped locally adjacent
所以如果它们是乱序的，他们只是在本地交换了相邻的
to each other.
彼此。
So let's try this.
所以让我们试试这个。
So 7 and 2, you're clearly out of order.
所以7和2，你们显然是乱序的。
So let's swap just you two.
所以让我们只交换你们两个。
7 and 5, you're out of order.
7和5，你们是乱序的。
Let's swap you two.
让我们交换你们两个。
7 and 4, let's swap you two.
7和4，让我们交换你们两个。
7 and 1, let's swap you two.
7和1，让我们交换你们两个。
7 and 6, let's swap you two.
7和6，让我们交换你们两个。
7 and 0, swap you two.
7和0，交换你们两个。
7 and 3, swap you two.
7和3，交换你们两个。
OK, that was a lot of swapping.
好吧，交换了很多次。
But notice what happened.
但请注意发生了什么。
I'm not done, clearly.
我显然还没完成。
It's not sorted yet.
它还没有排序。
But I have improved the situation.
但我已经改善了情况。
How?
怎么？
Who is now definitely in the right place?
现在谁肯定是在正确的位置？
So, 7-- or Eli has wonderfully bubbled all the way up to the top of the list,
所以，7——或者说Eli已经神奇地冒泡到列表的顶部了，
so to speak.
可以这么说。
Now I can actually skip him moving forward.
现在我实际上可以跳过他继续前进。
So that takes one bite out of the problem.
所以这消除了问题的一部分。
Let's do this again.
让我们再做一次。
2 and 5 are OK.
2和5没问题。
5 and 4, let's swap.
5和4，让我们交换。
No, over there.
不，在那边。
[LAUGHS] Thank you.
[笑] 谢谢。
5 and 1, let's swap.
5和1，让我们交换。
5 and 6 are good.
5和6没问题。
6 and 0, let's swap.
6和0，让我们交换。
6 and 3, let's swap.
6和3，让我们交换。
And we don't have to worry about Eli.
我们不必担心Eli。
And now, what's your name again?
现在，你叫什么名字来着？
AUDIENCE: [? Haron. ?]
观众：[？哈伦。？]
DAVID MALAN: [? Haron-- ?] we don't have to worry about him either as well.
戴维·马兰：[？哈伦——？] 我们也不必担心他。
So now I can go back to the beginning.
所以现在我可以回到开头。
And even though it feels like I'm going back and forth a lot,
虽然感觉我在来回很多次，
that's OK because the problem's still getting better and better.
没关系，因为问题越来越好了。
I'm taking a bite out of it each time.
我每次都解决一部分。
2 and 4 are good.
2 和 4 很好。
4 and 1, let's swap.
4 和 1，我们交换一下。
4 and 5 are good.
4 和 5 很好。
5 and 0, swap.
5 和 0，交换一下。
5 and 3, swap.
5 和 3，交换一下。
And now these three are in the right place.
现在这三个数字放在正确的位置了。
Let's do it again.
我们再来一次。
2 and 1-- ah, here we go.
2 和 1，啊，我们开始了。
Let's swap.
我们交换一下。
2 and 4 are OK.
2 和 4 很好。
4 and 0, swap.
4 和 0，交换一下。
4 and 3, swap.
4 和 3，交换一下。
Now, these four are OK.
现在，这四个数字都很好。
1 and 2, you're good.
1 和 2，你们很好。
2 and 0, swap.
2 和 0，交换一下。
2 and 3, you're good.
2 和 3，你们很好。
You're good.
你们很好。
OK, now 1 and 0, swap--
好了，现在 1 和 0，交换一下。
1 and 2 and now 0 and 1.
1 和 2，现在 0 和 1。
A round of applause if we could for our volunteers.
让我们为我们的志愿者们鼓掌吧。
[APPLAUSE]
[鼓掌声]
[CHEERING]
[欢呼声]
So if you want to put your numbers on the tray there,
所以如果你想把你的数字放在那个托盘上，
we have some lovely Super Mario Oreos today, which
我们今天有美味的超级马里奥奥利奥饼干，这可能
maybe drives a lot of the volunteerism.
促进了很多志愿行为。
But here we go.
但我们开始了。
Thank you all so much.
非常感谢大家。
And maybe, Carter, if you can help with the reset?
也许，卡特，你能帮忙重置一下？
All right, here we go.
好了，我们开始了。
[INAUDIBLE] yes, all set.
[听不见]是的，都准备好了。
Thank you very much.
非常感谢。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Thank you, guys.
谢谢，伙计们。
Thank you, yes.
谢谢，是的。
To recap, let's actually formalize a little more algorithmically
回顾一下，让我们用更算法的方式正式化一下
what we did.
我们所做的。
And I deliberately kind of orchestrated things
我故意安排了一些事情
there to show two fundamentally different approaches, one
在那里展示两种截然不同的方法，一种
where I kind of selected the element I wanted again and again
我一遍又一遍地选择我想要的元素
on the basis of how small it was.
根据它的尺寸大小。
I looked for the smallest, then the next smallest, and so forth.
我找到了最小的，然后是下一个最小的，依此类推。
The second time around, I took a different approach
第二次，我采用了不同的方法
by just fixing local problems.
仅仅解决局部问题。
But I did it again and again and again until I
但我一遍又一遍地做，直到我
fixed all of the minor problems.
解决了所有的小问题。
And frankly, what they did organically at the beginning
坦率地说，他们一开始自然而然地做的事情
was probably closer to the second algorithm than the first,
可能更接近于第二种算法而不是第一种算法，
even though I'm not sure they would write down the same pseudocode for it.
尽管我不确定他们会为它写下相同的伪代码。
The first algorithm we executed is actually called selection sort.
我们执行的第一个算法实际上称为选择排序。
And I deliberately used that vernacular of selecting
我故意使用了这种选择的方式
the smallest element again and again to evoke this name of the algorithm.
反复选择最小的元素来唤起这个算法的名称。
So for instance, when we had these numbers here initially unsorted,
例如，当我们最初没有对这些数字进行排序时，
I kept looking again and again and again for the smallest element.
我一遍又一遍地寻找最小的元素。
And I don't know a priori what the smallest number is until I
而且我事先不知道最小的数字是什么，直到我
go through the list at least once.
至少遍历列表一次。
Then I can pluck out the 0.
然后我可以选出 0。
I then go through the list a second time to pluck out the 1, a third time
然后我第二次遍历列表来选出 1，第三次
to pluck out the 2.
选出 2。
Now, this assumes that I don't have an infinite amount of memory
现在，这假设我没有无限的内存
because even though I kept repeating myself looking for the next smallest
因为即使我不断重复自己寻找下一个最小的
element, next smallest element, I propose that I only
元素，下一个最小的元素，我建议我仅仅
keep track of one number at a time, one variable in my mind, which
一次跟踪一个数字，我脑海中一个变量，它
was the smallest element I have seen thus far.
是我迄今为止见过的最小元素。
If I used more memory, I could probably remember from the first pass
如果我使用更多内存，我可能会从第一次遍历中记住
where the 2 is, where the 3 is.
2 在哪里，3 在哪里。
But that's a different algorithm.
但那是不同的算法。
And it would take more space, more memory.
并且它会占用更多空间，更多内存。
I was confining myself to just one variable in my approach.
我在方法中只限制自己使用一个变量。
So here might be the pseudocode for what we'd call selection
所以这里可能是我们称之为选择排序的伪代码
sort, the very first algorithm that we all did together, not organically,
排序，我们大家一起做的第一个算法，不是自发的，
but more methodically as a group.
而是更有条理地作为团队。
I would propose that we use some syntax from C when we talk about the loop
我建议我们在谈论循环时使用 C 中的一些语法
and say for i from 0 to n minus 1.
并说从 0 到 n 减 1 的 i。
Now, why is that?
现在，为什么这样？
Well, if there were n people or 8, 0 through 7
嗯，如果有 n 个人或 8 个人，从 0 到 7
are the indexes or indices of those humans on stage from left to right.
是这些站在舞台上的人从左到右的索引。
So what did I have myself do?
所以我自己做了什么？
Find the smallest number between numbers bracket i and numbers bracket
在数字括号 i 和数字括号之间找到最小的数字
n minus 1.
n 减 1。
So when the loop starts at 0, this is literally
所以当循环从 0 开始时，这实际上是
saying between numbers bracket 0 and numbers bracket n minus 1.
说在数字括号 0 和数字括号 n 减 1 之间。
So from the far left to the far right, find me the smallest number.
所以从最左边到最右边，找到最小的数字。
Then swap that number with numbers bracket i.
然后将该数字与数字括号 i 交换。
So that's why we evicted the person all the way
所以这就是为什么我们第一次将那个人赶到最右边或最左边的原因，
over to the right or your left the very first time,
然后是下一个人，下一个人，等等。
and then the next person, and the next person, and so forth.
所以这是一个让我们来回移动的算法，来回移动，
So this is an algorithm that has us go back and forth, back and forth,
迭代地选择最小的元素。
iteratively selecting the smallest element.
所以如果我们现在将其推广，而不是从 8 个人推广到 n 个人，
So if we generalize this now, not away from eight people to, like, n people,
你可以将它们视为表示一个数组，也称为
you can think of them as representing an array, a.k.a.
像这样的门，最左边的门是 0，最右边的门是 n 减 1，
doors like this where the leftmost one is 0, the rightmost one is n minus 1,
倒数第二个是 n 减 2，依此类推，如果我们不知道或不关心
second to last is n minus 2, and so forth if we don't know or care
n 的具体值。
what n specifically is.
。
So how many total steps does selection sort perhaps take?
那么选择排序可能需要多少步呢？
And let's make this a little more real here.
让我们在这里更现实一点。
Let me actually open up, for instance, a quick visualization here.
让我在这里打开一个快速的可视化，例如。
And on the screen here, you'll just see now
现在你将在屏幕上看到
an artist's rendition of an array of values whereby tall purple bars
艺术家对一组值的渲染，其中高紫色条
represent big integers.
代表大的整数。
And short purple bars represent small integers.
短的紫色条代表小的整数。
So the idea of any sorting algorithm here as visualized
因此，任何排序算法的思路在这里被可视化
is to get the small bars on the left and the big bars on the right.
是将小的条放在左边，大的条放在右边。
And this is a nice handy tool that lets you play around
这是一个很好的工具，可以让你玩弄
with different algorithms.
不同的算法。
So here is selection sort that I've just clicked.
所以这里是我刚刚点击的选择排序。
In pink again and again is the equivalent
粉红色不断出现，相当于
of me walking through the volunteers looking for the next smallest element.
我走过志愿者，寻找下一个最小的元素。
And as soon as I found them, I swapped them into their leftmost location,
我一找到它们，就把它们交换到最左边的位置，
evicting whoever's there in order to gradually sort
驱逐任何在那里的人，以便逐步排序
this list from left to right.
这个列表从左到右。
And so as you can see here, it holds very briefly in pink
所以在这里你可以看到，它非常短暂地用粉红色显示
whatever the currently smallest element it has found is.
它找到的当前最小元素是什么。
That's the analog of, like, me pointing to my head
这类似于我指着我的头
whereby it's constantly comparing, comparing, comparing,
它不断地比较、比较、比较，
looking for the next smallest element.
寻找下一个最小的元素。
Now, I'm kind of stalling because I'm running out of intelligent words
现在，我有点停顿，因为我快没有聪明的词了
to say.
可以说。
But that is to say, this algorithm feels kind of slow.
但这就是说，这个算法感觉有点慢。
Like, it seems to be doing a lot of work.
就像，它似乎在做很多工作。
Where is the work coming in?
工作是从哪里来的？
Like, what is it doing a lot of specifically?
就像，它具体做了很多什么？
Yeah?
对吧？
Yeah, it keeps going back and forth and back and forth.
是的，它不断地来回移动。
And even though it's shaving a little bit of time,
即使它节省了一点时间，
right, because it doesn't have to stupidly go all the way back
对，因为它不必愚蠢地一直回到
to the beginning, and I was saving myself a few steps,
开头，我节省了一些步骤，
like, it's a lot of cyclicity again and again and again.
就像，它有很多循环，一遍又一遍。
And put another way, it's a lot of comparisons again and again.
换句话说，它做了很多比较，一遍又一遍。
And some of those comparisons you're doing multiple times
而且你多次进行了一些比较
because I only remembered one element at a time in my head.
因为我一次只能记住一个元素。
So I have to kind of remind myself on every pass which
所以我必须在每次传递时提醒自己哪一个
is smallest, which is smallest.
是最小的，哪个是最小的。
So this invites the question how fast or how slow or equivalently
所以这引发了一个问题，像冒泡排序这样东西有多快或多慢，或者等效地
how efficient or inefficient is something like bubble--
有多有效或多无效
selection sort.
选择排序。
Well, let's actually consider how we could analyze this as follows.
好吧，让我们实际考虑一下如何分析它，如下所示。
So if we have n numbers that we want to sort,
所以如果我们有 n 个数字要排序，
how many comparisons do we do the first time?
我们第一次做了多少次比较？
Well, if there's n numbers, you can only make n minus 1 comparisons.
好吧，如果有 n 个数字，你只能进行 n 减 1 次比较。
Why?
为什么？
Because if we have eight people here and we
因为如果我们这里有八个人，然后我们
started with whoever's all the way over here,
从最右边的人开始，
we compare this person against seven others-- n minus 1 if n is 8.
我们会将这个人与另外七个人比较——如果 n 等于 8，那么就是 n 减 1。
So the first pass through the list, I made n minus 1 comparisons.
所以在第一次遍历列表时，我进行了 n 减 1 次比较。
But that put the smallest number 0 in place.
但这把最小的数字 0 放到了正确的位置。
The second time I walked across our eight volunteers,
第二次遍历八位志愿者时，
I didn't need to walk in front of all eight.
我不需要在所有八个人面前走。
I could shave off a little bit and do seven of them,
我可以少走一些，只走七个人，
then six, then five, then four.
然后六个，然后五个，然后四个。
So if I were to write this out roughly mathematically,
所以如果我要用数学语言来表达这个过程，
I could do this-- n minus 1 plus n minus 2 plus n minus 3 plus
我可以这样做——n 减 1 加 n 减 2 加 n 减 3 加
dot, dot, dot, all the way down to my very last comparison
以此类推，一直到最后一个比较
at the end of the list.
在列表的末尾。
Now, this is the kind of thing that typically in high school
现在，这是一种你在高中
you'd look at the back of the math book or physics book
会翻到数学书或物理书后面的
that's got a little cheat sheet for all of the formulas that add up.
公式小抄来查找这些加起来的公式。
This series here, let me just stipulate, adds up to this-- n times
这个系列，我在这里声明一下，加起来等于这个——n 乘以
n minus 1 divided by 2.
n 减 1 除以 2。
So no matter what n is, this formula captures that series,
所以无论 n 是多少，这个公式都能够表达这个系列，
that summation of all of those values.
所有这些值的总和。
So that is how many steps I took again and again
所以这就是我在实现选择排序时，对八个人进行的比较的次数。
and again when implementing selection sort for eight people.
一次又一次，反复进行的操作。
So of course, let's multiply this out.
当然，让我们把它展开。
So this is like n squared minus n all divided by 2.
所以它就像 n 平方减 n，再除以 2。
Let's do it out a little bit more.
让我们再算一下。
That's n squared divided by 2 minus n over 2.
那就是 n 平方除以 2，减去 n 除以 2。
And now we're back into the territory of running times.
现在我们又回到了运行时间这个话题。
Like, how many steps does this algorithm take?
比如，这个算法需要多少步？
How many comparisons are we making?
我们在进行多少次比较？
Now, n squared seems like the biggest term.
现在，n 平方看起来是最大的项。
It's the dominant term.
它是主导项。
In other words, as n gets large-- not eight but 80 or 800
也就是说，当 n 越来越大——不是 8，而是 80 或者 800
or 8,000 or 8 million-- squaring that is going to make a way bigger difference
或者 8000 或者 800 万——把这个数平方会产生一个更大的差异
than just doing, like, n divided by 2 and subtracting that off.
比仅仅将 n 除以 2 然后减去它要大得多。
Similarly, just dividing even this quadratic formula by 2,
同样，即使是将这个二次方程除以 2，
like, yes, it's going to halve it literally.
确实，它会将其减半。
But that's kind of a drop in the bucket.
但这只是一小部分。
As n gets larger and larger and larger, it's
随着 n 越来越大，它
still going to be a crazy big number.
仍然是一个非常大的数字。
So computer scientists would typically wrap this in some big O notation
所以计算机科学家通常会用大 O 表示法来表示这个公式
and say, OK, OK, selection sort is on the order of n squared.
然后说，好的，好的，选择排序的时间复杂度是 n 平方。
That's not a precise measurement.
这不是一个精确的测量。
But it's on the order of n squared because it's
但它是 n 平方级别的，因为它是
making so many darn comparisons, not unlike everyone shaking everyone else's
进行了非常多的比较，就像我之前说的，每个人都互相握手一样。
hand like I proposed verbally earlier.
这需要很多工作才能完成。
It's a lot of work to get that done.
选择排序的步骤数是 n 平方级别。
So selection sort is on the order of n squared steps.
所以选择排序的步骤数是 n 平方级别。
And that's kind of a slow one.
这是一种比较慢的排序方式。
That's what was at the top of my cheat sheet
这是我在我作弊小抄的顶部写的东西
earlier when I proposed a ranking of some common running times.
之前我建议对一些常见运行时间进行排名时。
There's an infinite number of them.
它们的数量是无限的。
But those are some of the common ones.
但那些是比较常见的。
So can we do actually better?
所以我们实际上可以做得更好吗？
Well, if bubble sort then is in big O--
好吧，如果冒泡排序是在大O中-
sorry.
抱歉。
Sorry-- spoiler.
抱歉 - 剧透了。
If selection sort is in the order of n squared,
如果选择排序是n平方级的，
could we maybe get lucky sometimes?
我们可能有时候会幸运吗？
Like, with selection sort, what would the best case scenario be?
比如，对于选择排序，最佳情况是什么？
Well, the best case would be, like, everyone is already sorted,
好吧，最佳情况是，比如，所有元素都已经排序，
0 through 7.
从0到7。
And we just get lucky.
而我们只是幸运。
But does bubble sort--
但冒泡排序-
[SIGHS]---- does selection sort appreciate that?
[叹气]---- 选择排序会对此感到高兴吗？
Does selection sort take into account whether the list is already sorted?
选择排序会考虑列表是否已经排序吗？
Not necessarily, because if you look at the pseudocode even,
不一定，因为即使你查看伪代码，
there's no special conditional in here that says, if it's already sorted,
这里没有特殊的条件语句说，如果它已经排序，
exit early.
就提前退出。
It's just going to blindly do this this many times.
它只是会盲目地做这些事情这么多次。
And you can actually see pseudocode-wise the n squared.
你实际上可以在伪代码中看到n平方。
Notice that this line of pseudocode here is essentially telling me to do what?
注意，这里这行伪代码本质上是在告诉我做什么？
Do something n times from 0 to n minus 1,
从0到n减1，做n次事情，
or equivalently, if you prefer the real world, from 1 to n.
或者等效地，如果你更喜欢现实世界，从1到n。
That's n times total.
总共n次。
But what are you doing inside of this loop?
但在这个循环中，你在做什么？
Well, every time you're inside of this loop,
好吧，每次你在这个循环中，
you're looking for the smallest element, looking for the smallest element.
你都在寻找最小的元素，寻找最小的元素。
And that might take you as many as n steps.
这可能需要你最多n步。
So another way to think about the running time of this algorithm
所以，另一种思考这个算法运行时间的思路是
selection sort is this loop is telling you to do something n times.
选择排序，这个循环在告诉你做n次事情。
This line is telling you to do something n times as well.
这行代码也告诉你做n次事情。
And that's roughly n times n or n squared.
所以，大约是n乘以n，也就是n平方。
It's not precise.
它并不精确。
But it's on the order of n squared.
但它是n平方级的。
Unfortunately, if you're just blindly doing that much work always,
不幸的是，如果你总是盲目地做那么多工作，
even if you have any number of doors, this
即使你有任意数量的门，这
is going to end up being in omega of n squared as well,
最终也会是n平方级的omega，
because even in the best case where all of the numbers are already sorted,
因为即使在所有数字都已经排序的最佳情况下，
there is nothing about the algorithm called selection sort or even
关于叫做选择排序的算法，或者甚至
my implementation thereof that would have said, wait a minute-- like, I'm
我的实现，它会说，等等 - 我好像
done, and exit prematurely.
完成了，并且提前退出。
So selection sort is in big O of and omega
所以选择排序是在大O和omega中
of n squared as we've designed it.
是n平方级的，就像我们设计的那样。
And by coincidence, because those boundaries are the same,
而且巧合的是，因为这些边界是相同的，
you can also say that it's in theta of n squared.
你也可以说它是在n平方的theta中。
No matter what, you're going to spend n squared steps or n squared comparisons.
无论如何，你都将花费n平方步或n平方比较。
But that second algorithm that I keep teasing called bubble sort,
但是我一直在戏弄的第二个算法叫做冒泡排序，
and I deliberately used the word bubble in my description of what
我故意在描述中使用“冒泡”这个词
was happening because Eli, I think was our first volunteer, who
正在发生的事情，因为我认为埃利是我们第一个志愿者，他
kind of bubbled his way up all the way to the end of the list.
一路冒泡到列表的末尾。
Then number 6 did, then 5, then 4, then 3, then 2, then 1.
然后数字 6 冒泡了，然后是 5，然后是 4，然后是 3，然后是 2，然后是 1。
All of the numbers kind of bubbled their way up
所有数字都像冒泡一样向上移动
being the bigger values to the right.
成为更大的值在右侧。
So bubble sort just does something again and again
所以冒泡排序只是反复做一件事
by comparing adjacencies, comparing, comparing, comparing.
通过比较相邻元素，比较、比较、比较。
And then it does it again and again and again.
然后它反复做。
So let's analyze bubble sort.
所以让我们来分析冒泡排序。
If, for instance, this was the original array that we tried sorting before--
例如，这是我们之前尝试排序的原始数组--
same exact numbers--
完全相同的数字--
I was doing things like flipping the 7 and the 2, and then the 7 and the 5,
我做的事情就像交换 7 和 2，然后交换 7 和 5，
and then the 7 and the 4.
然后交换 7 和 4。
But that would only fix minimally one number.
但这只能最小程度地修复一个数字。
I then had to repeat again and again and again.
然后我不得不反复重复。
So that one too felt like it was taking some time.
所以那个也感觉很耗时。
So here's one way of thinking about bubble sort.
所以这里有一种思考冒泡排序的方法。
Bubble sort pseudocode could say this.
冒泡排序伪代码可以这样说。
Repeat the following n times.
重复以下操作 n 次。
And that's why I kept going through the list again and again--
这就是为什么我一直反复遍历列表--
for i from 0 to n minus 2.
从 i=0 到 n-2。
Now, this is a little weird, but we'll get back to this-- from i
现在，这有点奇怪，但我们会回头讨论这个-- 从 i
from 0 to n minus 2.
从 0 到 n-2。
If the number at location i and the number at location i plus 1
如果位置 i 处的数字和位置 i+1 处的数字
are out of order, swap them.
乱序，则交换它们。
And then just repeat, repeat, repeat.
然后重复、重复、重复。
But we've never seen n minus 2 in pseudocode before.
但我们以前从未在伪代码中见过 n-2。
Why is it n minus 2 and not the usual n minus 1?
为什么是 n-2 而不是通常的 n-1？
Yeah?
是的？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID MALAN: Exactly, because we're taking a number
大卫·马兰：没错，因为我们正在取一个数字
and comparing it to the next one.
并将其与下一个数字进行比较。
So you better not go all the way to the end
所以你最好不要一直走到最后
and expect there to be a next one at the end of the list.
并期望在列表的末尾有一个下一个数字。
So if we use these same numbers here, even though they're
所以如果我们在这里使用相同的数字，即使它们
in a different order, if this is location 0,
顺序不同，如果这是位置 0，
and this is location n minus 1 always, if you think
并且这是位置 n-1，如果你认为
of i as being my left hand, it's pointing from 0 to 1 to 2 to 3
i 是我的左手，它从 0 指向 1 指向 2 指向 3
to 4 to 5 to 6 to 7.
指向 4 指向 5 指向 6 指向 7。
If you get to the end, you don't want to look at i plus 1
如果你到了最后，你不想去看 i+1
because that's pointing to no man's land over here.
因为那指向了这里无人区。
And you can't go beyond the boundaries of your array.
而且你不能超出你的数组边界。
But n minus 2 would be the second to last element, as you know.
但是 n-2 将是倒数第二个元素，如你所知。
And that makes sure that my left hand and right
这样就可以确保我的左手和右手
hand stay within the boundaries of the array
手保持在数组边界内
if left hand represents i and right hand represents i plus 1.
如果左手代表 i，右手代表 i+1。
So it's just to make sure we don't screw up and go
所以只是为了确保我们不会搞砸并进入
too far past the boundary of the array.
超出数组范围太远。
But as implemented here, this too does not take into account whether or not
但正如这里实现的，这也忽略了数组是否
the array is already sorted.
已经排序。
So technically, we can actually do this n minus 1 times
因此从技术上讲，我们可以实际进行 n 减 1 次
because the last one you get for free.
因为最后一个是免费的。
It ends up being in place.
它最终会到位。
But even still, let's do a quick analysis here.
但即使如此，让我们在这里快速分析一下。
If we've got n doors in total from 0 on up to n minus 1,
如果我们总共有 n 个门，从 0 到 n 减 1，
bubble sort's analysis looks a little bit like this.
冒泡排序的分析看起来有点像这样。
Do the following-- n minus 1 times n minus 1 times.
执行以下操作——n 减 1 次乘以 n 减 1 次。
Well, how did we get from that?
好吧，我们是怎么从那里得到的？
Let me back up to the pseudocode.
让我回到伪代码。
If this is the pseudocode as I originally put it,
如果这是我最初写的伪代码，
I then propose verbally a refinement.
然后我口头上提出一个改进。
You don't need to repeat yourself n times again and again because again,
你不需要一遍又一遍地重复自己 n 次，因为再一次，
the last one bubbles up.
最后一个冒上来。
But by process of elimination, it's in the right place.
但通过排除法，它在正确的位置。
So you can think of it as just n minus 1 times.
所以你可以把它想象成只是 n 减 1 次。
How many times can you compare i and i plus 1?
你可以比较 i 和 i 加 1 多少次？
Well, you're iterating from 0 to n minus 2.
好吧，你正在从 0 到 n 减 2 迭代。
And this is where the math is going to get weird.
而这正是数学变得奇怪的地方。
But that is n minus 1 steps also.
但那也是 n 减 1 步。
Why?
为什么？
Because if you do it in the real world starting at one,
因为如果你在现实世界中从一开始做，
this is saying from i from 1 to n minus 1.
也就是说从 i 从 1 到 n 减 1。
And then maybe it pops a little more obviously.
然后它可能更明显地弹出。
This inner loop is repeating n minus 1 times.
这个内循环重复了 n 减 1 次。
So outer loop says do the following n minus 1 times.
所以外循环表示执行以下操作 n 减 1 次。
Inner loop says do this now n minus 1 times.
内循环表示现在执行此操作 n 减 1 次。
Mathematically, then, that's n minus 1 times n minus 1.
因此，从数学上讲，那是 n 减 1 乘以 n 减 1。
Now we've got our old FOIL method.
现在我们有了我们的旧 FOIL 方法。
So n squared minus n minus n plus 1.
所以 n 平方减 n 减 n 加 1。
Combine like terms gives us n squared minus 2n plus 1.
合并同类项，我们得到 n 平方减 2n 加 1。
But now let's think like a computer scientist.
但现在让我们像计算机科学家一样思考。
When n gets really large, we definitely don't care about the plus 1.
当 n 变得非常大时，我们绝对不在乎加 1。
When n gets really large, we probably don't even care about the minus 2n.
当 n 变得非常大时，我们可能甚至不在乎减 2n。
It will make a mathematical difference but a drop in the bucket
当 n 达到数百万或数十亿时，它会产生数学上的差异，但只是一滴水
once n gets to be in the millions or billions.
。
So this would be on the order of what, similarly?
那么这将类似于什么数量级？
On the order of n squared as well.
也是 n 平方数量级。
So algorithmically, and actually, we'll use a different term
所以从算法上来说，实际上，我们将使用一个不同的术语
now-- asymptotically-- asymptotic notation is the fancy term
现在——渐近地——渐近表示法是描述大 O、Ω 和 Θ 表示法的专业术语
to describe big O and omega and theta notation-- asymptotically bubble
——渐近地，冒泡
sort is, quote, unquote, "the same" as selection sort
排序，打个引号，“相同”于选择排序
in terms of its upper bound.
就其上界而言。
It's not 100% exactly the same.
它并不完全相同。
If we get into the weeds of the math, there are obviously different formulas.
如果我们深入数学的细节，显然会有不同的公式。
But when n gets really large and you plot the pictures on a chart,
但当 n 变得非常大，并且你在图表上绘制这些图片时，
they're going to look almost the same because they're going
它们看起来几乎是一样的，因为它们正在
to be fundamentally the same shape.
本质上是相同的形状。
So in our cheat sheet here, bubble sort now is in big O of n squared.
因此，在我们这里的速查表中，冒泡排序现在是 n 平方的 O(n^2)。
But let me propose that we make an improvement.
但我建议我们改进一下。
Here's our pseudocode earlier.
这是我们之前的伪代码。
When might it make sense to abort bubble sort early?
什么时候提前中止冒泡排序是有意义的？
Like, when could you logically conclude that I do not need
比如，什么时候你可以逻辑地得出结论，我不需要
to make another pass again and again?
一遍又一遍地进行另一个循环？
And remember what I did from left to right over our volunteers.
还记得我从左到右对志愿者做了什么吗？
I was comparing, comparing, comparing, comparing and maybe swapping
我一直在比较、比较、比较、比较，也许还在交换
people who were out of order.
顺序不对的人。
So what could I do to short circuit this?
所以，我能做些什么来简化这个过程呢？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众： [听不见]
DAVID MALAN: Perfect.
大卫·马兰： 太棒了。
If I compare through the whole list left to right and I make no swaps,
如果我从左到右比较整个列表，并且没有交换，
it stands to reason that they're already ordered.
那么很有道理，它们已经是有序的了。
Otherwise, I would have swapped them.
否则，我会交换它们。
And therefore, I would be crazy to do that again and again and again.
因此，我一遍又一遍地这样做简直是疯了。
Because if I didn't swap them the first time around,
因为如果我第一次没有交换它们，
why would I swap them the second time around if no one's moving.
如果没有人移动，为什么我要在第二次交换它们呢？
So I can terminate the algorithm early.
所以我可以提前终止算法。
So in pseudocode, I could say something like this.
因此，在伪代码中，我可以这样说。
If no swaps, quit.
如果没有任何交换，退出。
And I can do that inside of the inner loop.
我可以在内循环中做到这一点。
So once I make a pass through the people and I say, hm, did I make any swaps?
所以，一旦我遍历了这些人，然后我说，嗯，我做了任何交换吗？
If no, just quit because they're not going
如果没有，那就退出，因为它们不会
to move any further if they didn't just move already.
如果它们没有移动，就不会再移动了。
So bubble sort then might arguably be an omega of what?
那么，冒泡排序可以说是一个什么级别的 omega 呢？
In the best case, how few steps could we get away with with bubble sort?
在最好的情况下，我们使用冒泡排序可以减少到多少步？
OK, it's not one.
好的，不是一步。
But it is n.
但它是 n。
Why?
为什么？
Because I minimally need to go through the whole list to decide,
因为我至少需要遍历整个列表才能决定，
did I make any swaps.
我是否做了任何交换。
And logically-- and this will come up a lot in the analysis of algorithms--
从逻辑上讲 - 这在算法分析中经常出现 -
any question like, is this list sorted, cannot possibly take only one step
像这样的问题，这个列表是否已排序，不可能只用一步
if you've got n elements.
如果你有 n 个元素。
Why?
为什么？
Because then you're just guessing.
因为这样你就只是在猜测。
Like, if you don't at least take the time to look at every element,
就像，如果你至少没有花时间看一下每个元素，
how in the world can you conclude logically that they're sorted or not?
你怎么能逻辑地得出结论，它们是否已排序呢？
Like, you minimally have to meet us halfway and check every element.
就像，你至少必须满足我们一半的要求，并检查每个元素。
So it's minimally in omega of n.
所以它至少是 n 级别的 omega。
Constant time wouldn't even give you time to look at the whole list
如果存在 n 个元素，常数时间甚至不会给你时间查看整个列表。
if there's n elements.
如果存在 n 个元素。
So that's the intuition there.
所以这就是直觉。
So we can't say anything about theta notation for bubble sort
所以我们无法对冒泡排序的 theta 符号做任何判断。
because it's different, upper and lower bounds.
因为它们不同，有上限和下限。
But we seem to have done better asymptotically than selection sort.
但我们似乎在渐进方面比选择排序做得更好。
In the worst case, they're just as bad.
在最坏的情况下，它们一样糟糕。
They're super slow.
它们超级慢。
But in the best case, bubble sort with that tweak--
但在最好的情况下，带有那个调整的冒泡排序--
that conditional about swapping-- might actually be faster for us.
关于交换的条件判断--可能实际上对我们来说更快。
And you'd want Google, Microsoft, your phone, to use that kind of algorithm.
你会希望 Google、微软、你的手机，使用这种算法。
Let me go back to the sorting demonstration earlier.
让我回到之前排序演示。
Let me re-randomize the array.
让我重新随机化数组。
Small bars is small number.
小条代表小数字。
Big bars is big number.
大条代表大数字。
And let me click bubble sort this time.
这次让我点击冒泡排序。
And you'll see again, the pink represents comparisons.
你会再次看到，粉色代表比较。
But now the comparisons are always adjacent from left to right.
但现在比较始终是相邻的，从左到右。
So this is pretty much doing with more bars what I did with eight people here.
所以这基本上就是用更多条，做我在八个人身上做的事情。
And you'll see that the biggest elements, Eli
你会看到最大的元素，Eli
being the first one of the humans, bubbled up
作为第一个，冒泡到最右边
all the way to the right, followed by the next largest, next largest,
最右边，然后是下一个最大的，再下一个最大的，
next largest.
下一个最大的。
But here again you can visually see.
但在这里，你又能直观地看到。
And with the number of words I'm using to kind of stall here,
我用这么多词来拖延时间，
you can [? hear ?] that this is kind of slow
你能感觉到这很慢
because you're doing a lot of comparisons again and again and again.
因为你在不断地进行比较。
And you're making improvements.
而且你在不断改进。
So you're taking bites out of the problem
所以你一步步解决问题
but really only one bite at a time.
但一次只解决一小部分。
So I kind of feel this is going to be like holding in a sneeze
所以我觉得这就像憋着打喷嚏一样
if we don't finish this.
如果我们不完成它。
So I feel like we should give you emotional closure
所以我觉得我们应该给你一个情绪上的结束
with getting this to finish.
让它完成。
Any questions in the meantime because there's going to be no surprise.
在此期间有任何问题吗，因为不会有惊喜。
It's going to be sorted.
它将被排序。
This is bubble sort.
这就是冒泡排序。
No?
没有？
All right, we're almost there.
好了，我们快到了。
It's going faster because the list is effectively getting shorter.
它越来越快，因为列表实际上越来越短了。
And-- oh, OK, so that then was bubble sort.
然后，这就是冒泡排序。
But both of these, I claim now, are actually pretty inefficient.
但我现在声称，这两种方法实际上效率很低。
They're pretty slow.
它们很慢。
And my god, that was only eight humans on the stage.
我的天，舞台上只有八个人。
That was only, like, what, 40 or 50 bars on the screen.
那只是，屏幕上大概只有 40 或 50 根条。
What if we start talking about hundreds or thousands or millions of inputs?
如果我们开始讨论数百、数千甚至数百万个输入呢？
Like, those algorithms are probably going to take crazy
这些算法可能需要疯狂的
long because n squared gets really big.
时间，因为 n 平方变得非常大。
So can we do better than n squared?
所以，我们可以做得比 n 平方更好吗？
Well, we can.
当然可以。
But let me propose that we introduce a new problem-solving technique
但我想提议我们引入一种新的解决问题的技巧
that we've actually been using already, just not by name.
我们实际上一直在使用它，只是没有用名字。
In programming and in mathematics, there's this idea of recursion.
在编程和数学中，有一个叫做递归的概念。
And recursion is a description for a function that calls itself.
递归是对一个函数调用自身的描述。
A function that calls itself is recursive.
一个调用自身的函数就是递归的。
So what do we mean by this?
我们所说的这指的是什么呢？
Well, we've actually seen this already.
事实上，我们已经看到过这种现象。
Here's the same pseudocode for binary search earlier.
这里就是之前二分查找的伪代码。
And binary search-- bi implying two-- went
而二分查找（bi 指的是两个）则会
either left or right or left or right, halving each time.
要么往左要么往右，要么往左要么往右，每次都将范围缩减一半。
So that was the division and conquering.
所以这就是分治法。
So this is the same pseudocode.
所以这就是同样的伪代码。
But notice that in my pseudocode earlier,
但是请注意，在我之前的伪代码中，
I literally used the keyword search inside of my definition of search.
我在 search 的定义中直接使用了 search 这个关键字。
So this is sort of one of those, like, circular definitions.
所以这有点像循环定义。
Like, if this is a search algorithm, how am I
就像，如果这是一个搜索算法，那我怎么
getting away with using the word search in the definition of search?
在 search 的定义中使用 search 这个词却没事？
It's kind of when you get reprimanded for using a word
这就像你因为用某个词
to define a vocabulary word.
来解释一个词汇而受到批评。
This is kind of like that because this algorithm is calling itself.
这和那有点像，因为这个算法正在调用自身。
This search function is calling itself.
这个 search 函数正在调用自身。
Now, normally, if you were to have a function call itself,
通常情况下，如果你让一个函数调用自身，
call itself, call itself, call itself, it would just do that infinitely.
调用自身，调用自身，调用自身，它会无限循环下去。
And presumably, it would go on forever.
可以想见，它会永远执行下去。
Or the program or computer would probably
或者程序或计算机可能会
crash because out of memory or something like that-- more on that next week.
崩溃，因为内存不足或者类似原因——下周我们将详细讲解。
But there's a key detail, a key characteristic
但有一个关键细节，一个关键特征
about this algorithm that makes sure that doing the same thing again
关于这个算法，它确保重复执行同一件事
and again is not crazy.
不会陷入死循环。
It's actually going to lead us to a solution.
实际上，它将引领我们找到解决方案。
Even though I'm using search here or search here,
尽管我在这里或这里使用了 search，
what's happening to the size of the problem for each of these lines?
每执行一行，问题规模发生了什么变化？
What's happening?
发生了什么？
Yeah?
是吗？
It's being cut in half.
它被缩减了一半。
So even though I'm doing the exact same thing algorithmically again and again,
所以即使我在算法上重复做着完全相同的事，
I'm doing it on a smaller, smaller, smaller input--
但我是在越来越小的输入上执行——
fewer, fewer, fewer doors-- fewer, fewer, fewer people.
越来越少的门——越来越少的人。
And so even though I'm doing it again and again,
所以尽管我不断重复执行，
so long as I have this so-called base case, as we'll call it,
只要我拥有这种所谓的基线情况，就像我们通常所说的，
that just makes sure if there's no doors-- you're done--
它确保当没有门时——你完成了——
I can break out of what would otherwise be an infinite loop of sorts.
我可以跳出本该是无限循环的状态。
All right, so those two lines we've already kind of seen.
好了，这两行我们已经看到过了。
And actually, we saw this in week zero.
事实上，我们在第一周就看到过它。
So this is the pseudocode for the phone book example from week zero.
所以这是第一周电话簿示例的伪代码。
And you might recall that we had these lines of code here.
你可能还记得我们这里有这些代码行。
And this is very procedural or iterative where I literally
这非常过程化或迭代化，因为我明确地
told you go back to line 3.
告诉你要回到第 3 行。
And we did that today when we took attendance, so to speak.
我们在今天点名时就做了这件事，可以这么说。
With that third algorithm, you went back to step 2 again and again.
在第三种算法中，你不断地回到步骤 2。
That's a very iterative loop-based approach.
这是一种非常迭代的基于循环的方法。
But you know what?
但你知道吗？
I could be a little more clever here too in week zero.
在第一周，我也可以在这里聪明一点。
We just didn't want to get too far ahead of ourselves.
我们只是不想过早地领先自己。
Let me actually change these highlighted lines to be more, succinctly,
让我实际更改这些突出显示的行，使其更简洁，
search left half book, search right half of book.
搜索左半本书，搜索右半本书。
I can now tighten the code up.
我现在可以压缩代码了。
So it's kind of a shorter algorithm.
所以这是一种更短的算法。
But it's the exact same idea.
但它完全相同。
But on week zero, I very methodically told you what I want you to do next.
但在第一周，我非常有条理地告诉了你接下来要做什么。
But here, I'm sort of recognizing that, wait a minute,
但在这里，我意识到，等等，
I just spent the past six lines telling you how to search.
我刚刚花了六行告诉你如何搜索。
So go do more of that.
所以继续做。
You have all of the logic you need.
你拥有你需要的所有逻辑。
So this too is recursive in the sense that if this is a search algorithm,
所以这也从某种意义上说是递归的，如果这是一个搜索算法，
the search algorithm is using a search algorithm inside of it.
搜索算法在内部使用了一个搜索算法。
But here too, the phone book was getting divided and divided
但在这里，电话簿也被分割和分割，
and divided in half again and again.
并一再分成两半。
So recursion doesn't just describe mathematical formulas.
所以递归不仅仅描述数学公式。
It doesn't just describe pseudocode or code-- even physical structures.
它不仅仅描述伪代码或代码——甚至物理结构。
So we deliberately brought back these bricks here today,
所以我们今天特意带回了这些砖块，
which are reminiscent, of course, from Mario and Super Mario Brothers.
它们当然让人想起马里奥和超级马里奥兄弟。
That pyramid, especially if we get rid of the distractions
那个金字塔，特别是如果我们摆脱干扰，
of the ground and the mountains and so forth,
来自地面和山脉等等，
is itself recursive as a structure.
它本身就是一个递归的结构。
Now, why is that?
现在，为什么呢？
Well, here you can kind of play verbal games.
好吧，在这里你可以玩文字游戏。
If this is a pyramid of height 4--
如果这是一个高度为 4 的金字塔——
and ask the question, well, what is that-- what is a pyramid of height 4--
并问问题，好吧，那是什么——高度为 4 的金字塔是什么——
I could kind of be difficult and say, well, it's just
我可能会很固执地说，好吧，它只是
a pyramid of height 3 plus 1 other row.
一个高度为 3 的金字塔加上另一排。
All right, well, what's a pyramid of height 3?
好吧，高度为 3 的金字塔是什么？
You could be difficult and say, well, it's just a pyramid of height 2
你可以很固执地说，好吧，它只是一个高度为 2 的金字塔
plus 1 more row.
加上一排。
What's a pyramid of height 2?
高度为 2 的金字塔是什么？
Well, it's this plus 1 more row.
好吧，它是这个加上一排。
I might have skipped a step there.
我可能跳过了一步。
What's a pyramid of height 2?
高度为 2 的金字塔是什么？
Well, it's a pyramid of height 1 plus 1 more row.
好吧，它是一个高度为 1 的金字塔加上一排。
What's a pyramid of height 1?
高度为 1 的金字塔是什么？
Well, it's nothing plus 1 more row.
好吧，它是一排加上一排。
Or at this point, you can just say it's a single brick.
或者在这一点上，你可以直接说它是一块砖。
You can have a base case that just says, like, the buck stops here.
你可以有一个基本情况，它只是说，就像，这里就到此为止了。
Stop asking me these questions.
别再问我这些问题了。
I can special case or hard code my answer to the very tiniest of problems.
我可以对最小的问题进行特殊情况处理或硬编码我的答案。
So even those bricks then are sort of--
所以，即使这些砖块——
the pyramid is recursively defined.
金字塔是递归定义的。
And we can actually implement this even in code
我们实际上甚至可以在代码中实现这一点。
if we want in a couple of different ways to make this clear.
如果我们想用几种不同的方法来使这一点变得清晰。
So let me go back over to VS Code here.
所以让我回到 VS Code 这里。
And let me propose that we do one old-school iterative example with
让我提议我们用一个老式的迭代例子。
this--
这个
code iteration dot C.
code iteration.c。
And iteration just means to loop again and again.
迭代只是意味着反复循环。
An iteration is a pass through the code.
迭代是指遍历代码。
And let me go ahead and whip this up as follows.
让我继续按照如下步骤进行操作。
Let's include the CS50 library.
让我们包含 CS50 库。
So we have our get int function.
所以我们有了 get int 函数。
Let's include standard io so that we have printf.
让我们包含 stdio，这样我们就可以使用 printf 了。
Let's go ahead and create main with no command line arguments today.
让我们继续创建没有命令行参数的 main 函数。
Let's go ahead and create a variable of type int set
让我们继续创建一个 int 类型的变量，并将其
equal to the return value of get int asking
设置为 get int 函数的返回值，该函数会询问
the user for the height of the pyramid.
用户金字塔的高度。
And then let me assume for the sake of discussion
然后让我们为了讨论的方便假设
that there is a function now that will draw a pyramid of that height.
现在有一个函数可以绘制一个指定高度的金字塔。
All right, now let's actually implement that function as a helper function,
好的，现在让我们实际实现这个函数作为辅助函数。
so to speak.
可以这么说。
So if I have a function called draw, it's going to clearly take an integer.
所以如果我有一个名为 draw 的函数，它显然会接收一个整数。
And I'll call it, maybe, n as input.
我将把它命名为 n 作为输入。
And it doesn't need to return anything.
它不需要返回任何东西。
So I'm going to say that this is a void function.
所以我要说这是一个 void 函数。
It doesn't return a value.
它不返回值。
It just has a side effect of printing bricks on the screen.
它只是在屏幕上打印砖块的副作用。
How can I go about doing a pyramid of height n?
我怎样才能构建一个高度为 n 的金字塔呢？
Well, I'm going to do this one, which looks like this-- one at a time,
好吧，我将按顺序进行，看起来像这样 - 一次一个。
then two, then three, then four.
然后是两个，然后是三个，然后是四个。
And this is a little easier, for instance,
这有点容易，例如，
than problem set one, which had the pyramid flipped around the other way.
比问题集一容易，问题集一的金字塔是反过来的。
So this one's a little easier to do deliberately.
所以这个更容易刻意地完成。
So if I go back to my code, I could say something like this-- for int i gets 0.
所以如果我回到我的代码，我可以这样说 - 对于 int i 获取 0。
i is less than, let's say, n, which is the height--
i 小于，比如说，n，也就是高度 -
i plus, plus.
i 加加。
That's going to essentially iterate over every row of the pyramid top to bottom.
这基本上会从上到下迭代金字塔的每一行。
This might feel similar--
这可能感觉类似 -
reminiscent-- to problem set one.
让人想起 - 问题集一。
Then in my inner loop, I'm going to do four.
然后在我的内循环中，我将进行四次操作。
int j gets 0.
int j 获取 0。
j is less than i plus 1 j plus, plus.
j 小于 i 加 1 j 加加。
And we'll see why this works in a moment.
我们稍后会看到为什么这样做有效。
And then let's go ahead and print out a single hash, no new line.
然后让我们继续打印一个单独的哈希符号，不换行。
But at the very bottom of this row, let's print out just a new line
但是在这一行的最底部，让我们只打印一个换行符
to move the cursor down a line.
将光标向下移动一行。
Now, I'm not done yet.
现在，我还没有完成。
Let me hide my terminal for a second.
让我隐藏一下我的终端。
I need the prototype.
我需要原型。
So I'm going to copy this, paste it up here with a semicolon.
所以我要复制它，把它粘贴到这里，并添加一个分号。
And I think now the code is correct.
我想现在代码是正确的。
Now, why is this correct?
现在，为什么这是正确的？
Because on my outer loop, I'm iterating n times starting at 0.
因为在我的外循环中，我从 0 开始迭代 n 次。
My inner loop-- realize I want to have at least one hash,
我的内循环 - 意识到我至少想要一个井号，
then two, then three, then four.
然后是两个，然后是三个，然后是四个。
So I can't start my number of hashes at 0.
所以我的井号数量不能从 0 开始。
And that's why I'm doing j all the way up to i plus 1 so that when i is 0,
这就是为什么我要一直将 j 做到 i 加 1，这样当 i 等于 0 时，
I'm actually still printing one hash, and then two hashes, and then three.
我实际上仍然会打印一个井号，然后是两个井号，然后是三个。
Otherwise, I would start with 0, which is not my goal.
否则，我会从 0 开始，这不是我的目标。
Let me go in and do make iteration to compile this--
让我进去并进行迭代以编译这个 -
dot slash iteration.
点斜杠迭代。
And let me go ahead and make my terminal bigger--
让我继续把我的终端弄得更大 -
enter.
输入。
The height will be, for instance, 4.
例如，高度将是 4。
And indeed, it's not quite to scale because these are a little more
实际上，它没有完全按比例，因为这些更
vertical than they are horizontal.
垂直而不是水平。
But it essentially looks like that pyramid.
但它本质上看起来像那个金字塔。
And I can do this even larger.
我甚至可以做到更大。
Let's do this again after clearing my screen.
让我们在清除屏幕后再次这样做。
Let's do like 10 of these.
让我们做 10 个这样的。
And it gets bigger.
它变得更大。
Let's do, like, 50 of these.
让我们做 50 个这样的。
And it gets even bigger.
它变得更大。
It doesn't even fit on the screen.
它甚至不适合屏幕。
But it works.
但它有效。
And that's an iterative approach, 100% correct,
这是一种迭代方法，100% 正确，
and similar to what you might have done already for something
类似于你可能已经为某些东西做的事情
like week zero or week one.
比如第零周或第一周。
But it turns out if we leverage recursion,
但事实证明，如果我们利用递归，
we can be a little more clever, in fact.
实际上，我们可以更聪明一点。
Let me go ahead and do this.
让我继续这样做。
Let me minimize my terminal window.
让我最小化我的终端窗口。
And let me go back into my code here.
让我回到这里我的代码。
And let me propose to implement the exact same program recursively instead.
让我建议改为递归地实现完全相同的程序。
And let me go ahead and do this.
让我继续这样做。
I'm going to leave main--
我要离开主程序 -
let's see-- exactly as is.
让我们看看 - 正如它所是。
And I'm going to go ahead and change my draw function to work as follows.
我要继续改变我的绘制函数以按如下方式工作。
Let me delete all of these loops because loops are sort
让我删除所有这些循环，因为循环是一种
of an indication of using iteration.
使用迭代的指示。
And I'm instead going to do this.
我将改为这样做。
What is a pyramid of height 4?
什么是高度为 4 的金字塔？
I said it's a pyramid of height 3 plus 1 more row.
我说它是一个高度为 3 的金字塔，加上一行。
So let's take that literally.
所以让我们按照字面意思理解。
If a pyramid of height n needs to be drawn,
如果需要绘制高度为 n 的金字塔，
let's first draw a pyramid of n minus 1.
让我们先绘制一个高度为 n 减 1 的金字塔。
And then how do I go about drawing one more row?
然后我如何绘制另一行？
Well, this, I can use a bit of iteration.
好吧，这个我可以使用一点迭代。
But I don't need a doubly-nested loop anymore.
但我不再需要双重嵌套循环。
I can set i equal to 0, i less than n, i plus, plus.
我可以将 i 设置为 0，i 小于 n，i 加加。
And this block of code is simply going to print
这块代码将简单地打印
one simple row of hashes again and again followed by a new line just
仅仅是一行简单的哈希符号，一遍又一遍地重复，然后是一个新行
to move the cursor down.
以便将光标向下移动。
So notice this line here.
所以请注意这里这行代码。
And I'll add some comments-- print pyramid of height n minus 1,
我会添加一些注释——打印高度为 n-1 的金字塔，
print one more row.
再打印一行。
So I'm kind of taking a bite out of the problem by printing one row.
所以，我通过打印一行代码来解决问题。
But I'm deferring to, weirdly, myself, to print the rest of the pyramid.
但我却将打印剩余金字塔的任务推迟了，有点奇怪，是我自己来完成。
Now I'm going to go ahead and try compiling this-- make--
现在，我将尝试编译这段代码——make——
oh.
哦。
And this is no longer iteration.
现在它不再是迭代了。
So I'm actually going to do this-- code recursion dot c.
所以我实际上会这样做——code recursion.c。
I'm going to paste that same code into this new version,
我会将相同的代码粘贴到这个新版本中，
just so we have a different file without breaking the old one.
这样我们就可以拥有一个不同的文件，而不会破坏旧文件。
And now I'm going to do make recursion.
现在我将执行 make recursion。
All right, interesting.
好的，有趣。
So Clang is yelling at me with this error.
所以，Clang 正在用这个错误对我大喊大叫。
All paths through this function will call itself.
这个函数的所有路径都会调用自身。
So Clang is actually smart enough to notice in my code
所以，Clang 实际上足够聪明，能够在我的代码中注意到
that no matter what, the draw function is going to call the draw function.
无论如何，draw 函数都会调用 draw 函数。
And the draw function is going to call the draw function.
draw 函数将调用 draw 函数。
And the draw function's going to call the draw function.
Now, to be fair, n, the input to draw, is getting smaller and smaller.
公平地说，n 作为 draw 函数的输入，正在越来越小。
But what's going to happen eventually to the input of draw
但最终，draw 函数的输入会发生什么情况
as I've written this code right now?
正如我现在编写的代码那样？
Yeah, in the back?
是啊，在后面？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID MALAN: Exactly.
大卫·马兰：没错。
Remember that integers are signed by default.
请记住，默认情况下整数是有符号的。
They can be both positive or 0 or negative.
它们可以是正数、0 或负数。
And so here, if I just keep blindly subtracting 1,
因此，在这里，如果我不断地盲目地减去 1，
it's going to do that seemingly forever until I technically underflow.
它看起来将永远这样做，直到我技术性地溢出。
But that's going to be like 2 billion rows of pyramids later.
但那将在 20 亿行金字塔之后。
So I think what I actually need to do is something like this.
我认为我实际上需要做的事情是这样的。
I need to ask the question, if n equals 0--
我需要问一个问题，如果 n 等于 0——
or heck, just to be super safe, let's say if n is less than or equal to 0,
或者，为了绝对安全，我们假设 n 小于或等于 0，
just to make sure it never goes negative, let's just go ahead
为了确保它永远不会变成负数，让我们继续
and return without doing anything.
并返回而不做任何操作。
So I'm going to comment this as, like, if nothing to draw, well, then
所以我将对此进行注释，例如，如果没有任何内容要绘制，那么
don't blindly call draw again.
不要再次盲目地调用 draw 函数。
So this is that so-called base case.
所以，这就是所谓的基线情况。
This is analogous to saying, like, if John Harvard not in phone book
这类似于说，例如，如果约翰·哈佛不在电话簿中
or if no lockers or doors left, then just exit or return in this case.
或者如果没有剩下的储物柜或门，那么在这种情况下就退出或返回。
So now I'll never call draw a negative number of times
所以，现在我永远不会负数次调用 draw 函数
or zero number of times.
或零次。
I will only do it so long as n is positive.
我只会这样做，只要 n 是正数。
So now if I make my terminal bigger, make recursion again does compile fine.
所以现在，如果我让我的终端更大，再次执行 make recursion，它就可以正常编译。
Dot slash recursion-- let's do the same input for.
./recursion——让我们对它使用相同的输入。
And I get the exact same number of bricks.
我得到了相同数量的砖块。
Let's go ahead and do it again with maybe 10.
让我们再试一次，也许用 10 块砖。
That seems to work too.
看起来也可以。
Let's do it again with 50.
让我们再试一次，用 50 块砖。
That seems to work too.
看起来也可以。
And I can go a little crazy.
我可以有点疯狂。
I can do, like, 5,000.
我可以做，比如，5000 块砖。
This is still going to work.
这仍然会起作用。
It's just not going to fit on my screen.
只是不会在我的屏幕上显示。
But it is doing a valiant attempt to print all of those out.
但它正在尽力打印出所有这些。
Now, it turns out that could get us in trouble
现在，事实证明这可能会给我们带来麻烦
if we start poking around in the-- now, maybe not 5,000 but 500,000 or 5
如果我们开始在里面戳来戳去，现在，也许不是 5000 块，而是 50 万块或者 5
million or beyond.
百万块或更多。
But for now, we'll just assume that this is just a slow process at that.
但现在，我们假设这只是一个缓慢的过程。
But if we go back to the goal, which was to print this thing here,
但如果我们回到目标，即打印这个东西，
this too is a recursive structure that we're just now translating
这也是一个递归结构，我们现在正在将
the ideas of recursive code to.
递归代码的理念转换为。
And actually, if you've never discovered this,
实际上，如果你从未发现过这一点，
we would be remiss in not doing this for you.
我们不应该为你做这件事。
If I go into a browser here.
如果我进入这里的浏览器。
And suppose that I'm not using any AI fancy technology.
假设我没有使用任何人工智能技术。
I'm just going to Google.com.
我只是要访问 Google.com。
And I search for recursion because I'm curious to see what it means.
我搜索递归，因为我好奇地想知道它的含义。
Google for years has had this little Easter egg for computer scientists.
多年来，谷歌一直为计算机科学家准备了这个小彩蛋。
It's not a typo.
这不是错字。
Get it?
明白了吗？
Ha, ha, kind of funny.
哈哈，有点好笑。
Yeah?
是吗？
OK, like, see?
好吧，就像，看到了吗？
Recursion-- so if you click recursion, OK, now we're
递归，所以如果你点击递归，好的，现在我们
in night mode for some reason.
出于某种原因处于夜间模式。
But OK, like, so it just does this endlessly.
但好的，就像，所以它只是无休止地这样做。
OK, so programmers with too much free time or too much
好的，所以那些有太多空闲时间或太多
control over Google's own servers to do that.
控制权的程序员可以对谷歌自己的服务器做这些。
So it turns out, yes, if you search for recursion on Google,
所以事实证明，是的，如果你在 Google 上搜索递归，
this is a long-standing Easter egg in this case.
这在这种情况下是一个长期存在的彩蛋。
But the point of introducing recursion is
但介绍递归的目的是
that, one, it's actually going to be a very powerful problem-solving technique
那就是，首先，它实际上将是一种非常强大的问题解决技术
because honestly, it, one, we've seen in pseudocode already,
因为坦率地说，我们已经看到了伪代码，
it kind of tightens up the amount of code or the amount of lines
它在一定程度上缩短了代码量或行数
that you need to write to convey an algorithm.
你需要编写来表达算法。
And two, it will actually allow us to solve
其次，它实际上将允许我们解决
problems in a fundamentally different way
以一种根本不同的方式解决问题
by using computer's memory in an interesting way.
通过以一种有趣的方式使用计算机的内存。
And so toward that end, we wanted to introduce one final sort today, which
因此，为了这个目的，我们今天想介绍最后一种排序，即
we won't use humans to demonstrate but just numbers instead, namely
我们不会用人类来演示，而是用数字来演示，即
something called merge sort.
一种叫做归并排序的东西。
And merge sort is an algorithm for sorting n numbers that I claim
归并排序是一种对 n 个数字进行排序的算法，我认为
is going to be better than selection sort and bubble sort.
它将比选择排序和冒泡排序更好。
It's got to be better because that n squared was killing us.
它必须更好，因为 n 平方正在杀死我们。
We want to get something lower than n squared.
我们想要得到比n平方更低的复杂度。
So merge sort's pseudocode essentially looks like this.
所以归并排序的伪代码本质上是这样的。
And this is it.
就是这样。
Merge sort says, if you've got n numbers or an array of numbers,
归并排序说，如果你有n个数字或一个数字数组，
sort the left half of them, sort the right half of them.
对它们左半部分进行排序，对它们右半部分进行排序。
And then merge the sorted halves.
然后合并排序后的两半。
And we'll see what this means in just a moment.
我们马上就会看到这意味着什么。
But if there's only one number, just quit.
但如果只有一个数字，就退出。
So this is my base case because this is recursive.
所以这是我的基本情况，因为它是递归的。
Because if this is a sorting algorithm called merge sort,
因为如果这是一个名为归并排序的排序算法，
I'm kind of cheating by using the verb sort in the sorting algorithm.
我在排序算法中使用动词“排序”有点作弊。
But that just makes it recursive.
但这只是使它递归。
It doesn't make it wrong.
这并不意味着它错了。
So what do I mean by merging?
那么，我所说的合并是什么意思呢？
Just to make this clear, here among these numbers are two lists of size 4.
为了更清楚地说明，这里，在这组数字中，有两个大小为4的列表。
And I'm going to scooch them over to the left and the right
我将它们向左和向右移动
just to make clear that on the left is one half that is sorted--
只是为了更清楚地说明，左侧是已经排序的一半——
1346 from smallest to largest.
从最小到最大依次为1346。
On the right is a second half that's also sorted 0257.
右侧是第二部分，也已经排序了，为0257。
So for the sake of discussion, suppose that I'm
为了讨论，假设我正在
partway through this algorithm called merge sort.
进行这个名为归并排序的算法。
And I've sorted the left half already, clearly.
我已经对左半部分进行了排序，很明显。
I've sorted the right half already, clearly.
我已经对右半部分进行了排序，很明显。
Now I need to merge the sorted halves.
现在我需要合并排序后的两半。
What do we mean by that?
这意味着什么呢？
Well, that means to essentially, conceptually,
嗯，这意味着本质上，从概念上讲，
point your left hand at the first at the left half.
将你的左手指向左侧的第一部分。
Point your right hand at the right half.
将你的右手指向右侧的部分。
And then decide which of these numbers should come first
然后决定这些数字中哪个应该排在最前面
in order to merge or kind of stitch these two lists together
以便将这两个列表合并或缝合在一起
in sorted order.
以排序顺序。
Well, which is smaller?
哪一个更小？
Obviously, 0.
显然，是0。
So that last step, merge sorted halves, would have me take this number
所以最后一步，合并排序后的两半，会让我取这个数字
and put it in an extra empty array up here.
把它放在这里一个额外的空数组中。
Now I move my right hand to the next number in the right half.
现在我将我的右手移动到右侧的下一个数字。
And I compare the 1 and the 2.
我比较了1和2。
Obviously, 1 comes next.
显然，1是下一个。
So I put this now up here.
所以我把它放在这里。
Now I compare the 3 and the 2.
现在我比较了3和2。
Obviously, the 2 comes next.
显然，2是下一个。
And so I put this up here--
所以我把它放在这里——
3 and 5-- obviously, 3--
3和5——显然，是3——
4 and 5-- obviously, 4--
4和5——显然，是4——
6 and 5-- obviously, 5--
6和5——显然，是5——
and 6 and 7-- obviously, 6.
以及6和7——显然，是6。
And I didn't leave quite enough room for 7, perhaps, and lastly, 7.
我可能没有留出足够的空间来放置7，最后是7。
So that's all we mean by merging two lists together.
这就是我们所说的合并两个列表的意思。
If they're already sorted, you just kind of stitch them
如果它们已经排序，你只需将它们缝合
together by plucking from one or the other the next number
在一起，通过从一个或另一个中取出下一个数字。
that you actually want.
你真正想要的。
And that's it.
就是这样。
And even though I picked up partway through this algorithm,
即使我在这个算法进行到一半的时候才开始了解它，
those three steps alone would seem to work.
这三个步骤本身就足以运作。
So long as you can sort the left half and sort the right half,
只要你能将左半部分排序，并将右半部分排序，
you can surely then merge the sorted halves.
你就可以将排序好的两半合并在一起。
Now I'll go ahead and do this digitally rather than use the physical numbers
现在，我将用数字方式进行操作，而不是使用物理数字
because clearly, it's a little involved moving them up and down.
因为很明显，上下移动它们会比较麻烦。
But this rack here, this shelving, essentially
但是这个架子，这个货架，本质上
represents one array with maybe a second array here.
代表了一个数组，也许这里还有一个数组。
And heck, if I really want it, a third and a fourth array.
如果我真的需要，还可以有第三个和第四个数组。
It turns out that with selection sort and bubble sort,
事实证明，对于选择排序和冒泡排序，
we've really been tying our hands because I only
我们一直束手束脚，因为我只有
allowed myself a constant amount of memory, just one variable in my head,
允许自己使用固定数量的内存，在我的脑海中只有一个变量，
for instance, with selection sort that let me keep
例如，使用选择排序，它让我可以跟踪
track of who was the smallest element.
哪个是最小的元素。
And when we did bubble sort, the only number I kept in mind
当我们进行冒泡排序时，我唯一记住的数字
was i, like i and i plus 1.
是 i，比如 i 和 i 加 1。
I didn't allow myself any additional memory.
我没有允许自己使用任何额外的内存。
But it turns out in programming and in CS, you
但事实证明，在编程和计算机科学中，你
can trade off one resource for another.
可以将一种资源换成另一种资源。
So if you want to spend less time solving a problem,
所以，如果你想花更少的时间解决问题，
you've got to throw space at it.
你必须投入空间。
You've got to spend more space, spend more money,
你必须花更多空间，花更多钱，
in order to give yourself more space to reduce your time.
以便给自己更多空间来减少时间。
Conversely, if you're fine with things being slow in terms of time,
反之，如果你对时间上的缓慢没有意见，
then you can get away with very little space.
那么你就可以用很少的空间。
So it's kind of like this balance whereby
所以这有点像一种平衡，即
you have to decide which is more important to you, which
你必须决定哪一个对你更重要，哪一个
is more expensive for you, or the like.
对你来说更昂贵，或者类似的情况。
So let's go ahead then and consider exactly this algorithm as follows.
那么，让我们继续考虑这个算法，如下所示。
So suppose that these are the numbers in question.
假设这些是要排序的数字。
So here is our array.
这是我们的数组。
It's clearly unsorted.
很明显，它没有排序。
I'd like to sort this.
我想对它进行排序。
I could use selection sort.
我可以使用选择排序。
But selection sort was not great because it's big O of n squared.
但选择排序并不理想，因为它的时间复杂度为 O(n^2)。
And it's omega of n squared, so sort of damned if you do.
而且它的时间复杂度下界也是 O(n^2)，所以说，无论做什么都会被限制。
Damned if you don't.
不做也是一样。
Bubble sort was a little better.
冒泡排序稍微好一点。
It was still big O of n squared.
它的时间复杂度仍然是 O(n^2)。
But sometimes, we could get lucky and shave some time off.
但有时，我们可能会很幸运，能够节省一些时间。
So it was omega of only n.
所以它的时间复杂度下界只有 O(n)。
Let's see if merge sort is fundamentally better.
让我们看看归并排序是否本质上更好。
And let's do so by trying to reduce the number of comparisons-- no more looping
让我们通过减少比较次数来实现——不再进行循环
back and forth and back and forth and back and forth endlessly.
反复循环，永无止境。
So here's how we can draw inspiration from the idea of recursion and divide
所以，我们可以从递归和分治思想中汲取灵感，
and conquer as per week zero.
正如第一周所讲的那样。
Let's first think of these numbers as indeed in an array
让我们首先将这些数字视为确实存在于一个数组中
contiguously from left to right.
从左到右连续排列。
Let's then go ahead and sort the left half.
然后，让我们继续对左半部分进行排序。
Because again, the pseudocode that you have
因为再一次，你所拥有的伪代码
to remember throughout this whole algorithm has just three real steps.
在整个算法中需要记住的只有三个实际步骤。
Sort the left half.
对左半部分进行排序。
Sort the right half.
对右半部分进行排序。
Merge the sorted halves.
合并排序后的两半。
And then this is sort of a one-off thing.
然后，这是一个一次性的东西。
But it's important.
但它很重要。
But this is the juicy part.
但这是最精彩的部分。
Sort left half.
对左半部分进行排序。
Sort right half.
对右半部分进行排序。
Merge the sorted halves.
合并排序后的两半。
So if we go back to this array on the top shelf, here's the original array.
所以如果我们回到最上面架子上的这个数组，这是原始数组。
Let's go ahead and sort the left half.
让我们继续对左半部分进行排序。
And I'm going to do so by sort of stealing some more memory,
我会通过窃取更多内存来完成，
so I can sort of work on a second shelf with just these numbers.
这样我就可以在第二层架子上只用这些数字进行操作了。
So 6341 is now an array of size 4, essentially.
所以6341本质上现在是一个大小为4的数组。
How do I sort an array of size 4?
我如何对一个大小为4的数组进行排序？
Well, I've got an algorithm for that-- selection sort.
嗯，我有一个算法——选择排序。
But we decided that's slow.
但我们决定它太慢了。
Bubble sort-- that's slow.
冒泡排序——那太慢了。
Wait a minute.
等等。
I'm in the middle of defining merge sort.
我正在定义归并排序。
Let's recursively use the same algorithm by just
让我们递归地使用相同的算法，只需
sorting the left half of the left half.
对左半部分的左半部分进行排序。
So if you've got an array of size 4, it's only three steps to solve it.
所以如果你有一个大小为4的数组，只需要三个步骤就可以解决它。
Sort left half.
对左半部分进行排序。
Sort right half.
对右半部分进行排序。
Merge.
合并。
So let's do that.
所以让我们来做吧。
Let's sort the left half.
让我们对左半部分进行排序。
OK, wait a minute.
好的，等等。
How do you sort an array of size 2?
你如何对一个大小为2的数组进行排序？
I've got an algorithm for that.
我有一个算法。
Sort the left half.
对左半部分进行排序。
Sort the right half.
对右半部分进行排序。
Merge the two halves.
合并这两个部分。
All right, let's sort the left half.
好的，让我们对左半部分进行排序。
What now?
现在呢？
So 6 is a list of size 1.
所以6是一个大小为1的列表。
What was that special base case then?
那么，那个特殊的基本情况是什么？
So it was quit or just return.
所以它是退出或返回。
Like, I'm already done.
就像，我已经完成了。
So this list of size 1 is sort of weirdly already sorted.
所以这个大小为1的列表以一种奇怪的方式已经被排序了。
So I'm making progress.
所以我正在取得进展。
Meanwhile, what's the next step after sorting this left half?
同时，对左半部分排序后的下一步是什么？
Sort the right half.
对右半部分进行排序。
Done.
完成了。
This is already sorted.
这些已经排好序了。
But here's the magic.
但这里有魔法。
What's the third step for these numbers?
这些数字的第三步是什么？
Merge them.
合并它们。
So this is like the left hand, right hand thing.
所以这就像左手、右手一样。
Which one comes first?
哪个先来？
Obviously, 3 and then 6.
显然，先来 3 然后是 6。
And now we are making progress because now the list of size 2 is sorted.
现在我们正在取得进展，因为现在长度为 2 的列表已经排好序了。
So what have I just done?
所以，我刚才做了什么？
I've just finished sorting the left half of the left half.
我刚刚完成了对左侧一半的左侧一半的排序。
So after I've sorted the left half, what comes next if you rewind in time?
所以，在我对左侧一半排序后，如果你倒回时间，下一步是什么？
Sort the right half of that left half.
对左侧一半的右侧一半进行排序。
So now I take the right half.
现在我取右侧一半。
And how do I sort this right half of size 2?
我如何对长度为 2 的右侧一半进行排序？
Well, sort its left half.
好吧，对它的左侧一半进行排序。
Done.
完成了。
Sort its right half.
对它的右侧一半进行排序。
Done.
完成了。
Now merge them together.
现在将它们合并在一起。
And obviously, the 1 comes first, then the 4.
显然，1 先来，然后是 4。
Now where are we?
现在我们在哪里？
We're at the point in the story where we have a left left half
我们现在处于故事中的一个点，那里有一个左侧的左侧一半
sorted and a right left half sorted.
已经排好序，还有一个右侧的左侧一半已经排好序。
So what comes next now narratively?
那么，从叙述的角度来看，下一步是什么？
Merge the two together, so left hand, right hand, so 1346.
将两者合并在一起，所以左手、右手，所以 1346。
And where are we now in the story?
现在我们在故事中的什么位置？
We're sort of at the beginning because I've now sorted the left half.
我们现在处于故事的开头，因为我已经对左侧一半进行了排序。
And you recall the demo I did physically, this
你还记得我之前做的物理演示，这个
is how I had the left half was already sorted on the second shelf.
就是我在第二层架子上已经对左侧一半进行了排序的方式。
But now that I've sorted the left half of the original array, what's
但是，现在我已经对原始数组的左侧一半进行了排序，那么
the original second step?
原始的第二步是什么？
Sort the right half.
对右侧一半进行排序。
So it's the same idea.
所以，它是一样的想法。
So I'm borrowing some extra memory here.
所以，我在这里借用了一些额外的内存。
And now I've got an array of size 4.
现在我得到一个长度为 4 的数组。
How do I sort an array of size 4?
我如何对一个长度为 4 的数组进行排序？
Sort the left half.
对左侧一半进行排序。
All right, how do I sort an array of size 2?
好的，我如何对一个长度为 2 的数组进行排序？
Sort the left half.
对左侧一半进行排序。
Done.
完成了。
Sort the right half.
对右侧一半进行排序。
Done.
完成了。
Now what?
现在怎么办？
Merge the two together.
将两者合并在一起。
And of course, it's 2 and 5.
当然，是 2 和 5。
Now what do I do?
现在我该怎么办？
I've sorted the left half of the right half.
我已经对右侧一半的左侧一半进行了排序。
So now I sort the right half of the right half.
所以，现在我需要对右侧一半的右侧一半进行排序。
How do I sort a list of size 2?
我如何对长度为 2 的列表进行排序？
Well, sort the left half.
好吧，对左侧一半进行排序。
Done.
好了。
Sort the right half.
对右半部分排序。
Done.
好了。
Merge them together-- 0 and 7.
把它们合并在一起——0 和 7。
Where am I in the story?
我在故事中的什么位置？
I've sorted the left half and the right half of the original right half.
我已经对左侧部分和原始右侧部分的右侧部分进行了排序。
So I merge these two together--
所以，我把这两个合并在一起——
0 and then 2 and then 5 and then 7.
0，然后是 2，然后是 5，然后是 7。
Whew.
呼。
Where are we?
我们现在在哪里？
We're at exactly the point in the story where we had the numbers
我们现在正处在故事中的一个点，在那里我们有这些数字
originally on the second shelf.
最初在第二层架子上。
We had a list that's sorted on the left, a list that's sorted on the right.
我们有一个左侧排序的列表，一个右侧排序的列表。
And what I demoed physically was merging those two together.
我实际演示的是将这两个合并在一起。
So what happens now?
那么现在会发生什么呢？
01234567.
01234567。
And it seems kind of magical and kind of weird in that I kind of cheated.
这看起来有点神奇，也有一点奇怪，因为我有点作弊了。
And when I had these leaves--
当我拥有这些叶子——
these leaf nodes, so to speak-- these singletons--
这些叶子节点，你可以这么说——这些单一元素——
I was, like, sorted.
我已经排序好了。
I wasn't really doing anything.
我实际上没有做什么。
But it's that merging that seems to really be doing
但正是这种合并，似乎真正起到了
the magic of sorting things for us.
为我们对事物进行排序的魔力。
So that felt like a mouthful.
所以这感觉有点拗口。
And recursion in general is the kind of thing
而递归总体来说，就是那种会
that will, like, bend your brain a little bit.
让你稍微想一想的东西。
And if that went over your head, like, that's fine.
如果这让你摸不着头脑，那也没关系。
It takes time and time and time and practice.
需要时间，时间，时间，以及练习。
But what there was not a lot of with this algorithm was again and again
但这个算法中很少出现的是，一次又一次
and again and again.
一次又一次。
I was kind of only doing things once.
我实际上只做了一次。
And then once I fixed a number, I moved on to the next.
然后，一旦我固定了一个数字，我就继续下一个。
And that's sort of the essence of this algorithm here.
这就是这个算法的本质。
If it helps you to see it in another visual way,
如果你希望从另一个视觉角度来看，
let me go back to our previous visualization here.
让我回到我们之前的可视化界面。
Let me re-randomize the array and click merge sort.
让我重新随机化数组，然后点击合并排序。
And this time, notice that merge sort is using more space.
这次请注意，合并排序使用了更多空间。
Technically, I was using 1, 2, 3 shelves.
从技术上讲，我使用了 1、2、3 层架子。
But you can actually be slightly more intelligent about it
但你实际上可以稍微聪明一点
and actually just go back and forth and back and forth between two shelves
实际上只需在两层架子之间来回移动
just to save a little space.
以节省一些空间。
So you're still using twice as much space.
所以你仍然使用了两倍的空间。
But you don't need four times as much space as the diagrams
但你不需要四倍于图表
or as the shelves might imply.
或者架子可能暗示的空间。
So here is merge sort.
所以这是合并排序。
And you'll notice that we're sort of working in halves-- sometimes
你会注意到我们是在一半一半地进行——有时
big halves, sometimes smaller halves.
是大块，有时是小块。
But you can see as the two halves are merged,
但你可以看到，随着两部分合并，
things seem to happen very quickly.
事情似乎很快就发生了。
And so notice that this is the same number of bars as before.
所以请注意，这与之前的条形图数量相同。
But that was way faster, right?
但是快多了，对吧？
I don't need to stall nearly as much as I have in the past.
我不需要像过去那样拖延那么多了。
So why is that?
所以为什么呢？
Well, if we go back to the diagram in question,
好吧，如果我们回到问题中的图表，
here's the array that's already sorted.
这里是有序的数组。
And if we consider now exactly how much work is done,
现在如果我们考虑到底做了多少工作，
I'll stipulate already it's not n squared. n squared was slow.
我再说一次，它不是n平方。n平方很慢。
And merge sort is actually much better than that.
而归并排序实际上比那好得多。
Let's see how much better it is.
让我们看看它有多好。
So here is the original list--
所以这里是原始列表——
63415270.
63415270。
And here are all of the remnants of that algorithm, all of the states
这里都是该算法的所有残留物，所有我们曾经处于的状态
that we were in at some point-- sort of leaving a whole bunch of breadcrumbs.
我们在某个时间点都曾经处在这个状态——就像留下了一堆面包屑。
How many pieces of work did I do?
我做了多少工作？
Well, like, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19,
嗯，比如，1，2，3，4，5，6，7，8，9，10，11，12，13，14，15，16，17，18，19，
20, 21, 22, 23, 24.
20，21，22，23，24。
So I moved things around, like, 24 times, it seems.
所以，我好像移动了24次。
And how do I actually reason about that?
我该如何推论呢？
Well, these are the numbers.
好吧，这些是数字。
This is like my temporary workspace here.
这里就像我的临时工作区。
And 24 is the literal number.
而24就是字面上的数字。
But let's see if we can't do things a little more generically.
但让我们看看是否能更通用地做一些事情。
Log base 2 of n, recall, is what refers to anything
回想一下，以2为底的对数n指的是任何东西
that we're doing in half-- dividing, dividing, dividing.
我们正在做的一半——分割，分割，分割。
And that's kind of what I was doing here.
这就是我在这里做的事情。
I took a list of size 8-- divide it into two of size 4, then four of size 2,
我拿了一个长度为8的列表——把它分成两个长度为4的列表，然后四个长度为2的列表，
then eight of size 1.
然后八个长度为1的列表。
Well, how many times can you do this if you start with eight numbers?
好吧，如果你从八个数字开始，你能做多少次呢？
Well, that's log base 2 of 8.
好吧，那就是以2为底的对数8。
And if we do some fancy math, that's just log base 2 of 2 to the third.
如果我们做一些复杂的数学运算，它只是以2为底的2的三次方对数。
And remember, the base and the number here can cancel out.
记住，这里底数和数字可以抵消。
So that's actually 3.
所以实际上是3。
So log base 2 of 8 is 3, which means that's how many times you
所以以2为底的对数8是3，这意味着这就是你
can divide a problem of size 8 in half, in half, in half.
可以将一个长度为8的问题分成两半，再分成两半，再分成两半。
But every time we did that per this chart, I had to take the numbers
但是根据这张图表，我们每次这样做的时候，我都必须取数字
and merge them together, merge them together, merge them together.
并把它们合并起来，合并起来，合并起来。
And so on every row of this postmortem of the algorithm,
因此，在这个算法事后分析的每一行，
there are n steps, n steps, n steps.
都有n步，n步，n步。
So laterally, there's n steps because I had to merge all of those things
所以，水平方向上，有n步，因为我必须把所有这些东西
back together.
合并在一起。
But what is the height of these yellow remnants?
但是这些黄色残留物的高度是多少呢？
Well, it's 3, which is log base 2 of 8, which is 3.
好吧，它是3，也就是以2为底的对数8，也就是3。
So this is technically three times 8, ergo 24 steps.
所以，从技术上讲，它是3乘以8，也就是24步。
But more generally, this is log n height and n width, so to speak.
但是更一般地来说，我们可以称它为对数n高度和n宽度。
So the total running time I claim is actually
所以，我声称总运行时间实际上是
n log n, which it's OK if that doesn't quite gel immediately in your mind,
n log n，如果你没有立刻理解，那也没关系，
especially if you're rusty on algorithms.
尤其是如果你对算法不熟悉。
But and we can throw away the base because that's just a constant factor
但是我们可以抛弃底数，因为它只是一个常数因子。
and with a wave of our hand when we talk about big O notation, merge sort,
当我们谈论大O表示法时，我们挥手示意，并说归并排序，
I claim is in big O of n log n-- that is, n times log n.
我断言它处于n log n 的大O中，也就是n乘以log n。
Unfortunately, it is also in omega of n log
不幸的是，它也处于n log 的Ω中
n, which means that, frankly, bubble sort might sometimes outperform it,
n，这意味着，坦率地说，冒泡排序有时可能比它表现更好，
at least when the inputs are already sorted or certainly relatively small.
至少当输入已经排序或相对较小时。
But that's probably OK because in general,
但这可能没关系，因为一般来说，
data that we're sorting probably isn't very sorted.
我们正在排序的数据可能并没有很好地排序。
And honestly, we could even half merge sort
老实说，我们甚至可以将归并排序减半
to just do one pass to check initially, is the whole thing sorted,
只需要进行一次遍历，最初检查整个数据是否排序，
and then maybe terminate early.
然后可以提前终止。
So we can maybe massage the algorithm a little better to be a little smarter.
因此，我们可以稍微修改一下算法，让它更聪明一些。
But fundamentally, merge sort is in theta of n log n,
但从根本上说，归并排序处于n log n 的θ中，
is how you would say it.
这就是你的说法。
It's on the order of n times log n steps.
它的阶数是n乘以log n步。
Now, in terms of that chart, it's strictly higher than linear.
现在，就图表而言，它严格高于线性。
But it's strictly lower than quadratic-- n and n squared, respectively.
但它严格低于二次函数——分别为n和n平方。
So it clearly seems to be faster.
所以它显然看起来更快。
So it's not as good as linear search.
所以它不如线性搜索好。
And it's definitely not as good as binary search.
而且它肯定不如二分查找好。
But it's way better than selection sort or bubble sort actually were.
但它比选择排序或冒泡排序要好得多。
So with that said, we thought we'd conclude
因此，我们想在结尾
by showing you a final film that's just about
向你展示一部仅关于
a minute long that compares these actual algorithms and shows them as follows.
一分钟长的电影，它比较了这些实际的算法，并以如下方式展示它们。
You'll see on the top, the middle, and the bottom, three different algorithms.
你会看到在顶部、中间和底部，三种不同的算法。
On the top, you will see selection sort.
在顶部，你会看到选择排序。
On the bottom, you will see bubble sort.
在底部，你会看到冒泡排序。
And in the middle, you will see and hear an appreciation of what n log n is--
在中间，你会看到并听到对n log n的欣赏——
a.k.a., merge sort today.
也就是今天的归并排序。
So if we could dim the lights dramatically,
所以如果我们能将灯光调暗，
this is n log n vis a vis n squared.
这是n log n与n平方对比。
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
[视频播放]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
[END PLAYBACK]
[播放结束]
All right, that's it for CS50.
好了，CS50 就到这里。
We'll see you next time.
我们下次再见。
[APPLAUSE]
[鼓掌]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]